<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>theme-human_rights on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/theme-human_rights/</link><description>Recent content in theme-human_rights on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/theme-human_rights/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kazakhstan: TLS MITM attacks and blocking of news media, human rights, and circumvention tool sites</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2024-kazakhstan-report/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2024-kazakhstan-report/</guid><description>In recent years, internet censorship in Kazakhstan has been reported quite extensively. As part of this study, OONI, Internet Freedom Kazakhstan (IFKZ), and Eurasian Digital Foundation collaborated to investigate internet censorship in Kazakhstan over the past year (between June 2023 to June 2024) through the analysis of empirical network measurement data.
In this report, we share OONI censorship measurement findings and relevant legal context. We found numerous news media, human rights, and circumvention tool websites blocked in Kazakhstan by means of TLS interference.</description></item><item><title>Tanzania: Surge in online LGBTIQ censorship and other targeted blocks</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2024-tanzania-lgbtiq-censorship-and-other-targeted-blocks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2024-tanzania-lgbtiq-censorship-and-other-targeted-blocks/</guid><description>This report documents the blocking of LGBTIQ websites and other targeted blocks in Tanzania based on the analysis of OONI data.
Key Findings Introduction Methods Acknowledgement of limitations Findings Blocking of LGBTIQ websites LGBTIQ social networks LGBTIQ rights LGBTIQ news and culture LGBTIQ suicide prevention Blocking of websites that support human rights Blocking of online dating websites Blocking of Clubhouse and 4chan Blocking of ProtonVPN Conclusion Acknowledgements Key Findings Our analysis of OONI data collected from Tanzania over the last year (between 1st January 2023 to 31st January 2024) reveals the extensive blocking of LGBTIQ sites, which correlates with the escalating discrimination and crackdown on LGBTIQ communities in Tanzania in recent years.</description></item><item><title>Grindr blocked in Jordan: Shrinking LGBTQ spaces</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-jordan-blocks-grindr/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-jordan-blocks-grindr/</guid><description>Jordan recently blocked access to Grindr — the world’s largest social networking app for gay, bi, trans, and queer people — adding to the list of social media apps banned in the country, including TikTok and Clubhouse.
OONI network measurement data collected from Jordan suggests that ISPs started blocking access to Grindr on August 8th 2023, and that the block remains ongoing.
This report shares OONI data on the blocking of Grindr in Jordan.</description></item><item><title>How Internet censorship changed in Russia during the 1st year of military conflict in Ukraine</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-russia-a-year-after-the-conflict/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-russia-a-year-after-the-conflict/</guid><description>As of today, last year, Russia started its military operation in Ukraine. This was followed by increased levels of internet censorship, as Internet Service Providers (ISPs) in Russia started blocking access to several news media websites. In early March 2022, OONI published a report documenting these blocks, as well as the blocking of a site (200rf.com) that shares information about captured and killed Russian soldiers in Ukraine. OONI also reported that Russian ISPs started throttling access to Twitter on 26th February 2022, and switched to blocking it by 4th March 2022 – at which point, they also started blocking access to Facebook.</description></item><item><title>iMAP State of Internet Censorship Report 2022 - Hong Kong</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-hong-kong/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-hong-kong/</guid><description>Hong Kong, a place geographically conjunct to the soil of Mainland China, has been previously known as a free society, endured and still enduring multiple historical occasions. Once, there was no nationwide internet censorship until the latest development that local authorities and Beijing forcefully implemented the Hong Kong national security law in late June 2020. Currently, at least four websites are known to be censored, and a few ongoing discussions among pro-Beijing parties and the government to put censorship up on instant messaging and social platforms.</description></item><item><title>iMAP State of Internet Censorship Report 2022 - Indonesia</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-indonesia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-indonesia/</guid><description>In July 2014, Regulation of the Minister of Communications and Informatics Number 19 of 2014 on the Handling of Negative Internet Sites came into force as part of the regulator&amp;rsquo;s programme for Healthy and Safe Internet (INSAN or Internet Sehat dan Aman). The law mandated ISPs to block any internet content that is deemed to carry &amp;ldquo;negative&amp;rdquo; elements such as pornography, hoaxes, or SARA conflicts.
As of September 2022, the Indonesian Ministry of Information and Communication (Kominfo) has blocked over 1,000,000 websites through TrustPositif,1 a filtering application that has been operational since 2010 per Ministerial Regulation No 19 of 2014.</description></item><item><title>iMAP State of Internet Censorship Report 2022 - Malaysia</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-malaysia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-malaysia/</guid><description>It is a codified guarantee that the internet will not be censored except for illegal, obscene and indecent content, while in reality the extent of censorship and its implementation are wider than projected and remain to be explored.
Diterjemah ke dalam bahasa Melayu
The Ministry of Communications and Multimedia (MCMC) do not publish list of blocked sites, however statements were released from time to time to announce the number of sites blocked.</description></item><item><title>iMAP State of Internet Censorship Report 2022 - Thailand</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-thailand/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-thailand/</guid><description>Thailand, a country situated on the mainland of Southeast Asia, was under military junta for five years from 2014 to 2019. Upon the general election in 2019, the country has been nominally a parliamentary constitutional monarchy, although with lèse-majesté laws continuing to be invoked especially with regard to internet censorship. Adding the COVID-19 pandemic into the picture, the Thai government introduced Regulation 29 to curb fake news, which led to reported incidences of internet censorship.</description></item><item><title>iMAP State of Internet Censorship Report 2022 - Vietnam</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-vietnam/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-vietnam/</guid><description>Swedish Ambassador to Vietnam Pereric Högberg affirmed that Vietnam is making good use of opportunities from the internet, being one of the leading countries in Southeast Asia in terms of internet connection and development1. Vietnam is not limited to using the Internet and social networks2. However, there are still websites with controlled access in Vietnam.
Dịch sang tiếng Việt
Under the authoritarian political system, freedom of assembly, association, expression, press and religion, as well as civil society activism, is tightly restricted and controlled by the party despite legislation recognising civil and political rights in the Constitution.</description></item><item><title>No Access: LGBTIQ Website Censorship in Six Countries</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-no-access-lgbtiq-website-censorship-six-countries/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-no-access-lgbtiq-website-censorship-six-countries/</guid><description>Today, in collaboration with OutRight Action International and the Citizen Lab, we are excited to share our new research report, “No Access: LGBTIQ Website Censorship in Six Countries”, which examines the blocking of LGBTIQ websites in Indonesia, Malaysia, Iran, Russia, Saudi Arabia, and the United Arab Emirates (UAE).
READ FULL REPORT
Annotated Bibliography
Below we share some of our key research findings.
Summary of findings We joined forces with OutRight Action International and the Citizen Lab to examine the blocking of LGBTIQ websites in six countries: Indonesia, Malaysia, Iran, Russia, Saudi Arabia, and the United Arab Emirates (UAE).</description></item><item><title>Belarus protests: From internet outages to pervasive website censorship</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-belarus-internet-outages-website-censorship/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-belarus-internet-outages-website-censorship/</guid><description>Image: Block page served in Belarus.
This report was prepared in collaboration with Human Constanta and the Digital Observers Community Belarus.
More than 70 websites have been blocked in Belarus over the last weeks, following a controversial presidential election and amid ongoing anti-government protests. Many of the blocked sites include news media and are related to the elections, while several other sites expressing political criticism were blocked as well. At the time of writing, many of these sites remain blocked in Belarus.</description></item><item><title>Evaluating OONI’s New Measurement Engine in the Context of the Blocking of Women on Web in Spain</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-engine-evaluation-spain/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-engine-evaluation-spain/</guid><description>Reproduction rights site www.womenonweb.org has been blocked in Spain over the last months by several local Internet Service Providers (ISPs). Once Spanish hacktivist communities noticed that www.womenonweb.org was inaccessible, they coordinated on running OONI Probe tests to collect measurement data that could serve as evidence. The findings of this investigation have been published in an excellent report, whose writing was coordinated by our former colleague, Vasilis Ververis.
We were involved in the technical review of the report.</description></item><item><title>Call to Action: Let’s measure the blocking of LGBTQI websites around the world!</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-measure-blocking-lgbtqi-sites/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-measure-blocking-lgbtqi-sites/</guid><description>LGBTQI websites are blocked in several countries around the world, such as Malaysia and Indonesia. This includes popular dating apps and sites, like grindr, which is blocked in Lebanon and Iran.
How can we track the blocking of LGBTQI sites around the world?
We have teamed up with OutRight Action International &amp;ndash; a leading international LGBTQI human rights organization &amp;ndash; to investigate the blocking of LGBTQI sites worldwide.
We invite you to contribute to this research!</description></item><item><title>On the blocking of abortion rights websites: Women on Waves &amp; Women on Web</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-blocking-abortion-rights-websites-women-on-waves-web/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-blocking-abortion-rights-websites-women-on-waves-web/</guid><description>Image: By Clarote (Coding Rights)
Read the Portuguese version by Coding Rights.
View the report&amp;rsquo;s press coverage by The Intercept.
As abortion remains partially or totally criminalized in numerous countries, the fight to promote sexual and reproductive rights, as well as women&amp;rsquo;s health, also relies on access to information. But recently, we were told that the website of the abortion rights non-governmental organization womeonwaves.org, which provides reproductive health services and education to women in countries with restrictive abortion laws, was inaccessible in Brazil.</description></item><item><title>Ethiopia: Verifying the unblocking of websites</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-unblocking/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 19:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-unblocking/</guid><description>Pro PM Abiy Ahmed Rally at Meskel Square, June 2018 - Photo by Berhan Taye
On 22nd June 2018, the Ethiopian government reported that it had unblocked 264 websites. This (great) news was also reported by ESAT, a major Ethiopian media website that was blocked over the last years.
Today, OONI and Access Now publish new research based on the testing of sites that were previously found to be blocked, in an attempt to examine whether they have in fact been unblocked in recent days.</description></item><item><title>Internet Censorship in Pakistan: Findings from 2014-2017</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/pakistan-internet-censorship/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/pakistan-internet-censorship/</guid><description>Islamabad: Political dissent in Pakistan under threat, government censors online content - PC: Haroon Baloch
A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) and Bytes for All Pakistan.
Table of contents
Key Findings
Introduction
Background
Network landscape and internet penetration
Legal environment
Freedom of expression
Press freedom
Access to information
Privacy and digital surveillance
Censorship
Reported cases of internet censorship and surveillance
Methodology: Measuring internet censorship in Pakistan</description></item><item><title>Internet Censorship in Iran: Network Measurement Findings from 2014-2017</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/iran-internet-censorship/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/iran-internet-censorship/</guid><description>Image: Blockpage in Iran
A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI), ASL19, ARTICLE 19, and Small Media.
Table of contents
Key Findings
Introduction
Background
Network landscape
Internet use
Legal environment
Reported cases of internet censorship
Methodology: Measuring internet censorship in Iran
Review of the Citizen Lab&amp;rsquo;s test list for Iran
OONI network measurement testing
Web Connectivity
HTTP Invalid Request Line
HTTP Header Field Manipulation
Vanilla Tor test</description></item><item><title>Measuring Internet Censorship in Cuba's ParkNets</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/cuba-internet-censorship-2017/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/cuba-internet-censorship-2017/</guid><description>Image by Arturo Filastò (CC-BY-SA-3.0) A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI)
View the pdf version of the report here.
Table of contents
Key Findings
Introduction
Background
Network landscape and internet penetration
ETECSA
ParkNets
Joven Club
StreetNets
El Paquete
Summary
Measuring Internet Censorship in Cuba
Methodology
Collection and analysis of OONI Probe network measurements
Custom tests
Findings
Blocked websites
News Media
Political Criticism
Human Rights Issues</description></item><item><title>The State of Internet Censorship in Indonesia</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/indonesia-internet-censorship/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/indonesia-internet-censorship/</guid><description>Image: Block page in Indonesia
A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) and Sinar Project.
Table of contents
Key Findings
Introduction
Background
Network landscape and internet penetration
Legal environment
Freedom of expression
Press freedom
Access to information
Privacy
Censorship and surveillance
Reported cases of internet censorship and surveillance
Examining internet censorship in Indonesia
Methodology
Collection of OONI Probe network measurements
Web Connectivity
HTTP Invalid Request Line</description></item><item><title>Ethiopia: Evidence of social media blocking and internet censorship</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-report/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-report/</guid><description>Youth in Addis trying to get Wi-Fi Connection. Credit Addis Fortune Newspaper
Recently we published a post about what appeared to be a possible internet shutdown in Ethiopia during a wave of ongoing protests by ethnic groups. Today, in collaboration with Amnesty International we are releasing a report that includes evidence of recent censorship events during Ethiopia’s political upheaval.
See the Amharic translation of the report. Translated by Wolete Mariam.</description></item></channel></rss>