<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Otf on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/otf/</link><description>Recent content in Otf on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/otf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Support the OTF: Support a Free and Open Internet</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-support-otf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-support-otf/</guid><description>&lt;p>Over the last month, the &lt;a href="https://www.opentech.fund/">Open Technology Fund (OTF)&lt;/a> &amp;ndash; &lt;em>one of the main funders of free
censorship circumvention and privacy-enhancing technologies that human
rights defenders worldwide rely on&lt;/em> &amp;ndash; has been under threat, following
the &lt;a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2020/06/17/media/us-agency-for-global-media-michael-pack/index.html">ousting of its leadership&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We previously published a &lt;a href="https://ooni.org/post/2020-06-19-save-internet-freedom-support-the-open-technology-fund/">statement in support of the OTF&lt;/a>,
explaining &lt;strong>why we think the OTF is essential for internet freedom&lt;/strong>
and encouraging the public to &lt;a href="https://saveinternetfreedom.tech/">sign the letter to congress&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this post, we share our experience working with the OTF, and discuss
how they have played a crucial role in supporting the fight against
internet censorship worldwide.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Save Internet Freedom: Support the Open Technology Fund</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-06-19-save-internet-freedom-support-the-open-technology-fund/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 16:48:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-06-19-save-internet-freedom-support-the-open-technology-fund/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last Wednesday was &lt;a href="https://edition.cnn.com/2020/06/17/media/us-agency-for-global-media-michael-pack/index.html">dubbed&lt;/a> as a “Wednesday night massacre”, following the firing of the directors of four organizations overseen by the &lt;a href="https://www.usagm.gov/">US Agency for Global Media (USAGM)&lt;/a>: Radio Free Asia, Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, Middle East Broadcasting, and the Open Technology Fund (OTF).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Out of these four organizations, we would like to draw your attention to the &lt;a href="https://www.opentech.fund/">OTF&lt;/a>, not only because they have been a long-term funder of our project but, more importantly, because they have been essential in creating the internet freedom community as we know it.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>