<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>country-br on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/country-br/</link><description>Recent content in country-br on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/country-br/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Brazil: OONI data on the blocking of Telegram</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-brazil-telegram/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-brazil-telegram/</guid><description>Encontre a versão em português do relatório localizada pela Coding Rights aqui: https://codingrights.org/library-item/brasil-dados-da-ooni-sobre-o-bloqueio-do-telegram/
Two days ago, on 26th April 2023, Brazil started blocking access to Telegram.
On the same day, a federal judge in Brazil reportedly ordered the temporary suspension of Telegram in response to the messaging service’s alleged failure to share all information on neo-Nazi chat groups requested by the police. This information was reportedly requested as part of a school attacks inquiry, as Brazilian authorities investigate neo-Nazi groups that are believed to have used Telegram to incite school attacks.</description></item><item><title>On the blocking of abortion rights websites: Women on Waves &amp; Women on Web</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-blocking-abortion-rights-websites-women-on-waves-web/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-blocking-abortion-rights-websites-women-on-waves-web/</guid><description>Image: By Clarote (Coding Rights)
Read the Portuguese version by Coding Rights.
View the report&amp;rsquo;s press coverage by The Intercept.
As abortion remains partially or totally criminalized in numerous countries, the fight to promote sexual and reproductive rights, as well as women&amp;rsquo;s health, also relies on access to information. But recently, we were told that the website of the abortion rights non-governmental organization womeonwaves.org, which provides reproductive health services and education to women in countries with restrictive abortion laws, was inaccessible in Brazil.</description></item><item><title>OONI Data Reveals How WhatsApp Was Blocked (Again) in Brazil</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/brazil-whatsapp-block/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/brazil-whatsapp-block/</guid><description>Country: Brazil
Probed ISPs: Tim mobile (AS 26615), Oi landline (AS 7738)
Censorship method: DNS Hijacking
OONI tests: HTTP Requests, DNS Consistency
Measurement period: 2016-05-02 - 2016-05-03
19:10 UTC Saturday, 7 May 2016 Update: Add OONI Explorer measurements links
Ever since WhatsApp implemented end-to-end encryption to protect the privacy and security of its 1 billion users worldwide, several cases of censorship have been ordered by governments who are frustrated with the fact that they can no longer access users&amp;rsquo; private communications.</description></item></channel></rss>