<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>country-tr on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/country-tr/</link><description>Recent content in country-tr on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/country-tr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Turkey: Throttling and DNS blocking of Twitter following deadly earthquake</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-turkey-throttling-blocking-twitter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-turkey-throttling-blocking-twitter/</guid><description>On 6th February 2023, a devastating 7.8-magnitude earthquake (followed by many strong aftershocks) struck (southern and central) Turkey and (northern and western) Syria, resulting in more than 36,000 deaths.
In the aftermath of the earthquake (on 8th February 2023), access to Twitter was reportedly temporarily restricted. OONI data collected from Turkey provides evidence that the block was implemented through targeted throttling and DNS interference.
The following chart aggregates OONI measurement coverage from the testing of Twitter (twitter.</description></item><item><title>On the blocking of abortion rights websites: Women on Waves &amp; Women on Web</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-blocking-abortion-rights-websites-women-on-waves-web/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-blocking-abortion-rights-websites-women-on-waves-web/</guid><description>Image: By Clarote (Coding Rights)
Read the Portuguese version by Coding Rights.
View the report&amp;rsquo;s press coverage by The Intercept.
As abortion remains partially or totally criminalized in numerous countries, the fight to promote sexual and reproductive rights, as well as women&amp;rsquo;s health, also relies on access to information. But recently, we were told that the website of the abortion rights non-governmental organization womeonwaves.org, which provides reproductive health services and education to women in countries with restrictive abortion laws, was inaccessible in Brazil.</description></item><item><title>Internet Access Disruption in Turkey - July 2016</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/turkey-internet-access-disruption/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/turkey-internet-access-disruption/</guid><description>With the attempted coup in Turkey, reports went out about social media being throttled and/or blocked. We analysed data about this that we collected with RIPE Atlas and the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI).
On 15 July, a coup was attempted in Turkey. We heard about social media being throttled and/or blocked, but much was unclear about what was actually going on. Here we present measurement data from various platforms that shared their data publicly.</description></item></channel></rss>