<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>censorship on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/censorship/</link><description>Recent content in censorship on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/censorship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Technical multi-stakeholder report on Internet shutdowns: The case of Iran amid autumn 2022 protests</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-iran-technical-multistakeholder-report/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-iran-technical-multistakeholder-report/</guid><description>Coordinators: OONI, ISOC Contributors: OONI, IODA, Measurement Lab (M-Lab), Cloudflare, Kentik, Censored Planet, ISOC, Article19 Facilitators: European Commission, United States This report shares empirical technical findings on the recent Internet shutdown events that emerged in Iran following the death of Jhina (Mahsa) Amini in September 2022. The report is intended to be the first among a series of multi-stakeholder reports aimed at shedding light on what is becoming a widespread and increasingly sophisticated practice of certain governments around the world.</description></item><item><title>Iran blocks social media, app stores and encrypted DNS amid Mahsa Amini protests</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-iran-blocks-social-media-mahsa-amini-protests/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-iran-blocks-social-media-mahsa-amini-protests/</guid><description>Protests erupted in Iran over the last week following the death of Mahsa Amini, a 22-year-old Kurdish woman who was reportedly beaten to death by Iran’s morality police for allegedly violating strict hijab rules. Amid the ongoing protests, which have reportedly resulted in at least 31 civilian deaths, Iranian authorities cracked down on the internet in an attempt to curb dissent.
Over the past week, Iran experienced severe mobile network outages, in addition to increased levels of internet censorship.</description></item><item><title>Azerbaijan and Armenia block TikTok amid border clashes</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-azerbaijan-and-armenia-blocks-tiktok/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-azerbaijan-and-armenia-blocks-tiktok/</guid><description>Earlier this week, on 12th September 2022, fighting erupted between Azerbaijani and Armenian troops along their border. Over the next few days, community members in Azerbaijan reported that the TikTok app was blocked locally.
We analyzed OONI network measurement data to investigate the block. We found that TikTok has been blocked in both Azerbaijan and Armenia over the last few days.
In this report, we share our technical findings. In both Armenia and Azerbaijan, we found TLS and DNS level interference of TikTok domains and endpoints during the border clashes.</description></item><item><title>Measuring DoT/DoH Blocking Using OONI Probe: A Preliminary Study</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-doh-dot-paper-dnsprivacy21/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-doh-dot-paper-dnsprivacy21/</guid><description>When you enter a URL such as https://example.com/, under the hood, your web browser resolves the example.com domain to one or more IP addresses using the Domain Name System (DNS), a set of federated servers and protocols providing this name-to-IP-address mapping. For example, as of 2022-06-16, example.com resolves to the 93.184.216.34 (IPv4) and 2606:2800:220:1:248:1893:25c8:1946 (IPv6) addresses. Once it knows the IP addresses for the domain, the browser then uses them to fetch the requested webpage.</description></item><item><title>A Quick Look at QUIC Censorship</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-quick-look-quic-censorship/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-quick-look-quic-censorship/</guid><description>This blog post was originally published by the Open Technology Fund to disseminate Kathrin Elmenhorst&amp;rsquo;s QUIC-and-HTTP/3 censorship research as part of her ICFP fellowship with OONI.
Last year, the new network protocol QUIC was introduced. QUIC is a general-purpose transport layer network with the goal of reducing latency compared to existing protocols. Since the introduction of QUIC, we have seen rising volumes of QUIC-based web traffic in the form of HTTP/3.</description></item><item><title>New blocks emerge in Russia amid war in Ukraine: An OONI network measurement analysis</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-russia-blocks-amid-ru-ua-conflict/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-russia-blocks-amid-ru-ua-conflict/</guid><description>Information controls are known to occur during conflicts, and that’s exactly what we’re seeing in Russia following the recent invasion of Ukraine on 24th February 2022.
In recent days, OONI network measurement data collected from Russia shows that many Internet Service Providers (ISPs) have started blocking access to several news media websites, as well as to a website (200rf.com) that shares information about captured and killed Russian soldiers in Ukraine. OONI data also shows that Russian ISPs started throttling access to Twitter on 26th February 2022, and switched to blocking it by 4th March 2022 – at which point, they also started blocking access to Facebook.</description></item><item><title>Measuring HTTP/3 censorship with OONI Probe</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-http3-measurements-paper/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-http3-measurements-paper/</guid><description>Last year, QUIC emerged as a new internet protocol for creating reliable connections and encrypting communications between clients over the new HTTP/3 protocol. Observing the emergence and growing deployment of HTTP/3, we want to enable OONI Probe to measure HTTP/3 censorship and monitor how censors respond and adapt to technical innovation.
We therefore added HTTP/3 support (in early 2021) into OONI Probe (through our urlgetter research tool) to conduct measurements in China, Iran, India and Kazakhstan to investigate the state of HTTP/3 censorship in these countries.</description></item><item><title>Russia started blocking Tor</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-russia-blocks-tor/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-russia-blocks-tor/</guid><description>On 1st December 2021, some Internet Service Providers (ISPs) in Russia started blocking access to the Tor anonymity network.
In this report, we share OONI network measurement data on the blocking of the Tor network and www.torproject.org in Russia.
About Tor
Methods
Findings
Blocking of the Tor network
Blocking of the Tor Project website
Conclusion
Acknowledgements</description></item><item><title>A multi-perspective view of Internet censorship in Myanmar</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-multiperspective-view-internet-censorship-myanmar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-multiperspective-view-internet-censorship-myanmar/</guid><description>In the wake of a military coup in February 2021, Myanmar experienced unprecedented levels of internet censorship.
In response, we collaborated with CAIDA’s Internet Outage Detection and Analysis (IODA) team and Myanmar ICT for Development Organization (MIDO) on publishing a research report which documents a series of nightly internet outages and the blocking of social media, Wikipedia, and circumvention tool sites in Myanmar following the military coup.
In the months that followed, we continued to examine internet censorship in Myanmar quite closely.</description></item><item><title>How countries attempt to block Signal Private Messenger App around the world</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-how-signal-private-messenger-blocked-around-the-world/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-how-signal-private-messenger-blocked-around-the-world/</guid><description>Signal Private Messenger, commonly used by human rights defenders worldwide, is widely considered the state-of-the-art app for private and secure communications. But as its popularity surged recently, we have started to observe its blocking in several countries.
In this report, we share our analysis of OONI network measurement data on the blocking of the Signal Private Messenger app in Iran, China, Cuba, and Uzbekistan.
Currently, circumvention is enabled by default for Signal users in Iran, Egypt, Oman, Qatar, and the UAE.</description></item><item><title>Italy blocks Gutenberg book publishing website</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-italy-blocks-gutenberg-book-publishing-website/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-italy-blocks-gutenberg-book-publishing-website/</guid><description>Cases of internet censorship (that affect public interest) are rarely reported in Europe. Yet, www.gutenberg.org, a book-publishing website run by a non-profit organization, has been blocked in Italy since May 2020.
In this report, we share OONI network measurement data on the ongoing blocking of www.gutenberg.org across networks in Italy.
Background
Methods
Findings
Blocking methods by ISP
Vodafone Italia (AS30722)</description></item><item><title>No Access: LGBTIQ Website Censorship in Six Countries</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-no-access-lgbtiq-website-censorship-six-countries/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-no-access-lgbtiq-website-censorship-six-countries/</guid><description>Today, in collaboration with OutRight Action International and the Citizen Lab, we are excited to share our new research report, “No Access: LGBTIQ Website Censorship in Six Countries”, which examines the blocking of LGBTIQ websites in Indonesia, Malaysia, Iran, Russia, Saudi Arabia, and the United Arab Emirates (UAE).
READ FULL REPORT
Annotated Bibliography
Below we share some of our key research findings.
Summary of findings We joined forces with OutRight Action International and the Citizen Lab to examine the blocking of LGBTIQ websites in six countries: Indonesia, Malaysia, Iran, Russia, Saudi Arabia, and the United Arab Emirates (UAE).</description></item><item><title>Zambia: Social media blocked amid 2021 general elections</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-zambia-social-media-blocks-amid-elections/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-zambia-social-media-blocks-amid-elections/</guid><description>Recently, on 12th August 2021, general elections were held in Zambia, during which access to popular online social media platforms was reportedly blocked.
In this report, we share relevant OONI data on the blocking of WhatsApp, Twitter, and Facebook amid Zambia’s 2021 general election.
Background
Methods
Findings
Blocking of WhatsApp
Blocking of Twitter and Facebook
Conclusion</description></item><item><title>Media censorship in Azerbaijan through the lens of network measurement</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-azerbaijan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-azerbaijan/</guid><description>Key Findings Introduction Methods OONI network measurement Acknowledgement of limitations Background Network landscape and internet penetration Legal environment Internet censorship and media freedom environment Findings Blocked news media websites Blocking of social media amid 2020 Nagorno-Karabakh war Blocking of social media websites Blocking of instant messaging apps WhatsApp Telegram Blocked circumvention tool sites Tor and Psiphon Conclusion Acknowledgements Key Findings As part of our analysis of OONI measurements collected from Azerbaijan between January 2020 to May 2021, we found:</description></item><item><title>Myanmar: Data on internet blocks and internet outages following military coup</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-myanmar-internet-blocks-and-outages/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-myanmar-internet-blocks-and-outages/</guid><description>On 1st February 2021, the military in Myanmar carried out a coup d’etat, seizing power and detaining the country’s State Counsellor (equivalent to a prime minister) and other democratically elected leaders.
A few days after the coup, ISPs in Myanmar started blocking access to Facebook services. On 5th February 2021, they started blocking access to Twitter and Instagram as well. On 6th February 2021, access to the internet was shut down entirely for nearly 30 hours.</description></item><item><title>Uganda: Data on internet blocks and nationwide internet outage amid 2021 general election</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-uganda-general-election-blocks-and-outage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-uganda-general-election-blocks-and-outage/</guid><description>Last week, amid its 2021 general election, Uganda was disconnected from the internet entirely. The country experienced a widespread internet blackout that lasted 4 days, starting on the eve of the election (13th January 2021) and ending in the morning of 18th January 2021. In the days leading up to the election, access to major social media platforms and circumvention tools was blocked &amp;ndash; even when the OTT (Over the Top) tax (commonly referred to as the “Social Media Tax”) was paid.</description></item><item><title>Investigating Encrypted DNS Blocking in India</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-encrypted-dns-blocking-india/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-encrypted-dns-blocking-india/</guid><description>In October 2020, we collaborated with Divyank Katira and Gurshabad Grover, researchers at the Centre for Internet &amp;amp; Society, India, to implement and evaluate a new OONI experiment focused on detecting DNS censorship.
This new OONI experiment, called dnscheck, focuses on detecting the blocking of encrypted DNS transports such as DNS over TLS and DNS over HTTPS. Its methodology improves upon the measurement methodology OONI previously used to measure DoT blocking in Iran.</description></item><item><title>Tanzania blocks social media (and Tor?) on election day</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-tanzania-blocks-social-media-tor-election-day/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-tanzania-blocks-social-media-tor-election-day/</guid><description>Starting from yesterday (27th October 2020) &amp;ndash; on the eve of Tanzania&amp;rsquo;s 2020 general election &amp;ndash; OONI measurements continue to show the ongoing blocking of social media (and of the Tor circumvention tool) in Tanzania.
In this report, we share OONI data collected from Tanzania on these blocks, as well as relevant instructions for further OONI Probe testing.
Methods
Blocking of social media</description></item><item><title>Belarus protests: From internet outages to pervasive website censorship</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-belarus-internet-outages-website-censorship/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-belarus-internet-outages-website-censorship/</guid><description>Image: Block page served in Belarus.
This report was prepared in collaboration with Human Constanta and the Digital Observers Community Belarus.
More than 70 websites have been blocked in Belarus over the last weeks, following a controversial presidential election and amid ongoing anti-government protests. Many of the blocked sites include news media and are related to the elections, while several other sites expressing political criticism were blocked as well.</description></item><item><title>Investigating TLS blocking in India</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-tls-blocking-india/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-tls-blocking-india/</guid><description>This report investigates Transport Layer Security (TLS)-based blocking in India. Previous research by the Centre for Internet &amp;amp; Society, India (CIS) has already exposed TLS blocking based on the value of the SNI field. OONI has also implemented and started testing SNI-based TLS blocking measurements.
Recently, the Magma Project documented cases where CIS India and OONI&amp;rsquo;s methodologies could be improved. They specifically found that blocking sometimes appears to depend not only on the value of the SNI field but also on the address of the web server being used.</description></item><item><title>DNS over TLS blocked in Iran</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-iran-dot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-iran-dot/</guid><description>DNS over TLS (DoT) is a network protocol that allows one to use DNS over TLS (i.e. with encryption and authentication of the remote DNS server).
We investigated whether DoT works in Iran by gathering a list of 31 well-known DoT endpoints and running experiments from four distinct Iranian mobile and fixed-line Internet Service Providers (ISPs): MCI, TCI, Irancell, and Shatel.
We discovered that:
57% of the endpoints are blocked on a least one ISP;</description></item><item><title>Those Unspoken Thoughts: A study of censorship and media freedom in Manipur, India</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-those-unspoken-thoughts-otf-fellow-report/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-those-unspoken-thoughts-otf-fellow-report/</guid><description>This research report was produced by OTF Information Controls Fellow, Chinmayi S K. OONI served as her host organization throughout her fellowship.
Read full report The northeastern Indian state of Manipur has long been an area of conflict and crackdowns. But although human rights violations are well documented in the state, few studies have examined the impact of censorship and internet shutdowns in the region. In 2019, research fellow Chinmayi S K sought to address this critical gap by documenting the blocking of websites in Manipur and assessing how the use of information controls in the state compares to that in the rest of India.</description></item><item><title>Evaluating OONI’s New Measurement Engine in the Context of the Blocking of Women on Web in Spain</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-engine-evaluation-spain/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-engine-evaluation-spain/</guid><description>Reproduction rights site www.womenonweb.org has been blocked in Spain over the last months by several local Internet Service Providers (ISPs). Once Spanish hacktivist communities noticed that www.womenonweb.org was inaccessible, they coordinated on running OONI Probe tests to collect measurement data that could serve as evidence. The findings of this investigation have been published in an excellent report, whose writing was coordinated by our former colleague, Vasilis Ververis.
We were involved in the technical review of the report.</description></item><item><title>Burundi blocks social media amid 2020 general election</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-burundi-blocks-social-media-amid-election/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-burundi-blocks-social-media-amid-election/</guid><description>Yesterday, access to social media was reportedly blocked in Burundi amid its 2020 general election.
The lead-up to the election was marred by violence and unrest, as seven candidates vied to replace Incumbent President Nkurunziza, who has been in power over the last 15 years. Despite widespread deadly protests and a coup attempt, President Nkurunziza won a third term in 2015 following disputed elections. While President Nkurunziza reportedly announced that he would not contest the next elections, he is set to become a “supreme guide to patriotism” as he steps down now in 2020.</description></item><item><title>Myanmar blocks “fake news” websites amid COVID-19 pandemic</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-myanmar-blocks-websites-amid-covid19/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-myanmar-blocks-websites-amid-covid19/</guid><description>In March 2020, Internet Service Providers (ISPs) in Myanmar received a directive from the Ministry of Transport and Communications to block 230 websites, most of which contain adult content. However, 67 of these sites were blocked on the grounds of spreading “fake news”. The list of these 230 websites has not been published.
In an attempt to potentially identify the newly blocked websites, we analyzed OONI network measurements collected from Myanmar over the last months, between 1st January 2020 to 9th April 2020.</description></item><item><title>Measuring SNI based blocking in Iran</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-iran-sni-blocking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-iran-sni-blocking/</guid><description>In this blog post we start evaluating OONI&amp;rsquo;s new SNI blocking experiment. To this end, we will use measurements performed in Iran, where the blocking technique measured by this experiment is deployed.
OONI&amp;rsquo;s SNI blocking experiment discovers cases where a Client Hello packet carrying a specific SNI triggers blocking. In this context, SNI means Server Name Indication. It is an extension to the Transport Layer Security (TLS) protocol that allows a client to specify the domain name that it wants an HTTP server to serve.</description></item><item><title>Launched: New OONI Probe Desktop App for Windows and macOS</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-ooni-probe-desktop-app/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-ooni-probe-desktop-app/</guid><description>Today, OONI is thrilled to announce the public launch of the new OONI Probe desktop app that you can download and install on Windows and macOS to measure internet censorship and network performance.
Install OONI Probe Desktop app By running the tests in the new OONI Probe desktop app, you can measure:
Blocking of websites;
Blocking of WhatsApp, Facebook Messenger, and Telegram;</description></item><item><title>Iran temporarily blocks the Farsi language edition of Wikipedia</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-iran-blocks-farsi-wikipedia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-iran-blocks-farsi-wikipedia/</guid><description>Over the last days, between 2nd to 3rd March 2020, OONI measurements collected from 6 different networks in Iran showed that access to the Farsi edition of Wikipedia (fa.wikipedia.org) was temporarily blocked by means of DNS tampering and SNI filtering.
In this post, we share relevant OONI data.
Blocking of Farsi Wikipedia and Wikinews In the past, Iran mainly blocked the HTTP version of specific Wikipedia articles. But over the last years, this probably wasn’t very noticeable because Wikipedia used HTTPS with HSTS enabled, meaning that Iranian internet users could easily access the censored pages.</description></item><item><title>Togo: Instant messaging apps blocked amid 2020 presidential election</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-togo-blocks-instant-messaging-apps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-togo-blocks-instant-messaging-apps/</guid><description>Last Saturday, on 22nd February 2020, presidential elections were held in Togo. These elections follow a wave of protests over the last years against the 53-year rule of Gnassingbe Eyadema and, subsequently, his son, Faure Gnassingbe. A few days before the election, non-partisan election monitoring was restricted as National Democratic Institute (NDI) staff were expelled from the country. According to preliminary results from the electoral commission, incumbent President Faure Gnassingbe won re-election.</description></item><item><title>Call to Action: Let’s measure the blocking of LGBTQI websites around the world!</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-measure-blocking-lgbtqi-sites/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-measure-blocking-lgbtqi-sites/</guid><description>LGBTQI websites are blocked in several countries around the world, such as Malaysia and Indonesia. This includes popular dating apps and sites, like grindr, which is blocked in Lebanon and Iran.
How can we track the blocking of LGBTQI sites around the world?
We have teamed up with OutRight Action International &amp;ndash; a leading international LGBTQI human rights organization &amp;ndash; to investigate the blocking of LGBTQI sites worldwide.
We invite you to contribute to this research!</description></item><item><title>Iran’s nation-wide Internet blackout: Measurement data and technical observations</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-iran-internet-blackout/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-iran-internet-blackout/</guid><description>Over the last week, Iran experienced a nation-wide Internet blackout.
Most Iranians were barred from connecting to the global Internet and the outside world, but they had access to Iran’s national Intranet: the domestic network that hosts Iranian websites and services—all under the government’s watch.
This major Internet blackout was rolled out on 16th November 2019, right after protests erupted across multiple cities in Iran. The protests (against economic mismanagement and government corruption) were sparked by the government’s abrupt announcement to increase the price of fuel (as much as 300%) and to impose a strict rationing system.</description></item><item><title>On the blocking of abortion rights websites: Women on Waves &amp; Women on Web</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-blocking-abortion-rights-websites-women-on-waves-web/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-blocking-abortion-rights-websites-women-on-waves-web/</guid><description>Image: By Clarote (Coding Rights)
Read the Portuguese version by Coding Rights.
View the report&amp;rsquo;s press coverage by The Intercept.
As abortion remains partially or totally criminalized in numerous countries, the fight to promote sexual and reproductive rights, as well as women&amp;rsquo;s health, also relies on access to information. But recently, we were told that the website of the abortion rights non-governmental organization womeonwaves.org, which provides reproductive health services and education to women in countries with restrictive abortion laws, was inaccessible in Brazil.</description></item><item><title>Egypt blocks BBC and Alhurra: Expanding media censorship amid political unrest</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-egypt-blocks-bbc-and-alhurra/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-egypt-blocks-bbc-and-alhurra/</guid><description>Last weekend, protests erupted in Egypt in response to corruption allegations against President Abdul Fattah al-Sisi’s government.
Protests have been rare since President Sisi took power in 2014, but amid policies of economic austerity and recent corruption allegations, hundreds of Egyptians took to the streets. It was subsequently reported that BBC News and the US-funded Alhurra news website were amongst blocked services. The head of Egypt’s Supreme Council for Media Regulation reportedly stated that the BBC and other news websites may have been blocked because of their “inaccurate” coverage of the protests.</description></item><item><title>Ethiopia: From internet blackouts to the blocking of WhatsApp and Telegram</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-whatsapp-telegram/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-whatsapp-telegram/</guid><description>Communication access in Ethiopia has significantly been disrupted over the last week. Internet access and Short Message Services (SMS) were disconnected intermittently across the country. During the first half of the week, internet connectivity was shut down completely. After access was restored, both WhatsApp and Telegram were blocked. A few days ago, Ethio Telecom (the only telecom in the country) published a notice, acknowledging the internet disruptions, but came short on details about the extent of communication disruptions or why they occurred in the first place.</description></item><item><title>Nigeria’s 2019 elections through the lens of network measurements</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-nigeria-internet-censorship/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-nigeria-internet-censorship/</guid><description>Censorship events are increasingly being reported during political events in Africa (and elsewhere around the world). A few examples include the social media disruptions in Mali amid its 2018 presidential election, the blocking of social media in Uganda during its 2016 general elections, and the complete internet blackout in The Gambia during its 2016 presidential election.
Leading up to and during Nigeria’s 2019 general elections, we collaborated with our local partner, Paradigm Initiative, on measuring networks in the country to monitor potential censorship events.</description></item><item><title>Benin: Social media blocking and Internet blackout amid 2019 elections</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-benin-social-media-blocking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-benin-social-media-blocking/</guid><description>Two days ago, social media was reportedly blocked and access to the Internet was shutdown in Benin during its 2019 parliamentary elections.
In this report, the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) and the Center for Applied Internet Data Analysis (CAIDA) teams share OONI, IODA, and RIPE Atlas network measurement data that corroborate and provide insight into these recent censorship events in Benin.
Background
Social media blocking</description></item><item><title>Cuba blocks independent media amid 2019 constitutional referendum</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/cuba-referendum/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/cuba-referendum/</guid><description>On 24th February 2019, Cubans voted on a new constitution for the first time in decades.
But a few hours before the referendum, independent news outlet Tremenda Nota reported that their website got blocked in Cuba.
In this post, we share OONI network measurement data that confirms the blocking of tremendanota.com, as well as the blocking of several other independent media websites during the referendum.
We also found that ETECSA, Cuba’s only telecommunications company, has changed its censorship techniques, now censoring access to sites that support HTTPS by means of IP blocking.</description></item><item><title>From the blocking of Wikipedia to Social Media: Venezuela's Political Crisis</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/venezuela-blocking-wikipedia-and-social-media-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/venezuela-blocking-wikipedia-and-social-media-2019/</guid><description>As political tension escalated in Venezuela over the last few weeks, so did internet censorship.
It started off with edits to Wikipedia pages earlier this month, referencing the opposition leader, Juan Guaidó, as the President of Venezuela. This resulted in the blocking of Wikipedia. Then a group of Venezuelan soldiers circulated videos, announcing an uprising against the government of President Maduro and calling on the public to join them in the streets.</description></item><item><title>Zimbabwe protests: Social media blocking and internet blackouts</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/zimbabwe-protests-social-media-blocking-2019/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/zimbabwe-protests-social-media-blocking-2019/</guid><description>Last week, protests erupted in Zimbabwe in response to the government’s announcement that the price of fuel would more than double. According to Zimbabwe’s government, the price hikes aim to avert fuel shortages and to crackdown on the illegal trading of fuel. The new prices, however, mean that Zimbabwe now has the most expensive fuel in the world.
Zimbabwe’s fuel protests lasted for three days (14th to 17th January 2019), during which 12 people were reportedly killed and many more beaten by security forces.</description></item><item><title>The State of Internet Censorship in Venezuela</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/venezuela-internet-censorship/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/venezuela-internet-censorship/</guid><description>A study by IPYS Venezuela, Venezuela Inteligente, and the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI).
Update (2018-10-19): The section on Tor becoming accessible was added.
Key Findings
Introduction
Background
Political environment
Legal environment
Reported cases of internet censorship
Methodology: Measuring internet censorship in Venezuela
Acknowledgement of limitations Findings
Blocked websites</description></item><item><title>South Sudan: Measuring Internet Censorship in the World's Youngest Nation</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/south-sudan-censorship/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/south-sudan-censorship/</guid><description>Image by Mandavi
Established in July 2011, South Sudan is the youngest country in the world. But the transition to independence from Sudan has been far from smooth, as the country experiences an ongoing civil war. Even though internet penetration levels remain quite low, two media websites and two independent blogs were reportedly blocked last year.
This report is a joint research effort by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) and South Sudan’s The Advocates for Human Rights and Democracy (TAHURID).</description></item><item><title>Mali: Social media disruptions amid 2018 presidential election?</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/mali-disruptions-amid-2018-election/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/mali-disruptions-amid-2018-election/</guid><description>Two days ago, on 29th July 2018, Malians went to the polls to vote in presidential elections and reported that social media was inaccessible.
This is not the first time that social media is reportedly blocked in Mali. Facebook and Twitter were blocked two years ago amidst violent protests against the detention of a popular radio host. Last month, Internet Sans Frontieres reported that social media was disrupted in Mali, following a violent police crackdown on banned opposition protests calling for transparency and accountability in the 2018 presidential elections.</description></item><item><title>The State of Internet Censorship in Egypt</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/egypt-internet-censorship/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/egypt-internet-censorship/</guid><description>The report uncovers anomalies on Egyptian networks, including censorship and the hijacking of unencrypted HTTP connections for advertising and cryptocurrency mining.
Read full report in English Read full report in Arabic Read the summary of the report in Arabic
Last year, Egypt ordered the blocking of 21 news websites. OONI, a censorship measurement project under the Tor Project, responded by publishing a report on the blocking of (at least) 10 media websites, including Mada Masr and Al Jazeera.</description></item><item><title>Nigeria: Measuring Internet Censorship</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/nigeria-internet-censorship/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/nigeria-internet-censorship/</guid><description>Last October, Nigeria’s National Communications Commission (NCC) reportedly ordered the blocking of 21 websites. In response, we collaborated with Nigeria’s Paradigm Initiative to test those websites and collect network measurement data that can shed light on whether and how they’re blocked.
Our findings are included in a joint research report that we published today with Paradigm Initiative. The full report, titled “Tightening the Noose on Freedom of Expression: Status of Internet Freedom in Nigeria 2018”, can be downloaded here.</description></item><item><title>ParkNet: Short Documentary on Internet Censorship in Cuba</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/parknet-short-documentary-cuba/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/parknet-short-documentary-cuba/</guid><description>Last year we had the opportunity to travel to Cuba to explore its internet landscape. We spent most of our time hopping from one public WiFi hotspot to another, measuring networks in Havana, Santa Clara, and Santiago de Cuba. You might remember that we published a research report on our findings.
Today we publish a short documentary (“ParkNet”) on our study of internet censorship in Cuba.
“ParkNet” is a term that we coined to refer to parks that serve as public WiFi hotspots in Cuba.</description></item><item><title>Sierra Leone: Network disruptions amid 2018 runoff elections</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/sierra-leone-network-disruptions-2018-elections/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/sierra-leone-network-disruptions-2018-elections/</guid><description>Last weekend, two network disruptions occurred in Sierra Leone right before and after the country’s runoff elections.
This post examines these disruptions and shares data that corroborates local reports.
It seems that the network disruptions were caused by an ACE submarine cable cut. Google traffic and BGP data suggest that the second disruption, following the runoff elections, could be an internet blackout.
2018 general elections President Koroma is stepping down, having served ten years in office.</description></item><item><title>Iran Protests: OONI data confirms censorship events (Part 1)</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2018-iran-protests/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2018-iran-protests/</guid><description>At this point, you have probably read all about the major anti-government protests that erupted across Iran over the last week. You may have even read about how services like Telegram and Instagram were blocked, reportedly as part of a government attempt to stifle the unrest.
We publish this post to share OONI network measurement data collected from Iran between 28th December 2017 (when the protests started) to 2nd January 2018.</description></item><item><title>How Pakistan blocked news outlets, social media sites, and IM apps amidst protests</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/how-pakistan-blocked-social-media/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/how-pakistan-blocked-social-media/</guid><description>Last weekend, a number of social media sites and news outlets were blocked in Pakistan during Islamist protests. Protesters gathered in Islamabad alleged that Mr. Zahid Hamid, the Federal Law Minister, should be removed from his position because he omitted a reference to the Prophet Muhammad in a parliamentary bill. On Saturday, 25th November 2017, law enforcement agencies initiated an operation to disperse the sit-in at the Faizabad Interchange linking Islamabad and Rawalpindi.</description></item><item><title>Internet Censorship in Pakistan: Findings from 2014-2017</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/pakistan-internet-censorship/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/pakistan-internet-censorship/</guid><description>Islamabad: Political dissent in Pakistan under threat, government censors online content - PC: Haroon Baloch
A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) and Bytes for All Pakistan.
Table of contents
Key Findings
Introduction
Background
Network landscape and internet penetration
Legal environment
Freedom of expression
Press freedom
Access to information
Privacy and digital surveillance</description></item><item><title>Evidence of Internet Censorship during Catalonia's Independence Referendum</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/internet-censorship-catalonia-independence-referendum/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/internet-censorship-catalonia-independence-referendum/</guid><description>Image: Catalan Independence Referendum site seized
Two days ago, Catalonia held a referendum seeking independence from Spain. As the world awaits to see what happens next, we publish this post to share evidence of recent censorship events that occurred during and leading up to the referendum.
We confirm the blocking of at least 25 sites related to the Catalan referendum by means of DNS tampering and HTTP blocking, based on OONI Probe network measurements collected from three local networks.</description></item><item><title>Internet Censorship in Iran: Network Measurement Findings from 2014-2017</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/iran-internet-censorship/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/iran-internet-censorship/</guid><description>Image: Blockpage in Iran
A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI), ASL19, ARTICLE 19, and Small Media.
Table of contents
Key Findings
Introduction
Background
Network landscape
Internet use
Legal environment
Reported cases of internet censorship
Methodology: Measuring internet censorship in Iran
Review of the Citizen Lab&amp;rsquo;s test list for Iran</description></item><item><title>Measuring Internet Censorship in Cuba's ParkNets</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/cuba-internet-censorship-2017/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/cuba-internet-censorship-2017/</guid><description>Image by Arturo Filastò (CC-BY-SA-3.0) A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI)
View the pdf version of the report here.
Table of contents
Key Findings
Introduction
Background
Network landscape and internet penetration
ETECSA
ParkNets
Joven Club
StreetNets
El Paquete
Summary
Measuring Internet Censorship in Cuba</description></item><item><title>#EgyptCensors: Evidence of recent censorship events in Egypt</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/egypt-censors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/egypt-censors/</guid><description>Country: Egypt
OONI tests: Web Connectivity, HTTP Header Field Manipulation, HTTP Invalid Request Line, HTTP Host, Vanilla Tor.
Probed ISPs: Link Egypt (AS24863), Vodafone Egypt (AS36935), Telecom Egypt (AS8452).
Analysis period: 23rd May 2017 to 17th June 2017.
Censorship method: Deep Packet Inspection (DPI) used to RESET connections.
Starting on May 24th, the Egyptian government ordered ISPs to block at least 21 news websites on the grounds of “supporting terrorism and spreading lies”.</description></item><item><title>The State of Internet Censorship in Indonesia</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/indonesia-internet-censorship/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/indonesia-internet-censorship/</guid><description>Image: Block page in Indonesia
A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) and Sinar Project.
Table of contents
Key Findings
Introduction
Background
Network landscape and internet penetration
Legal environment
Freedom of expression
Press freedom
Access to information
Privacy
Censorship and surveillance
Reported cases of internet censorship and surveillance</description></item><item><title>The State of Internet Censorship in Myanmar</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/myanmar-report/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 13:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/myanmar-report/</guid><description>A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI), Sinar Project, and the Myanmar ICT for Development Organization (MIDO).
Table of contents
Key Findings
Introduction
Background
Network landscape and internet penetration
Legal environment
Freedom of expression
Press freedom
Access to information
Privacy
Censorship and surveillance
Reported cases of internet censorship and surveillance</description></item><item><title>The State of Internet Censorship in Thailand</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/thailand-internet-censorship/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/thailand-internet-censorship/</guid><description>Image: Block page in Thailand
A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI), Sinar Project, and the Thai Netizen Network.
Table of contents
Key Findings
Introduction
Background
Network landscape and internet penetration
Legal environment
Freedom of expression
Press freedom
Access to information
Privacy
Censorship and surveillance
Reported cases of internet censorship and surveillance</description></item><item><title>New OONI Probe Mobile App: Measure Internet Censorship &amp; Performance</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-mobile-app/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-mobile-app/</guid><description>Today the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) project is thrilled to announce the release of a new mobile app (“OONI Probe - Measure Internet Censorship &amp;amp; Performance”) that can now be installed on Android and iOS for testing Internet censorship and network performance.
By running the tests included in OONI’s mobile app, you can monitor:
Blocking of websites; Presence of systems that could be responsible for censorship or surveillance; Speed and performance of your network.</description></item><item><title>Kenya: Censorship-free internet?</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/kenya-study/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/kenya-study/</guid><description>Over the last five months we ran OONI tests in Kenya almost every day to examine whether internet censorship events were occurring in the country. Hundreds of thousands of network measurements were collected and analyzed. 1,357 URLs were tested for censorship, including both international websites and sites that are more relevant to Kenya (e.g. local news outlets). Yet, after five months of intensive testing from four local vantage points in Kenya, we found almost no signs of internet censorship in the country.</description></item><item><title>The State of Internet Censorship in Malaysia</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/malaysia-report/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/malaysia-report/</guid><description>Block page in Malaysia
A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) and Sinar Project.
Table of contents
Key Findings
Introduction
Background
Network landscape and internet penetration
Legal environment
Freedom of expression
Press freedom
Access to information
Privacy
Censorship and surveillance
Previous cases of internet censorship and surveillance</description></item><item><title>New OONI tests examine the blocking of WhatsApp and Facebook Messenger</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/whatsapp-and-facebook-tests/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/whatsapp-and-facebook-tests/</guid><description>Today the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) project is excited to announce the release of two new software tests which are designed to examine the blocking of WhatsApp and Facebook Messenger. You can now run these tests to monitor the accessibility of these apps across time, and to collect data that can serve as evidence when/if they are blocked.
WhatsApp test Many of our users have asked us to develop a test to examine the accessibility of WhatsApp, especially in light of it being blocked by various governments around the world during elections, protests, and other political events.</description></item><item><title>Ethiopia: Evidence of social media blocking and internet censorship</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-report/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-report/</guid><description>Youth in Addis trying to get Wi-Fi Connection. Credit Addis Fortune Newspaper
Recently we published a post about what appeared to be a possible internet shutdown in Ethiopia during a wave of ongoing protests by ethnic groups. Today, in collaboration with Amnesty International we are releasing a report that includes evidence of recent censorship events during Ethiopia’s political upheaval.
See the Amharic translation of the report. Translated by Wolete Mariam.</description></item></channel></rss>