<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nettest on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.org/nettest/</link><description>Recent content in Nettest on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.org/nettest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DASH Streaming Test</title><link>https://ooni.org/nettest/dash/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/nettest/dash/</guid><description>DASH Streaming Test DASH is designed to measure the quality of tested networks by emulating a video streaming. This test is called DASH because it uses the DASH (Dynamic Adaptive Streaming over HTTP) streaming technique.
Running this test can be useful to understand the baseline streaming performance of a specific network connection. It measures video-related metrics as well as network metrics that are key to understand the reason of performance issues.</description></item><item><title>DNS consistency</title><link>https://ooni.org/nettest/dns-consistency/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/nettest/dns-consistency/</guid><description>This test compares the DNS query results from a DNS resolver which is considered to be reliable with one that is tested for tampering.
The domain name system (DNS) is what is responsible for transforming a host name (e.g. torproject.org) into an IP address (e.g. 38.229.72.16). ISPs, amongst others, run DNS resolvers which map IP addresses to host names. In certain circumstances though, ISPs map the wrong IP addresses to the wrong host names.</description></item><item><title>Facebook Messenger test</title><link>https://ooni.org/nettest/facebook-messenger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/nettest/facebook-messenger/</guid><description>This test is designed to examine the reachability of Facebook Messenger within a tested network.
OONI&amp;rsquo;s Facebook Messenger test attempts to perform a TCP connection and DNS lookup to Facebook&amp;rsquo;s endpoints over the vantage point of the user.
Based on this methodology, Facebook Messenger is likely blocked if one or both of the following apply:
TCP connections to Facebook&amp;rsquo;s endpoints fail
DNS lookups to domains associated to Facebook do not resolve to IP addresses allocated to Facebook</description></item><item><title>HTTP Header Field Manipulation</title><link>https://ooni.org/nettest/http-header-field-manipulation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/nettest/http-header-field-manipulation/</guid><description>This test tries to detect the presence of network components (“middle box”) which could be responsible for censorship and/or traffic manipulation.
HTTP is a protocol which transfers or exchanges data across the internet. It does so by handling a client&amp;rsquo;s request to connect to a server, and a server&amp;rsquo;s response to a client&amp;rsquo;s request. Every time you connect to a server, you (the client) send a request through the HTTP protocol to that server.</description></item><item><title>HTTP Host</title><link>https://ooni.org/nettest/http-host/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/nettest/http-host/</guid><description>This test attempts to:
examine whether the domain names of websites are blocked
detect the presence of “middle boxes” (software which could be used for censorship and/or traffic manipulation) in tested networks
assess which censorship circumvention techniques are capable of bypassing the censorship implemented by the “middle box”
HTTP is a protocol which transfers or exchanges data across the internet. It does so by handling a client&amp;rsquo;s request to connect to a server, and a server&amp;rsquo;s response to a client&amp;rsquo;s request.</description></item><item><title>HTTP Invalid Request Line</title><link>https://ooni.org/nettest/http-invalid-request-line/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/nettest/http-invalid-request-line/</guid><description>This test tries to detect the presence of network components (“middle box”) which could be responsible for censorship and/or traffic manipulation.
Instead of sending a normal HTTP request, this test sends an invalid HTTP request line - containing an invalid HTTP version number, an invalid field count and a huge request method – to an echo service listening on the standard HTTP port. An echo service is a very useful debugging and measurement tool, which simply sends back to the originating source any data it receives.</description></item><item><title>HTTP Requests</title><link>https://ooni.org/nettest/http-requests/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/nettest/http-requests/</guid><description>This test tries to detect online censorship based on a comparison of HTTP requests over Tor and over the network of the user.
HTTP is a protocol which allows communication between a client and a server. It does so by handling a client&amp;rsquo;s request to connect to a server, and a server&amp;rsquo;s response to a client&amp;rsquo;s request. Every time you connect to a website, your browser (the client) sends a request through the HTTP protocol to the server which is hosting that website.</description></item><item><title>Lantern</title><link>https://ooni.org/nettest/lantern/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/nettest/lantern/</guid><description>This test provides an automated way of examining whether Lantern works in a tested network.
Lantern is a centralized and peer-to-peer proxy, which is used as a circumvention tool. It detects whether websites are blocked and, if so, it allows you to access them via Lantern servers or via the network of Lantern users.
This test runs Lantern and checks to see if it is working. If it&amp;rsquo;s able to connect to a Lantern server and reach a control website over it, then we consider that Lantern can be used for censorship circumvention within the tested network.</description></item><item><title>Meek Fronted Requests</title><link>https://ooni.org/nettest/meek-fronted-requests/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/nettest/meek-fronted-requests/</guid><description>This test examines whether the domains used by Meek (a type of Tor bridge) work in tested networks.
Meek is a pluggable transport which uses non-blocked domains, such as google.com, awsstatic.com (Amazon cloud infrastructure) and ajax.aspnetcdn.com (Microsoft azure cloud infrastructure), to proxy its users over Tor to blocked websites, while hiding both the fact that they are connecting to such websites and how they are connecting to them. As such, Meek is useful for not only connecting to websites that are blocked, but for also hiding which websites you are connecting to.</description></item><item><title>NDT Speed Test</title><link>https://ooni.org/nettest/ndt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/nettest/ndt/</guid><description>NDT (Network Diagnostic Test) is designed to measure the speed and performance of tested networks.
This network performance test was originally developed by The Internet2 Project and is currently maintained by Measurement Lab (M-Lab). NDT is designed to measure the speed and performance of networks by connecting to M-Lab servers close to the user, and by subsequently uploading and downloading random data. In doing so, NDT collects TCP/IP low level information that is useful to examining and characterizing the quality of the network path between the user and the mLab server.</description></item><item><title>Psiphon</title><link>https://ooni.org/nettest/psiphon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/nettest/psiphon/</guid><description>About Psiphon Psiphon is a free and open source tool that utilizes VPN, SSH, and HTTP proxy technology for censorship circumvention. The Psiphon VPN essentially serves as a tunnel that enables you to circumvent censorship because you access resources on the internet through the non-censored tunnel that Psiphon provides.
In an attempt to limit censorship circumvention, some governments have blocked access to Psiphon. OONI has therefore developed an OONI Probe test that anyone can run to measure the reachability of the Psiphon app.</description></item><item><title>RiseupVPN</title><link>https://ooni.org/nettest/riseupvpn/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/nettest/riseupvpn/</guid><description>About RiseupVPN RiseupVPN is a non-commercial, donation-based VPN service. It offers simple-to-use clients to secure your internet traffic against surveillance and to circumvent internet censorship. RiseupVPN doesn&amp;rsquo;t log any user data and doesn&amp;rsquo;t require registration. The software is based on LEAP VPN, an open source VPN solution, and is run by the Riseup collective which has been offering privacy-preserving online services for activists for more than 20 years.
RiseupVPN test The RiseupVPN test, contributed by the LEAP collective, provides an automated way of examining whether RiseupVPN works in a tested network.</description></item><item><title>Signal test</title><link>https://ooni.org/nettest/signal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/nettest/signal/</guid><description>About Signal Signal is a free and open source messaging app for encrypted voice calls and instant messages.
Signal provides security by encrypting communications in transit (end-to-end encryption) and by ensuring that past communications are secure even if encryption keys are stolen (forward secrecy). Several applications, such as WhatsApp, use the Signal protocol for encryption.
Signal test The OONI Probe Signal test is designed to measure the reachability of the Signal messaging app within a tested network.</description></item><item><title>Telegram test</title><link>https://ooni.org/nettest/telegram/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/nettest/telegram/</guid><description>This test is designed to examine the reachability of Telegram&amp;rsquo;s app and web version within a tested network.
More specifically, this test attempts to perform an HTTP POST request, and establish a TCP connection to Telegram’s access points (DCs), as well as an HTTP GET request to Telegram&amp;rsquo;s web version (web.telegram.org) over the vantage point of the user. The test is triggered as blocking when connections to all access points defined in the [test] (https://github.</description></item><item><title>Tor</title><link>https://ooni.org/nettest/tor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/nettest/tor/</guid><description>About Tor The Tor network, which is free and open source, provides its users with online anonymity, privacy, and censorship circumvention. Tor software is designed to bounce communications around a distributed network of relays run by volunteers around the world, thereby hiding its users’ IP addresses and enabling them to circumvent online tracking and internet censorship.
In an attempt to limit online anonymity and circumvention, some governments have blocked access to Tor.</description></item><item><title>Tor Bridge Reachability</title><link>https://ooni.org/nettest/tor-bridge-reachability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/nettest/tor-bridge-reachability/</guid><description>This test examines whether Tor bridges work in tested networks.
Tor is free and open source software which enables online anonymity and censorship circumvention. It was designed to bounce communications around a distributed network of relays run by volunteers around the world, thus hiding users' IP address and circumventing online tracking and censorship. However, Internet Service Providers (ISPs) in various countries around the world are often ordered by their governments to block users' access to Tor.</description></item><item><title>Vanilla Tor</title><link>https://ooni.org/nettest/vanilla-tor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/nettest/vanilla-tor/</guid><description>This test measures the reachability of the Tor network (which is designed for online anonymity and censorship circumvention).
The Vanilla Tor test attempts to start a connection to the Tor network. If the test successfully bootstraps a connection within a predefined amount of seconds (300 by default), then Tor is considered to be reachable from the vantage point of the user. But if the test does not manage to establish a connection, then the Tor network is likely blocked within the tested network.</description></item><item><title>WhatsApp test</title><link>https://ooni.org/nettest/whatsapp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/nettest/whatsapp/</guid><description>This test is designed to examine the reachability of both WhatsApp&amp;rsquo;s app and the WhatsApp web version within a tested network.
OONI&amp;rsquo;s WhatsApp test attempts to perform an HTTP GET request, TCP connection and DNS lookup to WhatsApp’s endpoints, registration service and web version over the vantage point of the user. Based on this methodology, WhatsApp’s app is likely blocked if any of the following apply:
TCP connections to WhatsApp&amp;rsquo;s endpoints fail;</description></item><item><title>Web Connectivity</title><link>https://ooni.org/nettest/web-connectivity/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 0000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/nettest/web-connectivity/</guid><description>This test examines whether websites (included in the Citizen Lab test lists) are reachable and if they are not, it attempts to determine whether access to them is blocked by means of DNS tampering, TCP/IP blocking or by a transparent HTTP proxy.
Specifically, this test is designed to perform the following:
Resolver identification
DNS lookup
TCP connect
HTTP GET request
By default, this test performs the above (excluding the first step, which is performed only over the network of the user) both over a control server and over the network of the user.</description></item></channel></rss>