<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>country-cn on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/country-cn/</link><description>Recent content in country-cn on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/country-cn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Measuring HTTP/3 censorship with OONI Probe</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-http3-measurements-paper/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-http3-measurements-paper/</guid><description>Last year, QUIC emerged as a new internet protocol for creating reliable connections and encrypting communications between clients over the new HTTP/3 protocol. Observing the emergence and growing deployment of HTTP/3, we want to enable OONI Probe to measure HTTP/3 censorship and monitor how censors respond and adapt to technical innovation.
We therefore added HTTP/3 support (in early 2021) into OONI Probe (through our urlgetter research tool) to conduct measurements in China, Iran, India and Kazakhstan to investigate the state of HTTP/3 censorship in these countries.</description></item><item><title>How countries attempt to block Signal Private Messenger App around the world</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-how-signal-private-messenger-blocked-around-the-world/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-how-signal-private-messenger-blocked-around-the-world/</guid><description>Signal Private Messenger, commonly used by human rights defenders worldwide, is widely considered the state-of-the-art app for private and secure communications. But as its popularity surged recently, we have started to observe its blocking in several countries.
In this report, we share our analysis of OONI network measurement data on the blocking of the Signal Private Messenger app in Iran, China, Cuba, and Uzbekistan.
Currently, circumvention is enabled by default for Signal users in Iran, Egypt, Oman, Qatar, and the UAE.</description></item><item><title>China is now blocking all language editions of Wikipedia</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-china-wikipedia-blocking/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-china-wikipedia-blocking/</guid><description>translation: 中国封锁了所有语言版本的维基百科
China recently started blocking all language editions of Wikipedia. Previously, the blocking was limited to the Chinese language edition of Wikipedia (zh.wikipedia.org), but has now expanded to include all *.wikipedia.org language editions.
In this post, we share OONI network measurement data on the blocking of Wikipedia in China. We found that all wikipedia.org sub-domains are blocked in China by means of DNS injection and SNI filtering.
DNS injection Through the use of OONI Probe, Wikipedia domains have been tested from multiple local vantage points in China since 2015.</description></item></channel></rss>