<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Support on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/support/</link><description>Recent content in Support on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/support/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ)</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/support/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/support/faq/</guid><description>This Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ) section aims to address the questions that we are frequently asked by the community.
Are there other questions you would like us to address? Please let us know.
View a version of the OONI FAQ in Khmer by DigitalHub101.
About OONI
What is OONI?
Why OONI?
What does OONI do?
Why measure internet censorship?
How is OONI funded?</description></item><item><title>OONI Glossary</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/support/glossary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/support/glossary/</guid><description>This glossary contains brief explanations for terms used in OONI apps, methodologies, and research reports.
If you would like to see additional terms in this glossary, please open a pull request or send us an email.
API
AS
ASN
BGP
Blocklist
Block page
Caching
Circumvention tools
Client
Data processing pipeline</description></item><item><title>User Guide: OONI Probe Command Line Interface (CLI)</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/support/ooni-probe-cli/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/support/ooni-probe-cli/</guid><description>Last updated: 24th September 2021
OONI Probe CLI version: 3.9.2
OONI Probe is free and open source software that you can run to measure internet censorship and other forms of network interference.
This user guide provides step-by-step instructions on how to install and use the OONI Probe Command Line Interface (CLI).
You can run OONI Probe CLI on macOS, Debian/Ubuntu Linux, and on Raspberry Pis.
What you will get from this guide:</description></item><item><title>User Guide: OONI Probe Desktop App</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/support/ooni-probe-desktop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/support/ooni-probe-desktop/</guid><description>Last updated: 6th September 2022
OONI Probe Desktop version: 3.7.0
OONI Probe is a free and open source app that you can use to measure internet censorship and other forms of network interference. This user guide provides step-by-step instructions on how to install, run, and customize your use of the OONI Probe desktop app.
What you will get from this guide:
Learn how to run OONI Probe Desktop to:</description></item><item><title>User Guide: OONI Probe Mobile App</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/support/ooni-probe-mobile/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/support/ooni-probe-mobile/</guid><description>Last updated: 6th September 2022
OONI Probe Mobile version: 3.7.1
OONI Probe is a free and open source app that you can use to measure internet censorship and other forms of network interference. This user guide provides step-by-step instructions on how to install, run, and customize your use of the OONI Probe mobile app.
What you will get from this guide:
Learn how to run OONI Probe Mobile to: Test the blocking of websites Test the blocking of instant messaging apps Test the blocking of circumvention tools Measure your network speed and performance Customize your OONI Probe testing to websites of your choice Learn how to access and share your OONI Probe test results Configure your OONI Probe app settings Upon reading this guide, we hope you will feel empowered to share your OONI Probe knowledge and skills with others!</description></item><item><title>User Guide: OONI Test Lists Editor</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/support/test-lists-editor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/support/test-lists-editor/</guid><description>Last updated: 7th September 2022
The OONI Test Lists Editor enables the public to review and contribute to the lists of websites (“test lists”) that are tested for censorship by OONI Probe users around the world.
This user guide provides step-by-step instructions on how to use the Test Lists Editor to review and contribute websites for censorship testing.
Upon reading this guide, we hope you will feel empowered to contribute to test lists!</description></item></channel></rss>