<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Msg on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>/msg/</link><description>Recent content in Msg on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="/msg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>/msg/2017-08-23-angola-elections/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/msg/2017-08-23-angola-elections/</guid><description>Angolan Legislative Election 2017 Election day is an important day, but so are the days following an election.
You can actively examine whether and to what extent online information is accessible in Angola. By running OONI Probe, you can examine:
Whether websites are blocked; Whether systems that could be responsible for censorship or surveillance are present in your network; Net neutrality violations. Increasing transparency of information controls during political events is important!</description></item><item><title/><link>/msg/2017-09-06-togo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/msg/2017-09-06-togo/</guid><description>Facebook and WhatsApp blocked in Togo? Today, 6th September 2017, we heard that Facebook and WhatsApp are inaccessible in Togo.
Run OONI Probe to collect data showing whether and how they (and other sites) are blocked!</description></item><item><title/><link>/msg/2018-01-belarus-test-blocking-of-charter97-org/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/msg/2018-01-belarus-test-blocking-of-charter97-org/</guid><description>Belarus: Test blocking of charter97.org Reporters Without Borders reported the blocking of news outlet charter97.org in Belarus: https://rsf.org/en/news/blocking-leading-belarusian-news-website-seen-test-eu
You can test this site with OONI Probe to examine whether and how it is being blocked. In addition to network measurement data, you will also receive relevant circumvention advice.
Simply click on this link (&amp;amp; open it with your OONI Probe mobile app) to test charter97.org with OONI Probe.
To view the results:</description></item><item><title/><link>/msg/2018-07-19-ux-survey/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/msg/2018-07-19-ux-survey/</guid><description>Help us improve OONI Probe Thanks for using OONI Probe! We&amp;rsquo;re excited to hear more about your experience with OONI Probe so that we can improve it.
Please take a few minutes to complete our survey: https://ooniuxteam.typeform.com/to/a1P0cn
Alternatively, you can fill out the survey using Tor&amp;rsquo;s self-hosted version of it: https://storm.torproject.org/shared/VpAFK13fdAozTGTolFd2EsT1CkLY8-YlBLbRERy5EwI
Thank you!</description></item><item><title/><link>/msg/2020-01-16-wikipedia-turkey/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/msg/2020-01-16-wikipedia-turkey/</guid><description>Document the unblocking of Wikipedia Wikipedia is reportedly unblocked in Turkey, after having been blocked for more than 2 years.
Document this important development by testing Wikipedia domains with OONI Probe:
1 - Open your browser and type https://ooni.org/get-involved/run 2 - Tap on the Wikipedia button and open with the OONI Probe app 3 - Tap Run The results will automatically get published here: https://explorer.ooni.org/search?until=2020-01-17&amp;amp;domain=www.wikipedia.org&amp;amp;probe_cc=TR</description></item></channel></rss>