<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Network Measurement on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/network-measurement/</link><description>Recent content in Network Measurement on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/network-measurement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Join us at the OMG Village at the Global Gathering 2025!</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2025-gg-omg-village/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2025-gg-omg-village/</guid><description>&lt;div>
 &lt;a href="https://ooni.github.io/post/2025-gg-omg-village/images/omg-banner.png">
 &lt;img
 src="https://ooni.github.io/post/2025-gg-omg-village/images/omg-banner_hu15940790895691255656.png"

 
 srcset="https://ooni.github.io/post/2025-gg-omg-village/images/omg-banner_hu2984693150132907711.png 2x"
 
 
 title="OMG Village announcement"
 
 alt="OMG Village announcement"
 
 />
 &lt;/a>
 
&lt;/div>


&lt;p>Are you attending the upcoming &lt;a href="https://wiki.digitalrights.community/index.php?title=Global_Gathering_2025">Global Gathering&lt;/a> event in Estoril, Portugal? Are you interested in investigating internet shutdowns and censorship, and curious to learn more about the tools and open datasets that support this work?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Join us at the Global Gathering &lt;strong>Open Measurement Gathering (OMG) Village&lt;/strong>: a community space organized and hosted by 4 internet measurement projects: &lt;a href="https://ooni.org/">Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI)&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.measurementlab.net/">Measurement Lab (M-Lab)&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://ioda.inetintel.cc.gatech.edu/">Internet Outage Detection &amp;amp; Analysis (IODA)&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://censoredplanet.org/">Censored Planet&lt;/a>. We also have the pleasure of being joined by our friends &lt;a href="https://netalitica.com/">Netalitica&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://ainita.net/">Project Ainita&lt;/a>, who will each host a booth on Day 3.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OMG! Summary of the 3rd Open Measurement Gathering (OMG) Ask Me Anything (AMA) event</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2025-omg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2025-omg/</guid><description>&lt;p>On June 25, 2025, the Open Measurement Gathering (OMG) held a public event, “Open Measurement Gathering AMA”, featuring &lt;a href="https://censoredplanet.org/">Censored Planet&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://ioda.live">IODA&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://ooni.org/">OONI&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://www.measurementlab.net/">Measurement Lab&lt;/a>. This was a chance for the OMG group to share project updates, future plans, and gather questions and feedback from the Internet freedom community. Each measurement group presented for 30 minutes followed by Q&amp;amp;A.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This public virtual event was inspired by the past two OMG convenings (public &lt;a href="https://www.measurementlab.net/blog/open-measurement-gathering-1-public-report/">reports 1&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.measurementlab.net/blog/open-measurement-gathering-2/">2&lt;/a>) at which OMG groups have shared exciting updates to their platforms, tools, and/or datasets before sharing with the broader Internet freedom community. For the third OMG convening, the groups decided to share previewing updates publicly to encourage community feedback.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>