<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>explorer on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>/tags/explorer/</link><description>Recent content in explorer on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/explorer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Launch: New OONI Censorship Findings platform</title><link>/post/2023-launch-ooni-censorship-findings-platform/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2023-launch-ooni-censorship-findings-platform/</guid><description>Image: OONI Censorship Findings platform.
Today we are thrilled to announce the launch of the OONI Censorship Findings platform!
Internet censorship is frequently being reported around the world, but how can we verify such events with empirical evidence?
Our new platform provides short reports on internet censorship around the world based on OONI&amp;rsquo;s open data. With the launch of the platform, we are publishing 20 reports on internet censorship that emerged in 2023.</description></item><item><title>New OONI Explorer features for investigating internet censorship through open data</title><link>/post/2023-new-explorer-features/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2023-new-explorer-features/</guid><description>We’re excited to share that OONI Explorer includes new features for investigating internet censorship worldwide based on open data.
Specifically, these features include:
New domain-centric pages; New network-centric pages; New “internet outage” charts (integrating IODA, Google traffic, and Cloudflare Radar data), available in each country-specific and network-specific page; New user feedback reporting mechanism, available through the “Verify” button in the banner of each OONI measurement page. In this blog post, we share information about these new features.</description></item></channel></rss>