<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>country-id on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/country-id/</link><description>Recent content in country-id on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/country-id/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>iMAP 2022: New Research Reports on Internet Censorship in 8 Asian countries</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-imap-8-research-reports-southeast-asia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-imap-8-research-reports-southeast-asia/</guid><description>On 21st December 2022, our long-term partner, Sinar Project, published 8 new research reports on internet censorship in Southeast Asia and Hong Kong (China) in collaboration with their Internet Monitoring and Action Project (iMAP) partners. We are particularly excited about these reports as they make use of OONI data!
Internet Monitoring Action Project (iMAP) aims to establish regional and in-country networks that monitor network interference and restrictions to the freedom of expression online in 8 countries: Myanmar, Cambodia, Hong Kong (China), Indonesia, Malaysia, Philippines, Thailand, and Vietnam.</description></item><item><title>iMAP State of Internet Censorship Report 2022 - Indonesia</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-indonesia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-indonesia/</guid><description>In July 2014, Regulation of the Minister of Communications and Informatics Number 19 of 2014 on the Handling of Negative Internet Sites came into force as part of the regulator&amp;rsquo;s programme for Healthy and Safe Internet (INSAN or Internet Sehat dan Aman). The law mandated ISPs to block any internet content that is deemed to carry &amp;ldquo;negative&amp;rdquo; elements such as pornography, hoaxes, or SARA conflicts.
As of September 2022, the Indonesian Ministry of Information and Communication (Kominfo) has blocked over 1,000,000 websites through TrustPositif,1 a filtering application that has been operational since 2010 per Ministerial Regulation No 19 of 2014.</description></item><item><title>No Access: LGBTIQ Website Censorship in Six Countries</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-no-access-lgbtiq-website-censorship-six-countries/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-no-access-lgbtiq-website-censorship-six-countries/</guid><description>Today, in collaboration with OutRight Action International and the Citizen Lab, we are excited to share our new research report, “No Access: LGBTIQ Website Censorship in Six Countries”, which examines the blocking of LGBTIQ websites in Indonesia, Malaysia, Iran, Russia, Saudi Arabia, and the United Arab Emirates (UAE).
READ FULL REPORT
Annotated Bibliography
Below we share some of our key research findings.
Summary of findings We joined forces with OutRight Action International and the Citizen Lab to examine the blocking of LGBTIQ websites in six countries: Indonesia, Malaysia, Iran, Russia, Saudi Arabia, and the United Arab Emirates (UAE).</description></item><item><title>The State of Internet Censorship in Indonesia</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/indonesia-internet-censorship/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/indonesia-internet-censorship/</guid><description>Image: Block page in Indonesia
A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) and Sinar Project.
Table of contents
Key Findings
Introduction
Background
Network landscape and internet penetration
Legal environment
Freedom of expression
Press freedom
Access to information
Privacy
Censorship and surveillance
Reported cases of internet censorship and surveillance
Examining internet censorship in Indonesia
Methodology
Collection of OONI Probe network measurements
Web Connectivity
HTTP Invalid Request Line</description></item></channel></rss>