<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>statement on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/statement/</link><description>Recent content in statement on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/statement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Support the OTF: Support a Free and Open Internet</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-support-otf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-support-otf/</guid><description>Over the last month, the Open Technology Fund (OTF) &amp;ndash; one of the main funders of free censorship circumvention and privacy-enhancing technologies that human rights defenders worldwide rely on &amp;ndash; has been under threat, following the ousting of its leadership.
We previously published a statement in support of the OTF, explaining why we think the OTF is essential for internet freedom and encouraging the public to sign the letter to congress.</description></item><item><title>Save Internet Freedom: Support the Open Technology Fund</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-06-19-save-internet-freedom-support-the-open-technology-fund/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 16:48:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-06-19-save-internet-freedom-support-the-open-technology-fund/</guid><description>Last Wednesday was dubbed as a “Wednesday night massacre”, following the firing of the directors of four organizations overseen by the US Agency for Global Media (USAGM): Radio Free Asia, Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, Middle East Broadcasting, and the Open Technology Fund (OTF).
Out of these four organizations, we would like to draw your attention to the OTF, not only because they have been a long-term funder of our project but, more importantly, because they have been essential in creating the internet freedom community as we know it.</description></item></channel></rss>