<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>country-by on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>/tags/country-by/</link><description>Recent content in country-by on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/country-by/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Investigating Internet shutdowns through Mozilla telemetry</title><link>/post/2021-investigating-internet-shutdowns-mozilla-telemetry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2021-investigating-internet-shutdowns-mozilla-telemetry/</guid><description>More than 200 million users worldwide use the Firefox web browser (developed by Mozilla) every month.
If access to the Internet is shut down in a country, Mozilla should expect to see a dramatic drop in Firefox usage from that country. Given how widespread the use of Firefox is around the world, could Mozilla telemetry be a valuable resource for the Internet freedom community to investigate Internet shutdowns?
To explore this question, the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) and Internet Outage Detection and Analysis (IODA) teams joined forces to analyze a dataset of potential outage signals gathered through regular Mozilla telemetry, access to which was provided by Mozilla as part of a relevant research project to validate assumptions about the data.</description></item><item><title>Belarus protests: From internet outages to pervasive website censorship</title><link>/post/2020-belarus-internet-outages-website-censorship/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2020-belarus-internet-outages-website-censorship/</guid><description>Image: Block page served in Belarus.
This report was prepared in collaboration with Human Constanta and the Digital Observers Community Belarus.
More than 70 websites have been blocked in Belarus over the last weeks, following a controversial presidential election and amid ongoing anti-government protests. Many of the blocked sites include news media and are related to the elections, while several other sites expressing political criticism were blocked as well. At the time of writing, many of these sites remain blocked in Belarus.</description></item><item><title>urandom.pcap: Belarus (finally) bans Tor</title><link>/post/belarus-fries-onion/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/belarus-fries-onion/</guid><description>Country: Belarus
Probed ISPs: Beltelecom (AS 6697)
Censorship method: TCP injections
We have recently heard of network anomalies in Belarus. Tor has been finally blocked in December 2016, although it had been explicitly declared that Tor should be blocked since February 2015.
An anonymous cypherpunk has helped to gather some evidence regarding Tor being blocked in Belarus. It&amp;rsquo;s neither a complete study nor an in-depth research and it&amp;rsquo;s unclear if any other further evidence will be gathered, so we decided to share current knowledge as-is:</description></item></channel></rss>