<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>events on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/events/</link><description>Recent content in events on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OONI Partner Training 2021</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-partner-training-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-partner-training-2021/</guid><description>Over the last week, we had the pleasure to host two 3-day OONI Partner Training events for our partners in Africa, Latin America, the Middle East, and Asia. As part of these events, our goal was to share OONI-specific knowledge and skills, and to collect feedback to better serve community needs.
In this post, we share information about the training events.
About
Sessions
Session 1: Information Controls Around the World (Day 1)</description></item><item><title>OONI at RightsCon 2018</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-rightscon-2018/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-rightscon-2018/</guid><description>We are excited to participate at RightsCon next week: the world’s leading event on human rights in the digital age. Annually hosted by Access Now, this three-day conference will take place in Toronto between 16th-18th May 2018.
Over the last years, RightsCon has provided us the opportunity to participate in critical discussions in the digital rights field, meet many fascinating people and organizations, and to form new coalitions. We therefore look forward to participating at RightsCon and are eager to meet many new faces!</description></item><item><title>OONI's recent participation at events in Africa, India, and Europe</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-africa-india-europe-conferences/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-africa-india-europe-conferences/</guid><description>Over the last months, the OONI team had the opportunity to host workshops, give presentations, and participate in discussions at the following conferences and events:
Seminar at the University of Cape Town (South Africa)
Internet Policy in Africa: Research Methods for Advocacy workshop (Uganda)
Nullcon 2018 (India)
Internet Freedom Festival (IFF) 2018 (Spain)
Tor Meeting (Italy)
These events provided us a great opportunity to meet many fascinating people from various communities, learn about their work, form new collaborations, and collect feedback for the improvement of our tools and methodologies.</description></item><item><title>OONI at the 34th Chaos Communication Congress (34C3)</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-34c3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-34c3/</guid><description>Next week the OONI team will be attending the 34th Chaos Communication Congress (34C3): Europe’s largest hacker conference on technology, society, and utopia. Are you going? We hope to see you there!
OONI lecture OONI&amp;rsquo;s founder and project lead, Arturo Filastò, will be presenting OONI at 34C3.
Lecture OONI: Lets Fight Internet Censorship Together! Day 29th December 2017 Time 14:30 Room Saal Borg Attend the lecture to learn all about OONI, recent censorship findings from around the world, and how you can join the fight against internet censorship.</description></item><item><title>OONI at LAVITS and Primavera Hacker 2017</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-lavits-phacker-2017/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-lavits-phacker-2017/</guid><description>Earlier this month we had the opportunity to present OONI at two conferences in Chile: LAVITS and Primavera Hacker.
LAVITS LAVITS is a Latin American network of surveillance technology and society studies that organizes international symposiums since 2009. It features publications, talks and workshops related to surveillance and technology, internet censorship, resistance and counter surveillance, identification, biometrics, protection of personal data and privacy. The fifth series of the LAVITS symposium took place in Santiago, Chile from 29th November to 1st December 2017.</description></item><item><title>OONI Team Meeting: Montreal 2017</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-team-meeting-montreal-2017/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-team-meeting-montreal-2017/</guid><description>Last week, right before the Tor meeting, the OONI team gathered in Montreal for a 4-day meeting to reflect, regroup, hack, and plan.
This post shares information from our meeting and future plans with the broader community. All session notes are available on GitHub.
Summary: What OONI is working on
Sessions
Day 1 - 7th October 2017
Day 2 - 8th October 2017</description></item><item><title>OONI Partner Gathering 2017</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-partner-gathering-2017/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-partner-gathering-2017/</guid><description>Two weeks ago we hosted the first OONI Partner Gathering in Toronto, Canada. This report provides an overview of the event, partner needs and challenges, and future goals to address them.
View the pdf version of the report here.
About
Objectives
Sessions
Day 1 - 10th July 2017
Day 2 - 11th July 2017
Inclusiveness
Challenges and needs</description></item><item><title>OONI at the CryptoRave 2017</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-cryptorave-2017/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-cryptorave-2017/</guid><description>CryptoRave is a free, non-commercial and collectively funded 48 hour event featuring talks, workshops and activities related to security, privacy, anonymity, hacking and freedom of expression that attracts more that 2,500 people mainly from South America. The event took place in São Paulo, Brazil on 5th and 6th May 2017.
A number of people attended the OONI presentation and workshop (&amp;ldquo;Listatona&amp;rdquo;) that was co-organized with Coding Rights. During the workshop participants were able to better understand OONI&amp;rsquo;s testing methodology, and how OONI Probe performs network measurements.</description></item><item><title>OONI at the Internet Freedom Festival &amp; RightsCon 2017</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-iff-rightscon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-iff-rightscon/</guid><description>Over the last month the OONI team joined the internet freedom community at the following events:
Vietnam Cyber Dialogue (VCD)
Internet Freedom Festival (IFF)
Iran Cyber Dialogue (ICD)
RightsCon 2017
International Journalism Festival (IJF)
These events provided us with the opportunity to engage with community members, create new friendships, learn about new projects, and to share skills and knowledge.</description></item><item><title>OONI-dev meeting and hackathon 2016</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-dev-and-hackathon-2016/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-dev-and-hackathon-2016/</guid><description>Oonitarians are spread out across the globe, and OONI’s core team is no exception. We recently met in Berlin to hack on OONI’s software, work on our roadmap, and to have all those discussions that are more fruitful to have in person than on IRC. We also held a hackathon to engage new individuals with our project!
Below we document some of the things that we worked on as part of our OONI-dev meeting and hackathon.</description></item><item><title>OONI Hackathon: Join us to explore internet censorship!</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/berlin-hackathon-2016/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/berlin-hackathon-2016/</guid><description>Interested in exploring (and exposing) internet censorship? Join the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) hackathon in Berlin!
When? Friday, 11th November &amp;amp; Saturday, 12th November 2016
Where? The OnionSpace (Gottschedstraße 4, 13357 Berlin, Germany)
What time? 10am onwards
Who? Software developers, data analysts, academics, journalists, bloggers, lawyers, activists, and all those who don’t go by any particular label, but are curious enough to join!</description></item></channel></rss>