<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ux on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>/tags/ux/</link><description>Recent content in ux on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 09:38:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/ux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OONI Run Usability Study: Findings</title><link>/post/2020-06-09-ooni-run-usability-study-findings/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 09:38:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2020-06-09-ooni-run-usability-study-findings/</guid><description>OONI Run is a platform (launched in September 2017) that you can use to generate mobile deep links and widget code to coordinate OONI Probe testing. To enable community members to more effectively use OONI Run, we researched its limitations and collected structured community feedback through an OONI Run usability study.
This report outlines the objectives, personas, assumptions, and methods of this study.
We also share the outcomes based on the analysis of information collected through our survey and interviews with community members, as well as some of the next steps towards improving OONI Run.</description></item><item><title>Do you use OONI Probe? We want your feedback!</title><link>/post/ooniprobe-ux-survey-and-interviews/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/ooniprobe-ux-survey-and-interviews/</guid><description>Survey (self-hosted mirror)
Since last year’s launch of the OONI Probe mobile apps, tens of thousands of people have been measuring internet censorship in around 200 countries every month. But OONI Probe is far from perfect.
We’re excited to hear more about your experience with the apps so that we can improve them.
We invite you to complete our survey and/or participate in an interview to provide feedback.
Survey We’d love to hear your thoughts on the current OONI Probe mobile apps.</description></item></channel></rss>