<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>country-kz on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/country-kz/</link><description>Recent content in country-kz on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/country-kz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kazakhstan: TLS MITM attacks and blocking of news media, human rights, and circumvention tool sites</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2024-kazakhstan-report/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2024-kazakhstan-report/</guid><description>In recent years, internet censorship in Kazakhstan has been reported quite extensively. As part of this study, OONI, Internet Freedom Kazakhstan (IFKZ), and Eurasian Digital Foundation collaborated to investigate internet censorship in Kazakhstan over the past year (between June 2023 to June 2024) through the analysis of empirical network measurement data.
In this report, we share OONI censorship measurement findings and relevant legal context. We found numerous news media, human rights, and circumvention tool websites blocked in Kazakhstan by means of TLS interference.</description></item><item><title>Throttling of news media amid Kazakhstan’s 2022 presidential election</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-throttling-kz-elections/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-throttling-kz-elections/</guid><description>Snap presidential elections were held in Kazakhstan in November 2022, following a wave of unrest that started in January 2022. Following the victory of incumbent president Tokayev, early legislative elections were held in March 2023.
Through the analysis of OONI data, we observe the throttling of Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty (RFE/RL) Kazakhstan&amp;rsquo;s service websites in Kazakh and Russian (www.azattyq.org and rus.azattyq.org) in Kazakhstan, starting from 27th September 2022 and lasting until at least 11th April 2023.</description></item><item><title>Measuring DoT/DoH Blocking Using OONI Probe: A Preliminary Study</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-doh-dot-paper-dnsprivacy21/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-doh-dot-paper-dnsprivacy21/</guid><description>When you enter a URL such as https://example.com/, under the hood, your web browser resolves the example.com domain to one or more IP addresses using the Domain Name System (DNS), a set of federated servers and protocols providing this name-to-IP-address mapping. For example, as of 2022-06-16, example.com resolves to the 93.184.216.34 (IPv4) and 2606:2800:220:1:248:1893:25c8:1946 (IPv6) addresses. Once it knows the IP addresses for the domain, the browser then uses them to fetch the requested webpage.</description></item><item><title>Measuring HTTP/3 censorship with OONI Probe</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-http3-measurements-paper/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-http3-measurements-paper/</guid><description>Last year, QUIC emerged as a new internet protocol for creating reliable connections and encrypting communications between clients over the new HTTP/3 protocol. Observing the emergence and growing deployment of HTTP/3, we want to enable OONI Probe to measure HTTP/3 censorship and monitor how censors respond and adapt to technical innovation.
We therefore added HTTP/3 support (in early 2021) into OONI Probe (through our urlgetter research tool) to conduct measurements in China, Iran, India and Kazakhstan to investigate the state of HTTP/3 censorship in these countries.</description></item></channel></rss>