<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>shutdown on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.org/tags/shutdown/</link><description>Recent content in shutdown on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.org/tags/shutdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Investigating Internet shutdowns through Mozilla telemetry</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/2021-investigating-internet-shutdowns-mozilla-telemetry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/2021-investigating-internet-shutdowns-mozilla-telemetry/</guid><description>More than 200 million users worldwide use the Firefox web browser (developed by Mozilla) every month.
If access to the Internet is shut down in a country, Mozilla should expect to see a dramatic drop in Firefox usage from that country. Given how widespread the use of Firefox is around the world, could Mozilla telemetry be a valuable resource for the Internet freedom community to investigate Internet shutdowns?
To explore this question, the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) and Internet Outage Detection and Analysis (IODA) teams joined forces to analyze a dataset of potential outage signals gathered through regular Mozilla telemetry, access to which was provided by Mozilla as part of a relevant research project to validate assumptions about the data.</description></item><item><title>Examining internet blackouts through public data sources</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/examining-internet-blackouts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 16:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/examining-internet-blackouts/</guid><description>Pulling the plug on the internet is one of the ways that governments around the world attempt to exert control over the flow of information.
While the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) project has developed numerous software tests for examining different forms of internet censorship (such as the blocking of websites, instant messaging apps, and censorship circumvention tools), we currently do not have tests that are designed to examine internet blackouts, when the internet as a whole is rendered inaccessible within a location.</description></item><item><title>The Gambia: Internet Shutdown during 2016 Presidential Election</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/gambia-internet-shutdown/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/gambia-internet-shutdown/</guid><description>Last week we attempted to perform OONI network measurement tests in the Gambia to examine whether websites were blocked during its 2016 presidential election. But merely a few hours after we connected our probe to perform tests, it stopped working completely.
We suspected that this was due to an internet shutdown. To confirm this, we referred to third-party data to examine whether a country-wide internet blackout was taking place.
In this report, we summarize some of our key findings pertaining to the internet shutdown that appears to have occurred in the Gambia on the eve of its 2016 presidential election.</description></item><item><title>Ethiopia: Internet Shutdown Amidst Recent Protests?</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/ethiopia-internet-shutdown-amidst-recent-protests/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/ethiopia-internet-shutdown-amidst-recent-protests/</guid><description>Nearly 100 deaths and thousands of arrests have been reported in Ethiopia over the last days, as part of protests against the marginalization and persecution of the Oromos and Amharas, Ethiopia’s two largest ethnic groups. But the attacks and arrests may not have been the only forms of retribution carried out by the Ethiopian government in its crackdown against protesters.
Last weekend, the internet was reportedly shut down in the country.</description></item></channel></rss>