<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>http3 on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/http3/</link><description>Recent content in http3 on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/http3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Quick Look at QUIC Censorship</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-quick-look-quic-censorship/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-quick-look-quic-censorship/</guid><description>This blog post was originally published by the Open Technology Fund to disseminate Kathrin Elmenhorst&amp;rsquo;s QUIC-and-HTTP/3 censorship research as part of her ICFP fellowship with OONI.
Last year, the new network protocol QUIC was introduced. QUIC is a general-purpose transport layer network with the goal of reducing latency compared to existing protocols. Since the introduction of QUIC, we have seen rising volumes of QUIC-based web traffic in the form of HTTP/3.</description></item><item><title>Measuring HTTP/3 censorship with OONI Probe</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-http3-measurements-paper/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-http3-measurements-paper/</guid><description>Last year, QUIC emerged as a new internet protocol for creating reliable connections and encrypting communications between clients over the new HTTP/3 protocol. Observing the emergence and growing deployment of HTTP/3, we want to enable OONI Probe to measure HTTP/3 censorship and monitor how censors respond and adapt to technical innovation.
We therefore added HTTP/3 support (in early 2021) into OONI Probe (through our urlgetter research tool) to conduct measurements in China, Iran, India and Kazakhstan to investigate the state of HTTP/3 censorship in these countries.</description></item></channel></rss>