<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>country-jo on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>/tags/country-jo/</link><description>Recent content in country-jo on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/country-jo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Grindr blocked in Jordan: Shrinking LGBTQ spaces</title><link>/post/2023-jordan-blocks-grindr/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2023-jordan-blocks-grindr/</guid><description>Jordan recently blocked access to Grindr — the world’s largest social networking app for gay, bi, trans, and queer people — adding to the list of social media apps banned in the country, including TikTok and Clubhouse.
OONI network measurement data collected from Jordan suggests that ISPs started blocking access to Grindr on August 8th 2023, and that the block remains ongoing.
This report shares OONI data on the blocking of Grindr in Jordan.</description></item><item><title>Jordan: Measuring Facebook live-streaming interference during protests</title><link>/post/jordan-measuring-facebook-interference/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/jordan-measuring-facebook-interference/</guid><description>Last December, anti-austerity protests erupted in Jordan against a controversial fiscal reform bill. The protests ensued once a week for several weeks thereafter. Amid the protests, locals reported that they were unable to view live-streaming from Facebook. But they also reported that viewing live-streaming was otherwise possible when protests were not taking place.
Therefore, our first hypothesis was that perhaps people in Jordan couldn’t load videos on Facebook because they were using overloaded networks (rather than Facebook live streaming being interfered with).</description></item></channel></rss>