<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mobile on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.org/tags/mobile/</link><description>Recent content in mobile on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.org/tags/mobile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Job Opening: Mobile Developer for OONI Probe</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/2021-job-opening-ooni-mobile-developer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/2021-job-opening-ooni-mobile-developer/</guid><description>Are you a mobile developer interested in defending human rights on the internet? We have a job opening for you!
The OONI team (a non-profit fighting internet censorship, originally born out of the Tor Project) is looking for a dedicated mobile developer to work on OONI Probe: a free software app designed to measure internet censorship and network performance.
The application deadline is Sunday, 31st October 2021.
Job description If you join our team, you will lead the development of the OONI Probe mobile app, supporting human rights defenders worldwide to investigate and fight internet censorship.</description></item><item><title>Major Revamp: OONI Probe Mobile App 2.0 Launched!</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/revamped-ooni-probe-mobile-app/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/revamped-ooni-probe-mobile-app/</guid><description>Today the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) project is thrilled to announce the release of a major, new OONI Probe mobile app version!
Are websites and social media apps blocked? Is your network unusually slow?
Install OONI Probe now on Android or iOS to find out!
Why run OONI Probe?
OONI Probe 2.0 Highlights
Major UI overhaul
Overview of Test Results</description></item></channel></rss>