<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DPI on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/dpi/</link><description>Recent content in DPI on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/dpi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ethiopia: From internet blackouts to the blocking of WhatsApp and Telegram</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-whatsapp-telegram/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-whatsapp-telegram/</guid><description>&lt;p>Communication access in Ethiopia has significantly been disrupted over the last week. Internet access and Short Message Services (SMS) were &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/save/https://twitter.com/addisstandard/status/1139127606211727360">disconnected&lt;/a> intermittently across the country.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the first half of the week, internet connectivity was &lt;a href="https://ioda.caida.org/ioda/dashboard#view=inspect&amp;entity=country/ET&amp;lastView=overview&amp;from=1560166834&amp;until=now">shut down completely&lt;/a>. After access was restored, both &lt;a href="https://explorer.ooni.io/measurement/20190615T215418Z_AS24757_NKzIEujAd7rEN95SsIZnraLm1yjqdU79EqczVKFLUzsOJh4DLE">WhatsApp&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://explorer.ooni.io/measurement/20190615T222820Z_AS24757_4flsDD8gZDpmh2jr60nmgLuGGymkNsRA8HOejGDOFZZDEWr6EP">Telegram&lt;/a> were blocked. A few days ago, Ethio Telecom (the only telecom in the country) &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20190619122350/https:/twitter.com/ethiotelecom_/status/1141013304762146817">published a notice&lt;/a>, acknowledging the internet disruptions, but came short on details about the extent of communication disruptions or why they occurred in the first place.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Iran Protests: DPI blocking of Instagram (Part 2)</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2018-iran-protests-pt2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2018-iran-protests-pt2/</guid><description>&lt;p>In early January 2018, OONI published a &lt;a href="https://ooni.github.io/post/2018-iran-protests/">post&lt;/a>
reporting on the blocking of Telegram and Instagram amidst protests in Iran. We
have since been analyzing RIPE data and other network measurements collected
from Iran in an attempt to better understand the blockages. Upon further
analysis, we found that Instagram was in fact blocked (during the Iran
protests) through the use of Deep Packet Inspection (DPI) technology which
targeted the TLS protocol. And it was configured in an interesting way.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ethiopia: Evidence of social media blocking and internet censorship</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-report/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-report/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img alt="Ethiopia image" src="https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-report/et-05.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Youth in Addis trying to get Wi-Fi Connection. Credit Addis Fortune Newspaper&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently we published a &lt;a href="https://ooni.org/post/ethiopia-internet-shutdown-amidst-recent-protests/">post&lt;/a> about what appeared to be a possible internet
shutdown in Ethiopia during a wave of ongoing protests by ethnic groups. Today,
in collaboration with &lt;a href="https://www.amnesty.org/">Amnesty International&lt;/a> we are releasing a report that
includes evidence of recent censorship events during Ethiopia’s political
upheaval.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See the &lt;a href="https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-report/amharic-translation.pdf">Amharic translation&lt;/a> of the report. Translated by Wolete Mariam.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>View the &lt;strong>pdf&lt;/strong> version of the report &lt;a href="https://ooni.github.io/documents/Ethiopia-Offline-evidence-of.pdf">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Egypt: Media censorship, Tor interference, HTTPS throttling and ads injections?</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/egypt-network-interference/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/egypt-network-interference/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Country:&lt;/strong> Egypt&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Probed ISPs:&lt;/strong> Noor (AS 20928), TE Data (AS 8452), Vodafone (AS 24835)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Censorship method:&lt;/strong> DPI, network throttling, TCP injections&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>OONI tests:&lt;/strong> HTTP Requests, Web Connectivity, Vanilla Tor&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Measurement period:&lt;/strong> 2016-08-27 - 2016-10-26&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We recently noticed network anomalies in Egypt and performed a study in an
attempt to understand the situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our findings indicate that the Tor anonymity network appeared to be interfered
with in Egypt, while HTTPS connections to DigitalOcean&amp;rsquo;s Frankfurt data centre
were throttled. We also found that access to porn sites appeared to be
interfered with via in-band TCP packet injections of advertisement and malware
content, and that the blocking of &lt;a href="https://www.alaraby.co.uk">The New Arab&lt;/a>
website led to the blocking of specific content (such as images) of other sites
that are hosted on the same Content Distribution Network (CDN).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>EEEP and Greek Internet censorship</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/eeep-greek-censorship/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/eeep-greek-censorship/</guid><description>Technical analysis of Hellenic gaming commission blacklist in Greece</description></item></channel></rss>