<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Whatsapp on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/whatsapp/</link><description>Recent content in Whatsapp on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/whatsapp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ethiopia: From internet blackouts to the blocking of WhatsApp and Telegram</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-whatsapp-telegram/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-whatsapp-telegram/</guid><description>&lt;p>Communication access in Ethiopia has significantly been disrupted over the last week. Internet access and Short Message Services (SMS) were &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/save/https://twitter.com/addisstandard/status/1139127606211727360">disconnected&lt;/a> intermittently across the country.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>During the first half of the week, internet connectivity was &lt;a href="https://ioda.caida.org/ioda/dashboard#view=inspect&amp;entity=country/ET&amp;lastView=overview&amp;from=1560166834&amp;until=now">shut down completely&lt;/a>. After access was restored, both &lt;a href="https://explorer.ooni.io/measurement/20190615T215418Z_AS24757_NKzIEujAd7rEN95SsIZnraLm1yjqdU79EqczVKFLUzsOJh4DLE">WhatsApp&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://explorer.ooni.io/measurement/20190615T222820Z_AS24757_4flsDD8gZDpmh2jr60nmgLuGGymkNsRA8HOejGDOFZZDEWr6EP">Telegram&lt;/a> were blocked. A few days ago, Ethio Telecom (the only telecom in the country) &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20190619122350/https:/twitter.com/ethiotelecom_/status/1141013304762146817">published a notice&lt;/a>, acknowledging the internet disruptions, but came short on details about the extent of communication disruptions or why they occurred in the first place.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mali: Social media disruptions amid 2018 presidential election?</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/mali-disruptions-amid-2018-election/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/mali-disruptions-amid-2018-election/</guid><description>&lt;p>Two days ago, on 29th July 2018, Malians went to the polls to vote in &lt;a href="http://www.africanews.com/2018/07/26/mali-2018-presidential-election-top-10-facts/">presidential elections&lt;/a>
and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Internet_SF/status/1023883426208915456">reported&lt;/a> that social media was inaccessible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is &lt;em>not&lt;/em> the first time that social media is reportedly blocked in Mali.
Facebook and Twitter were &lt;a href="https://qz.com/762082/mali-is-the-latest-african-country-to-impose-a-social-media-blackout/">blocked two years ago&lt;/a>
amidst violent protests against the detention of a popular radio host. Last
month, Internet Sans Frontieres &lt;a href="https://www.accessnow.org/fighting-censorship-in-2018-elections/">reported&lt;/a>
that social media was disrupted in Mali, following a violent police crackdown
on banned opposition protests calling for transparency and accountability in
the 2018 presidential elections.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>New OONI tests examine the blocking of WhatsApp and Facebook Messenger</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/whatsapp-and-facebook-tests/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/whatsapp-and-facebook-tests/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today the &lt;a href="https://ooni.org/">Open Observatory of Network Interference
(OONI)&lt;/a> project is excited to announce the release
of &lt;em>two&lt;/em> new software tests which are designed to examine the blocking of
&lt;strong>WhatsApp&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>Facebook Messenger&lt;/strong>. You can now run these tests to monitor the
accessibility of these apps across time, and to collect data that can serve as
evidence when/if they are blocked.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="whatsapp-test">WhatsApp test&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Many of our users have asked us to develop a test to examine the accessibility
of WhatsApp, especially in light of it being &lt;a href="https://ooni.org/post/brazil-whatsapp-block/">blocked&lt;/a> by various governments
around the world during elections, protests, and other political events.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Ethiopia: Evidence of social media blocking and internet censorship</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-report/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-report/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img alt="Ethiopia image" src="https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-report/et-05.png">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Youth in Addis trying to get Wi-Fi Connection. Credit Addis Fortune Newspaper&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently we published a &lt;a href="https://ooni.org/post/ethiopia-internet-shutdown-amidst-recent-protests/">post&lt;/a> about what appeared to be a possible internet
shutdown in Ethiopia during a wave of ongoing protests by ethnic groups. Today,
in collaboration with &lt;a href="https://www.amnesty.org/">Amnesty International&lt;/a> we are releasing a report that
includes evidence of recent censorship events during Ethiopia’s political
upheaval.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See the &lt;a href="https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-report/amharic-translation.pdf">Amharic translation&lt;/a> of the report. Translated by Wolete Mariam.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>View the &lt;strong>pdf&lt;/strong> version of the report &lt;a href="https://ooni.github.io/documents/Ethiopia-Offline-evidence-of.pdf">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OONI Data Reveals How WhatsApp Was Blocked (Again) in Brazil</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/brazil-whatsapp-block/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/brazil-whatsapp-block/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Country:&lt;/strong> Brazil&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Probed ISPs:&lt;/strong> Tim mobile (AS 26615), Oi landline (AS 7738)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Censorship method:&lt;/strong> DNS Hijacking&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>OONI tests:&lt;/strong> HTTP Requests, DNS Consistency&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Measurement period:&lt;/strong> 2016-05-02 - 2016-05-03&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>19:10 UTC Saturday, 7 May 2016&lt;/strong> Update: Add OONI Explorer measurements links&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ever since &lt;a href="https://www.whatsapp.com/security/">WhatsApp implemented end-to-end
encryption&lt;/a> to protect the privacy and
security of its 1 billion users worldwide, several cases of censorship have
been ordered by governments who are frustrated with the fact that they can no
longer access users&amp;rsquo; private communications. Having implemented end-to-end
encryption with the Signal protocol, WhatsApp cannot decrypt its users&amp;rsquo; data,
even if it wanted to - which is precisely what makes it secure.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>