<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>blog on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/categories/blog/</link><description>Recent content in blog on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Job Opening: OONI Backend Developer</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2024-job-opening-ooni-backend-developer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2024-job-opening-ooni-backend-developer/</guid><description>Are you a backend developer interested in defending human rights on the internet? We have a job opening for you!
The OONI team (a non-profit measuring internet censorship globally) is looking for a dedicated Backend Developer to work on our backend components and infrastructure, and to provide OONI data analysis support for our research efforts.
Job description By joining our team, you will work on OONI’s backend components, ensuring the stable and reliable performance of our infrastructure in response to the growing global coverage of measurements.</description></item><item><title>OONI Community Interviews: Chido Musodza</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2024-interview-with-chido-musodza/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2024-interview-with-chido-musodza/</guid><description>Today we are excited to publish an interview with Chido Musodza, Program Associate, Community Engagement at Localization Lab. Chido is passionate about supporting minority language communities through the localization of open-source technology. Localization, on the one hand, makes tech products more inclusive and on the other hand, empowers the development of minority languages and their presence in digital space.
Watch Chido’s interview to learn more about the need for localization and community engagement!</description></item><item><title>OONI Partner Gathering 2024 in Malaysia</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2024-ooni-partner-gathering-report/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2024-ooni-partner-gathering-report/</guid><description>Background: OONI partners and previous events About the OONI Partner Gathering 2024 Objectives Why Malaysia? Sessions Day 1 – 8th May 2024 Day 2 – 9th May 2024 Unconference style sessions Inclusiveness Partner feedback Challenges Needs Outcomes Acknowledgements We are excited to share that on 8th and 9th May 2024, we hosted an in-person OONI Partner Gathering in Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia. As part of this 2-day event, we brought our partners (primarily from Asia and the Middle East) together to exchange skills and knowledge and strengthen our collaborations on internet censorship research and advocacy.</description></item><item><title>OONI Community Interviews: Tawanda Mugari</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2024-interview-with-tawanda-mugari/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2024-interview-with-tawanda-mugari/</guid><description>Today we are excited to publish an interview with Tawanda Mugari, Co-Founder &amp;amp; Geek in Chief of Digital Society of Africa (DSA). Through our partnership with DSA, we have had the opportunity to collaborate on research and training activities across southern Africa. Tawanda is a digital security expert, community leader and trainer who has been part of the OONI community for years. Watch Tawanda’s interview to learn more about his important work!</description></item><item><title>Internet sanctions on Russian media: diverging actions and mixed effects</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2024-eu-sanctions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2024-eu-sanctions/</guid><description>The original post appeared on the blog of SIDN Labs.
As a response to the Russian aggression against Ukraine, the European Union (EU) imposed sanctions on organisations affiliated with the Russian Federation prohibiting them from broadcasting content in the EU, including online distribution. In a collaborative effort with researchers from the University of Illinois Chicago, Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI), the University of Twente and the University of Amsterdam, we carried out a longitudinal traffic analysis to understand how internet service providers (ISPs) in different EU member states implement these sanctions.</description></item><item><title>Year in Review: OONI in 2023</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-year-in-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-year-in-review/</guid><description>As the end of 2023 approaches, we publish this post to share some OONI highlights from the last year. We also share some of the things we’ll be working on in 2024!
New OONI non-profit legal entity New OONI Project Manager New OONI measurement tools Launched OONI Probe Web Launched News Media Scan app with Deutsche Welle (DW) Building OONI Run v2 New OONI Explorer features Censorship Findings: 22 reports Domain-centric pages Network-centric pages User feedback reporting mechanism Charts on internet outages Research OONI research reports OONI reports for ISOC Pulse shutdown timeline Community New partnerships New OONI Outreach Kit New OONI screencasts and documentation Localization OONI Explorer OONI Run OONI Probe OONI documentation New OONI Community Interviews OONI workshops and presentations OONI-verse 2024 New OONI non-profit legal entity OONI is now a registered NGO in Italy!</description></item><item><title>OONI Community Interviews: Ihueze Nwobilor</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-interview-with-ihueze-nwobilor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-interview-with-ihueze-nwobilor/</guid><description>Today we are thrilled to publish an interview with Ihueze Nwobilor: Senior Programs Officer with Paradigm Initiative. Through our partnership with Paradigm Initiative, we have had the opportunity to collaborate on several research reports examining internet censorship in Nigeria. Ihueze’s work is focused on digital inclusion and on making digital technologies accessible to the under-served communities in numerous African countries, including Kenya, Nigeria, Senegal, South Sudan, Zambia, and Zimbabwe.
Since the blocking of Twitter in Nigeria in 2021, Ihueze has become an active OONI Probe user and gained a unique experience of using OONI data in his advocacy and government engagement work.</description></item><item><title>Launch: New OONI Censorship Findings platform</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-launch-ooni-censorship-findings-platform/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-launch-ooni-censorship-findings-platform/</guid><description>Image: OONI Censorship Findings platform.
Today we are thrilled to announce the launch of the OONI Censorship Findings platform!
Internet censorship is frequently being reported around the world, but how can we verify such events with empirical evidence?
Our new platform provides short reports on internet censorship around the world based on OONI&amp;rsquo;s open data. With the launch of the platform, we are publishing 20 reports on internet censorship that emerged in 2023.</description></item><item><title>Measure all the Things! IMC Hackathon 2023</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/imc-hackathon-results-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/imc-hackathon-results-2023/</guid><description>On 23rd October 2023, right before the Internet Measurement Conference (IMC) 2023, we co-hosted an internet measurement hackathon in collaboration with the Internet Society (ISOC), M-Lab, Censored Planet and IODA.
In this post we would like to share some of the projects that were developed as part of the hackathon. It was great to see how much was accomplished in such a short period of time!
The day started with an introduction to the various datasets from OONI&amp;rsquo;s Arturo, Censored Planet&amp;rsquo;s Armin, IODA&amp;rsquo;s Zach, ISOC&amp;rsquo;s Amreesh and M-Lab&amp;rsquo;s Lai Yi.</description></item><item><title>OONI Community Interviews: Siti Nurliza</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-interview-with-siti-nurliza/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-interview-with-siti-nurliza/</guid><description>Today we are thrilled to publish an interview with Siti Nurliza: a talented data analyst and technologist with Sinar Project, one of our most dedicated and long-term partners who have led OONI censorship measurement efforts in Southeast Asia for more than 6 years!
Sinar Project is a civic tech initiative using open technology, open data and policy analysis to systematically make important information public and more accessible to the Malaysian people.</description></item><item><title>Join us at the IMC 2023 Hackathon on Network Interference using Open Data</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-imc-hackathon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-imc-hackathon/</guid><description>Are you attending the Internet Measurement Conference (IMC) 2023?
Join us at the IMC Hackathon on Network Interference using Open Data on Monday, 23rd October 2023, in Montreal, Canada. The hackathon is organized by the Internet Society (ISOC), the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI), M-Lab and Censored Planet.
IMC is a yearly academic conference focusing on Internet measurement and analysis. The conference is sponsored by ACM SIGCOMM.
This IMC Hackathon will be about exploring, analyzing, and visualizing open network measurement data with a focus on identifying Internet censorship and Internet shutdown events.</description></item><item><title>New OONI Explorer features for investigating internet censorship through open data</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-new-explorer-features/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-new-explorer-features/</guid><description>We’re excited to share that OONI Explorer includes new features for investigating internet censorship worldwide based on open data.
Specifically, these features include:
New domain-centric pages; New network-centric pages; New “internet outage” charts (integrating IODA, Google traffic, and Cloudflare Radar data), available in each country-specific and network-specific page; New user feedback reporting mechanism, available through the “Verify” button in the banner of each OONI measurement page. In this blog post, we share information about these new features.</description></item><item><title>Job Opening: OONI Project Manager</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-job-opening-ooni-project-manager/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-job-opening-ooni-project-manager/</guid><description>This job posting is now closed. Any applications received after 2023-06-28 will not be considered
Are you a project manager interested in defending human rights on the internet? We have a job opening for you!
The OONI team (a non-profit measuring internet censorship globally) is looking for a dedicated project manager to help us manage our software development work.
We will be reviewing applications on a rolling basis.
Job description By joining our team, you will help ensure that our software projects are on track, supporting a global community that relies on our tools for measuring and fighting internet censorship.</description></item><item><title>Introducing OONI Probe Web</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/introducing-ooni-probe-web/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/introducing-ooni-probe-web/</guid><description>Today, we are excited to announce the launch of OONI Probe Web: a new browser-based tool for measuring the blocking of websites.
We built OONI Probe Web in response to long-term community feedback, requesting a censorship measurement tool that can be run from a browser, without requiring the installation of any software. Our goal is to support rapid response efforts to emergent censorship events.
However, please note that OONI Probe Web is experimental, and what can be measured from a browser is very limited in comparison to what can be measured from an app.</description></item><item><title>How we're improving OONI data quality: An analysis of failed measurements</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/improving-data-quality-analysis-of-failed-measurements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/improving-data-quality-analysis-of-failed-measurements/</guid><description>In this blog post, we manually analyse failed OONI measurements to assess why they were classified as such, whether they are symptomatic of censorship, and whether they still carry helpful information for researchers. We focus on measurements from three countries (India, Pakistan, and Indonesia) and outline steps on how we will improve overall data quality.
Background
Methodology
Results
Pakistan
India
Indonesia
Overall
Limitations
Conclusions and Future Work
Background Web Connectivity is a network test that determines whether a web resource is accessible from the network where the user runs OONI Probe.</description></item><item><title>Year in Review: OONI in 2022</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2022/</guid><description>As the end of 2022 approaches, we publish this post to share some OONI highlights from the last year. We also share some of the things we’ll be working on in 2023!
OONI Team
OONI Probe
New OONI Probe experiments
New Test Lists Editor
OONI Run improvements
OONI Probe Web prototype
OONI data
1 billion measurements
New OONI Measurement Aggregation Toolkit (MAT)
New Circumvention Tool Reachability Dashboard
Advancing OONI data analysis</description></item><item><title>OONI Community Video</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-community-video/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-community-video/</guid><description>We are happy to celebrate OONI&amp;rsquo;s 10th anniversary together with our amazing community, who have been at the heart of our work over the past decade.
Today, we are excited to share a new video with OONI community members, where they discuss how OONI has been useful to their work, while sharing what they would like to see OONI do in the future.
Featured community members and partners Andrés Azpúrua, Venezuela Inteligente Andrés is the co-founder and Director of Venezuela Inteligente, a non-profit organization that aims to facilitate information, communication and collaboration between citizens and civil society organizations to create impact from a non-partisan perspective.</description></item><item><title>Highlights: 10 Years of OONI</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/highlights-10-years-of-ooni/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/highlights-10-years-of-ooni/</guid><description>Today is OONI’s 10th anniversary!
As of today, 10 years ago, the first OONI measurement was published. Today, 10 years later, more than a billion OONI measurements have been published, shedding light on internet censorship worldwide.
In this post, we share some OONI highlights from the past 10 years, as well as some of our future plans.
You can start off by getting a glimpse of “OONI in 10 years” through the following animation, which shares some highlights from the past decade.</description></item><item><title>Join the 10th Ooniversary Events!</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/10th-ooniversary-events/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/10th-ooniversary-events/</guid><description>Subscribe on YouTube You’re invited to join us for the celebration of OONI’s 10th anniversary!
To share OONI highlights from the last 10 years, as well as how community members have used OONI tools and data as part of their work, we’ll be hosting 2 live-streamed events:
OONI Highlights:
Date and time: 5th December 2022 at 14:00 UTC (1 hour event)
Location: Live-streamed on OONI YouTube channel
OONI Community:</description></item><item><title>Survey: Help shape OONI’s strategic priorities</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-survey-ooni-strategic-priorities/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-survey-ooni-strategic-priorities/</guid><description>OONI will celebrate its 10th anniversary on 5th December 2022!
This is a time for celebration, but also a time for reflection: What worked well? What should we improve? What should we do differently going forward?
The OONI community has been at the heart of our work over the past decade, and so we invite our community to help shape OONI’s strategic priorities for the future.
Please take a few minutes to complete our survey: https://ooni.</description></item><item><title>New online OONI training course launched by Advocacy Assembly</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-ooni-training-course-advocacy-assembly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-ooni-training-course-advocacy-assembly/</guid><description>We are excited to share that a free, online OONI training course (“Measuring Internet Censorship with OONI tools”) has been launched today on Small Media’s Advocacy Assembly platform!
Through this course, you will learn how to measure internet censorship through the use of OONI tools. You will also learn how to access and interpret real-time OONI data on internet censorship around the world.
Today, the course is available in English, Arabic, Spanish, and Farsi.</description></item><item><title>New Test Lists Editor: Contribute websites for censorship testing</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-test-lists-editor/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-test-lists-editor/</guid><description>Today the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) team is excited to announce the public launch of our new Test Lists Editor!
This platform enables the public to review and contribute to the lists of websites (“test lists”) that are tested for censorship by OONI Probe users around the world.
Help the internet freedom community discover website blocks around the world by contributing through the new Test Lists Editor!</description></item><item><title>OONI’s submission for the OHCHR report on internet shutdowns and human rights</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-ooni-submission-ohchr-report-internet-shutdowns/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-ooni-submission-ohchr-report-internet-shutdowns/</guid><description>Currently, the 50th session of the UN Human Rights Council is taking place.
In response to the UN High Commissioner for Human Rights’s call for submissions in support of the OHCHR report on internet shutdowns and human rights to the 50th session of the Human Rights Council in June 2022, the OONI team provided a submission with relevant information on the occurrence of mandated disruptions of access to social media and messaging platforms over the past 5 years based on empirical OONI network measurement data.</description></item><item><title>Job Opening: OONI Community Coordinator</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-job-opening-ooni-community-coordinator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-job-opening-ooni-community-coordinator/</guid><description>Are you passionate about defending human rights on the internet? Are you extremely organized and enjoy supporting communities around the world? We have a job opening for you!
The OONI team (a non-profit fighting internet censorship) is looking for a dedicated community coordinator to help grow and support the OONI community around the world.
The application deadline is Sunday, 12th June 2022.
Job description By joining our team, you will support our partners and global community of human rights defenders to measure and fight internet censorship.</description></item><item><title>New Launch: OONI Measurement Aggregation Toolkit (MAT)</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-ooni-mat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-ooni-mat/</guid><description>Today the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) team is thrilled to announce the public launch of the OONI Measurement Aggregation Toolkit (MAT)!
The MAT is a tool that enables you to create your own custom charts based on aggregate views of real-time OONI data collected from around the world.
Use the MAT to track internet censorship worldwide based on real-time OONI data!
About the MAT
What is OONI data?</description></item><item><title>Year in Review: OONI in 2021</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2021/</guid><description>In light of the ongoing global COVID-19 pandemic, 2021 continued to be a challenging year for everyone.
Yet, several exciting things happened in the censorship measurement world. In this post, we share some OONI highlights from 2021, as well as some upcoming OONI projects for 2022!
OONI Probe
Automated OONI Probe testing
New Debian package for OONI Probe
New OONI Probe Command Line Interface for Linux and macOS
New OONI Probe Experimental card</description></item><item><title>iThena integration of OONI Probe boosts censorship measurement coverage worldwide</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-ithena-boosts-ooni-measurement-coverage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-ithena-boosts-ooni-measurement-coverage/</guid><description>Over the last months, the iThena project integrated OONI Probe into their platform, resulting in a major spike in OONI censorship measurement coverage around the world.
In this blog post, we’re excited to introduce you to iThena and discuss how they helped support censorship measurement worldwide.
About iThena
OONI Probe integration into iThena
About iThena iThena, developed by the Cyber-Complex Foundation, is a distributed computation and measurement project based on the Berkeley Open Infrastructure for Network Computing (BOINC) platform.</description></item><item><title>[Event Report] India, Let's Build the List</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-event-india-test-list/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-event-india-test-list/</guid><description>This is a guest post by The Bachchao Project, originally published here.
The Bachchao Project in partnership with OONI hosted an online event on 9th and 10th October 2021 to update the Citizen Lab test list for India. The event, which was called “India, Lets build the list”, was organised to help strengthen community based monitoring of internet censorship in India. The event allowed experts from different fields to contribute to a curated list of websites that are relevant to India and which are regularly tested for censorship by volunteers in India.</description></item><item><title>Why Collaboration and Transparency is Key to Internet Measurement</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-internet-measurements-collaboration-transparency/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-internet-measurements-collaboration-transparency/</guid><description>This post was originally published on the Internet Society Pulse blog.
With Internet shutdowns, disruptions and censorship events on the increase around the world, tracking where such events are happening and gathering evidence to help in the fight against them is becoming more and more important.
Tracking these events is crucial because of the impact they have on society and the economy. When social media apps are blocked, for example, freedom of speech, access to information, and movement-building is hampered.</description></item><item><title>Job Opening: Mobile Developer for OONI Probe</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-job-opening-ooni-mobile-developer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-job-opening-ooni-mobile-developer/</guid><description>Are you a mobile developer interested in defending human rights on the internet? We have a job opening for you!
The OONI team (a non-profit fighting internet censorship, originally born out of the Tor Project) is looking for a dedicated mobile developer to work on OONI Probe: a free software app designed to measure internet censorship and network performance.
The application deadline is Sunday, 31st October 2021.
Job description If you join our team, you will lead the development of the OONI Probe mobile app, supporting human rights defenders worldwide to investigate and fight internet censorship.</description></item><item><title>A brief introduction to OONI</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/brief-introduction-to-ooni/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/brief-introduction-to-ooni/</guid><description>This is gentle introduction to OONI that does not require readers to have a technical background.
If you are familiar with how the Internet works and how it can be censored you can skip The basics.
For frequently asked questions and answers, please refer to the OONI FAQ.
The basics You might be connecting to the Internet from a local network or using an Internet Service Provider (ISP).
ISPs are usually not connected to each other.</description></item><item><title>Accessing OONI data</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/mining-ooni-data/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/mining-ooni-data/</guid><description>This page has moved to: https://docs.ooni.org/data/</description></item><item><title>OONI Partner Training 2021</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-partner-training-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-partner-training-2021/</guid><description>Over the last week, we had the pleasure to host two 3-day OONI Partner Training events for our partners in Africa, Latin America, the Middle East, and Asia. As part of these events, our goal was to share OONI-specific knowledge and skills, and to collect feedback to better serve community needs.
In this post, we share information about the training events.
About
Sessions
Session 1: Information Controls Around the World (Day 1)</description></item><item><title>Making the OONI Probe Android app more resilient</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/making-ooni-probe-android-more-resilient/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/making-ooni-probe-android-more-resilient/</guid><description>We recently made OONI Probe Android more robust against accidental or deliberate blocking of our backend services. Specifically, we implemented support for specifying a proxy that speaks with OONI’s backend services. We also improved the build process to influence the TLS Client Hello fingerprint, which helps with avoiding accidental blocking.
Adding support for a proxy
Changing our Android TLS fingerprint
Future improvements
Adding support for a proxy Since late 2020, community members have been reporting specific OONI Probe Android failures.</description></item><item><title>Year in Review: OONI in 2020</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2020/</guid><description>In light of the global COVID-19 pandemic, 2020 has been a challenging year for everyone.
Yet, several exciting things happened in the censorship measurement world. In this post, we share some OONI highlights from 2020, as well as some upcoming OONI projects for 2021!
OONI Probe
New OONI Probe Desktop App for Windows and macOS
New OONI Probe measurement engine
OONI Run usability study
Measurement methodologies
New circumvention tool tests</description></item><item><title>Investigating Encrypted DNS Blocking in India</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-encrypted-dns-blocking-india/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-encrypted-dns-blocking-india/</guid><description>In October 2020, we collaborated with Divyank Katira and Gurshabad Grover, researchers at the Centre for Internet &amp;amp; Society, India, to implement and evaluate a new OONI experiment focused on detecting DNS censorship.
This new OONI experiment, called dnscheck, focuses on detecting the blocking of encrypted DNS transports such as DNS over TLS and DNS over HTTPS. Its methodology improves upon the measurement methodology OONI previously used to measure DoT blocking in Iran.</description></item><item><title>OONI Probe ASN Incident Report</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-ooni-probe-asn-incident-report/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-ooni-probe-asn-incident-report/</guid><description>Last week we noticed that some OONI measurements were available on OONI Explorer under a report ID containing a valid Autonomous System Number (ASN), even though the raw JSON data contained zero as the ASN (i.e. encoded as AS0). We initially thought that this was caused by a bug in our API code, but it actually turned out to be an OONI Probe bug in our probe engine (which powers the OONI Probe apps).</description></item><item><title>Internet Measurement Village 2020: Slides &amp; Video Recordings</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-imv-slides-recordings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-imv-slides-recordings/</guid><description>Over the last month, between 10th June 2020 to 3rd July 2020, we organized and hosted the Internet Measurement Village (IMV) 2020, an online community event aimed at sharing skills, knowledge, and resources on internet measurement, in defense of a free and open internet.
As all the IMV sessions were live-streamed and will continue to live on the OONI YouTube channel, we hope that these recordings will serve as a valuable resource on internet measurement for the internet freedom community.</description></item><item><title>Support the OTF: Support a Free and Open Internet</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-support-otf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-support-otf/</guid><description>Over the last month, the Open Technology Fund (OTF) &amp;ndash; one of the main funders of free censorship circumvention and privacy-enhancing technologies that human rights defenders worldwide rely on &amp;ndash; has been under threat, following the ousting of its leadership.
We previously published a statement in support of the OTF, explaining why we think the OTF is essential for internet freedom and encouraging the public to sign the letter to congress.</description></item><item><title>Azərbaycan: OONI Probe Test üçün çağırış</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-azerbaijan-ooni-probe-testing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-azerbaijan-ooni-probe-testing/</guid><description>This is a guest post by Arzu Geybullayeva (Azerbaijan Internet Watch), originally published here.
Azerbaijan Internet Watch Azərbaycanda internet senzurasını izləyir və bu çərçəvədə aşkar etdiyi pozuntuları öz səhifəsində sənədləşdirir. Bu barədə daha ətraflı məlumatı buradan əldə edə bilərsiniz.
Layihənin bir vacib cəhətlərindən biri də ölkədə bloklanan veb səhifələri izləmək ve bu bloklamaların necə baş verdiyini araşdırmaqdır. Bu barədə isə daha ətraflı buradan və buradan məlumat əldə edə bilərsiniz.</description></item><item><title>Save Internet Freedom: Support the Open Technology Fund</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-06-19-save-internet-freedom-support-the-open-technology-fund/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 16:48:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-06-19-save-internet-freedom-support-the-open-technology-fund/</guid><description>Last Wednesday was dubbed as a “Wednesday night massacre”, following the firing of the directors of four organizations overseen by the US Agency for Global Media (USAGM): Radio Free Asia, Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, Middle East Broadcasting, and the Open Technology Fund (OTF).
Out of these four organizations, we would like to draw your attention to the OTF, not only because they have been a long-term funder of our project but, more importantly, because they have been essential in creating the internet freedom community as we know it.</description></item><item><title>OONI Run Usability Study: Findings</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-06-09-ooni-run-usability-study-findings/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 09:38:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-06-09-ooni-run-usability-study-findings/</guid><description>OONI Run is a platform (launched in September 2017) that you can use to generate mobile deep links and widget code to coordinate OONI Probe testing. To enable community members to more effectively use OONI Run, we researched its limitations and collected structured community feedback through an OONI Run usability study.
This report outlines the objectives, personas, assumptions, and methods of this study.
We also share the outcomes based on the analysis of information collected through our survey and interviews with community members, as well as some of the next steps towards improving OONI Run.</description></item><item><title>Join the online Internet Measurement Village 2020</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-internet-measurement-village/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-internet-measurement-village/</guid><description>Subscribe on YouTube We are excited to bring the first online Internet Measurement Village to you this month.
Interested in learning all about Internet measurement and how to detect Internet censorship? Curious to explore open datasets on Internet censorship and Internet outages? Eager to learn how advocates are pushing back against Internet shutdowns and defending a free and open Internet?
Join us for the online Internet Measurement Village, starting on Wednesday, 10th June 2020 and ending on Friday, 3rd July 2020.</description></item><item><title>OONI Run Survey &amp; Interviews: Share your feedback</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-ooni-run-survey-and-interviews/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-ooni-run-survey-and-interviews/</guid><description>OONI Run is a platform that you can use to generate mobile deep links and widget code to coordinate OONI Probe testing.
Researchers and human rights defenders around the world have used OONI Run to coordinate OONI Probe censorship measurement campaigns, particularly leading up to and during political events (such as elections and protests).
We’re excited to hear more about your experience with OONI Run so that we can improve it.</description></item><item><title>Launched: New OONI Probe Desktop App for Windows and macOS</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-ooni-probe-desktop-app/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-ooni-probe-desktop-app/</guid><description>Today, OONI is thrilled to announce the public launch of the new OONI Probe desktop app that you can download and install on Windows and macOS to measure internet censorship and network performance.
Install OONI Probe Desktop app By running the tests in the new OONI Probe desktop app, you can measure:
Blocking of websites;
Blocking of WhatsApp, Facebook Messenger, and Telegram;
Blocking of Tor and Psiphon;
Presence of systems (“middleboxes”) that could potentially be responsible for censorship and/or surveillance;</description></item><item><title>Building a smart URL list system: Policy for URL prioritization</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-smart-url-list-system/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-smart-url-list-system/</guid><description>To improve the monitoring of website censorship around the world, OONI aims to create a smart URL list system, while ensuring, to the extent possible, the safety of the URL lists themselves by running them through the usual Citizen Lab URL review process. This will help ensure smarter test target selection and by extension, it will enable us &amp;ndash; and the broader internet freedom community &amp;ndash; to more effectively monitor, analyze, and respond to cases of website censorship around the world.</description></item><item><title>Let's measure the accessibility of COVID-19 websites around the world</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/covid-19-ooni-measurement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/covid-19-ooni-measurement/</guid><description>Ensuring a free and open internet during an emergency, like the current COVID-19 pandemic, is more important than ever. However, access to information related to the coronavirus pandemic has already been censored by certain governments. China censored information on the coronavirus on Chinese social media platforms, while Venezuela’s state-owned CANTV blocked access to a coronavirus information portal last week.
We therefore invite you to participate in a measurement campaign to check if COVID-19 sites are accessible in your country (and on the network you’re using) and to share relevant measurement data with the world.</description></item><item><title>Year in Review: OONI in 2019</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2019/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2019/</guid><description>As the new decade begins, we publish this post to share some OONI highlights from 2019. We also share some thoughts for 2020.
New Apps
Revamped OONI Probe Mobile App
New OONI Probe Desktop App
Near real-time publication of OONI measurements
Revamped OONI Explorer
OONI PostgreSQL MetaDB
Improved measurements
New OONI Probe tests
New OONI Probe measurement engine
Community
New partnerships
Research publications
OONI workshops and presentations
Community resources
OONI-verse</description></item><item><title>OONI Highlights: 2017-2019</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-highlights-2017-2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-highlights-2017-2019/</guid><description>This post was originally published on the OTF website.
Back in 2012, the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) was born with OTF support to create the first open methodologies that would enable anyone around the world to measure internet censorship and other forms of network interference.
Today, OONI comprises a global community that runs its censorship measurement software (OONI Probe) in more than 200 countries every month. Millions of measurements have been collected from tens of thousands of networks in 236 countries since 2012, all of which are openly published on OONI Explorer &amp;ndash; arguably the largest publicly available resource on internet censorship to date.</description></item><item><title>Call to Action: Let’s measure the blocking of LGBTQI websites around the world!</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-measure-blocking-lgbtqi-sites/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-measure-blocking-lgbtqi-sites/</guid><description>LGBTQI websites are blocked in several countries around the world, such as Malaysia and Indonesia. This includes popular dating apps and sites, like grindr, which is blocked in Lebanon and Iran.
How can we track the blocking of LGBTQI sites around the world?
We have teamed up with OutRight Action International &amp;ndash; a leading international LGBTQI human rights organization &amp;ndash; to investigate the blocking of LGBTQI sites worldwide.
We invite you to contribute to this research!</description></item><item><title>Next Generation OONI Explorer Launched!</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/next-generation-ooni-explorer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/next-generation-ooni-explorer/</guid><description>Today the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) team is thrilled to announce the public launch of the revamped, next generation OONI Explorer!
OONI Explorer is an open data resource on internet censorship around the world. This new platform offers access to millions of censorship measurements collected from 233 countries since 2012.
About OONI Explorer
Why use OONI Explorer?
Who is OONI Explorer for?
OONI Explorer 2.0
Revamped country pages</description></item><item><title>OONI Software Development Guidelines</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-software-development-guidelines/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-software-development-guidelines/</guid><description>The goal of this document is to explain and explicit some of the best practices relevant to software development that we follow at the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI).
By following these development guidelines we aim to produce higher quality code, which contains less defects and allows us to iterate more quickly delivering greater value to our end users is a shorter amount of time!
Version control Also known as: “How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Love the Git!</description></item><item><title>OONI Probe Android 2.0.0 Incident Report</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-probe-android-200-incident/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-probe-android-200-incident/</guid><description>The first public release of OONI Probe Android 2.0.0 (since 2.0.0-alpha.7) included a very serious bug: we lost measurements and collected measurements that we shouldn’t have. As soon as the problem was identified, we quickly released a fix (OONI Probe Android 2.0.1). All measurements that should not have been uploaded have been deleted and we are working on a new OONI Probe release (OONI Probe Mobile 2.1.0) that will allow you to manually re-upload measurements.</description></item><item><title>Year in Review: OONI in 2018</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2018/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2018/</guid><description>As the new year begins, we publish this post to share some OONI highlights from 2018. We also share some of the exciting new projects we’ll be launching in 2019!
New partnerships
Research publications
Dev work behind the scenes
Revamped OONI Probe mobile app
Revamped OONI Explorer
New OONI Probe desktop apps
Probe Orchestration
OONI workshops and presentations
Videos
Expanding OONI-verse
New partnerships Our network of partners grew significantly in 2018!</description></item><item><title>Major Revamp: OONI Probe Mobile App 2.0 Launched!</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/revamped-ooni-probe-mobile-app/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/revamped-ooni-probe-mobile-app/</guid><description>Today the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) project is thrilled to announce the release of a major, new OONI Probe mobile app version!
Are websites and social media apps blocked? Is your network unusually slow?
Install OONI Probe now on Android or iOS to find out!
Why run OONI Probe?
OONI Probe 2.0 Highlights
Major UI overhaul
Overview of Test Results
Enhanced Website Testing
Test websites of your choice</description></item><item><title>Do you use OONI Probe? We want your feedback!</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooniprobe-ux-survey-and-interviews/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooniprobe-ux-survey-and-interviews/</guid><description>Survey (self-hosted mirror)
Since last year’s launch of the OONI Probe mobile apps, tens of thousands of people have been measuring internet censorship in around 200 countries every month. But OONI Probe is far from perfect.
We’re excited to hear more about your experience with the apps so that we can improve them.
We invite you to complete our survey and/or participate in an interview to provide feedback.
Survey We’d love to hear your thoughts on the current OONI Probe mobile apps.</description></item><item><title>OONI Community Interviews: Julie Owono</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-community-interviews-julie-owono/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-community-interviews-julie-owono/</guid><description>If you’ve met Julie Owono, you’ll probably agree that her passion and determination for defending digital rights is one of the things that stands out about her.
In her capacity as the Executive Director of Internet Sans Frontières (Internet Without Borders), Julie has spearheaded advocacy efforts in defense of online freedoms in many West African countries. Notably, Julie led campaigns against internet shutdowns in Cameroon, as well as in Togo and Chad.</description></item><item><title>OONI at RightsCon 2018</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-rightscon-2018/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-rightscon-2018/</guid><description>We are excited to participate at RightsCon next week: the world’s leading event on human rights in the digital age. Annually hosted by Access Now, this three-day conference will take place in Toronto between 16th-18th May 2018.
Over the last years, RightsCon has provided us the opportunity to participate in critical discussions in the digital rights field, meet many fascinating people and organizations, and to form new coalitions. We therefore look forward to participating at RightsCon and are eager to meet many new faces!</description></item><item><title>OONI Community Interviews: Moses Karanja</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-community-interviews-moses-karanja/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-community-interviews-moses-karanja/</guid><description>We first met Moses Karanja several years ago at the Citizen Lab Summer Institute. He’s a Kenyan information controls researcher, having previously worked with Strathmore University Law School research centre, CIPIT. Currently, he’s a PhD student at the University of Toronto.
Over the last years, Moses has championed OONI community engagement across Africa. Thanks to his tireless efforts, communities in many African countries are now running OONI Probe and using OONI data to examine internet censorship and other forms of network interference.</description></item><item><title>ParkNet: Short Documentary on Internet Censorship in Cuba</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/parknet-short-documentary-cuba/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/parknet-short-documentary-cuba/</guid><description>Last year we had the opportunity to travel to Cuba to explore its internet landscape. We spent most of our time hopping from one public WiFi hotspot to another, measuring networks in Havana, Santa Clara, and Santiago de Cuba. You might remember that we published a research report on our findings.
Today we publish a short documentary (“ParkNet”) on our study of internet censorship in Cuba.
“ParkNet” is a term that we coined to refer to parks that serve as public WiFi hotspots in Cuba.</description></item><item><title>OONI's recent participation at events in Africa, India, and Europe</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-africa-india-europe-conferences/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-africa-india-europe-conferences/</guid><description>Over the last months, the OONI team had the opportunity to host workshops, give presentations, and participate in discussions at the following conferences and events:
Seminar at the University of Cape Town (South Africa)
Internet Policy in Africa: Research Methods for Advocacy workshop (Uganda)
Nullcon 2018 (India)
Internet Freedom Festival (IFF) 2018 (Spain)
Tor Meeting (Italy)
These events provided us a great opportunity to meet many fascinating people from various communities, learn about their work, form new collaborations, and collect feedback for the improvement of our tools and methodologies.</description></item><item><title>Investigating Internet Blackouts from the Edge of the network: OONI's new upcoming methodology</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/investigating-internet-blackouts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/investigating-internet-blackouts/</guid><description>The OONI team is creating a new methodology aimed at automatically detecting and examining internet blackouts. Learn all about our methodology here.
Imagine a day where the internet is shut down completely. You have to work, check the news, and communicate with your friends and family. All of a sudden, you can’t do any of that, because there simply is no internet. It feels like a strange form of time travel has taken place: you’re thrown several decades into the past, into a world without internet, but in one which has learned to heavily rely on it.</description></item><item><title>Year in Review: OONI in 2017</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2017/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2017/</guid><description>As the end of 2017 approaches, we publish this blog to share some OONI highlights from the last year. We also share some of the things we’ll be working on in 2018!
OONI Probe mobile apps
Speed and performance tests
OONI Run
OONI API
OONI Partner Gathering
Research reports
OONI in 2018
OONI Probe mobile apps In February 2017, measuring internet censorship with OONI Probe suddenly became easier than ever before!</description></item><item><title>OONI at the 34th Chaos Communication Congress (34C3)</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-34c3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-34c3/</guid><description>Next week the OONI team will be attending the 34th Chaos Communication Congress (34C3): Europe’s largest hacker conference on technology, society, and utopia. Are you going? We hope to see you there!
OONI lecture OONI&amp;rsquo;s founder and project lead, Arturo Filastò, will be presenting OONI at 34C3.
Lecture OONI: Lets Fight Internet Censorship Together! Day 29th December 2017 Time 14:30 Room Saal Borg Attend the lecture to learn all about OONI, recent censorship findings from around the world, and how you can join the fight against internet censorship.</description></item><item><title>OONI at LAVITS and Primavera Hacker 2017</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-lavits-phacker-2017/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-lavits-phacker-2017/</guid><description>Earlier this month we had the opportunity to present OONI at two conferences in Chile: LAVITS and Primavera Hacker.
LAVITS LAVITS is a Latin American network of surveillance technology and society studies that organizes international symposiums since 2009. It features publications, talks and workshops related to surveillance and technology, internet censorship, resistance and counter surveillance, identification, biometrics, protection of personal data and privacy. The fifth series of the LAVITS symposium took place in Santiago, Chile from 29th November to 1st December 2017.</description></item><item><title>Identifying cases of DNS misconfiguration: Not quite censorship</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/not-quite-network-censorship/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/not-quite-network-censorship/</guid><description>Country: Brazil, worldwide
OONI tests: Web Connectivity, HTTP requests
Probed ISPs: AS1916 (Associação Rede Nacional de Ensino e Pesquisa), AS262650 (Kyatera Informatica Ltda), AS2715 (Fundacao de Amparo a Pesquisa/RJ), AS27699 (TELEFÔNICA BRASIL S.A), AS28573 (CLARO S.A.), AS52873 (SOFTDADOS CONECTIVIDADE), AS7738 (Telemar Norte Leste S.A.), AS8167 (Brasil Telecom S/A - Filial Distrito Federal)
Measurement period: July 2016 — November 2017
Website inaccessibility reasons: IPv6 or DNS misconfiguration
We recently noticed that pernambuco.</description></item><item><title>Writing a modern cross-platform desktop app</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/writing-a-modern-cross-platform-desktop-app/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/writing-a-modern-cross-platform-desktop-app/</guid><description>The goal of this article is to outline some of the architecture &amp;amp; design considerations made while thinking about how we would implement the OONI Probe desktop apps. This is the result of research and experimentation with a variety of different libraries and approaches. For each part of the technical stack we will outline the rationale leading to our choices.
Requirements &amp;amp; design goals Our primary goal with the OONI Probe desktop apps is to enable Windows and macOS desktop users to run OONI Probe network measurement tests without knowledge of the command line.</description></item><item><title>OONI Team Meeting: Montreal 2017</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-team-meeting-montreal-2017/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-team-meeting-montreal-2017/</guid><description>Last week, right before the Tor meeting, the OONI team gathered in Montreal for a 4-day meeting to reflect, regroup, hack, and plan.
This post shares information from our meeting and future plans with the broader community. All session notes are available on GitHub.
Summary: What OONI is working on
Sessions
Day 1 - 7th October 2017
Day 2 - 8th October 2017
Day 3 - 9th October 2017</description></item><item><title>OONI Run: Let's fight internet censorship together!</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-run/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-run/</guid><description>Today we released OONI Run, a website linked to an exciting new OONI Probe mobile app feature that enables you to:
Engage your friends (and the world) to run censorship measurement tests
Monitor the blocking of your website around the world
OONI Run includes a variety of OONI Probe software testsdesigned to:
Test the blocking of websites
Find middleboxes
Measure the speed and performance of networks
Measure video streaming performance</description></item><item><title>OONI Partner Gathering 2017</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-partner-gathering-2017/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-partner-gathering-2017/</guid><description>Two weeks ago we hosted the first OONI Partner Gathering in Toronto, Canada. This report provides an overview of the event, partner needs and challenges, and future goals to address them.
View the pdf version of the report here.
About
Objectives
Sessions
Day 1 - 10th July 2017
Day 2 - 11th July 2017
Inclusiveness
Challenges and needs
Future goals and priorities
Outcomes
Acknowledgements
About Over the last year, the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) project has had the opportunity to collaborate with various digital rights organizations in Latin America, Africa, the Middle East, and Asia.</description></item><item><title>OONI at the CryptoRave 2017</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-cryptorave-2017/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-cryptorave-2017/</guid><description>CryptoRave is a free, non-commercial and collectively funded 48 hour event featuring talks, workshops and activities related to security, privacy, anonymity, hacking and freedom of expression that attracts more that 2,500 people mainly from South America. The event took place in São Paulo, Brazil on 5th and 6th May 2017.
A number of people attended the OONI presentation and workshop (&amp;ldquo;Listatona&amp;rdquo;) that was co-organized with Coding Rights. During the workshop participants were able to better understand OONI&amp;rsquo;s testing methodology, and how OONI Probe performs network measurements.</description></item><item><title>OONI at the Internet Freedom Festival &amp; RightsCon 2017</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-iff-rightscon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-iff-rightscon/</guid><description>Over the last month the OONI team joined the internet freedom community at the following events:
Vietnam Cyber Dialogue (VCD)
Internet Freedom Festival (IFF)
Iran Cyber Dialogue (ICD)
RightsCon 2017
International Journalism Festival (IJF)
These events provided us with the opportunity to engage with community members, create new friendships, learn about new projects, and to share skills and knowledge. We also had the opportunity to facilitate sessions that allowed us to collect feedback for the improvement of our software and research methodologies.</description></item><item><title>Examining internet blackouts through public data sources</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/examining-internet-blackouts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 16:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/examining-internet-blackouts/</guid><description>Pulling the plug on the internet is one of the ways that governments around the world attempt to exert control over the flow of information.
While the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) project has developed numerous software tests for examining different forms of internet censorship (such as the blocking of websites, instant messaging apps, and censorship circumvention tools), we currently do not have tests that are designed to examine internet blackouts, when the internet as a whole is rendered inaccessible within a location.</description></item><item><title>New OONI Probe Mobile App: Measure Internet Censorship &amp; Performance</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-mobile-app/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-mobile-app/</guid><description>Today the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) project is thrilled to announce the release of a new mobile app (“OONI Probe - Measure Internet Censorship &amp;amp; Performance”) that can now be installed on Android and iOS for testing Internet censorship and network performance.
By running the tests included in OONI’s mobile app, you can monitor:
Blocking of websites; Presence of systems that could be responsible for censorship or surveillance; Speed and performance of your network.</description></item><item><title>New OONI tests examine the blocking of WhatsApp and Facebook Messenger</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/whatsapp-and-facebook-tests/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/whatsapp-and-facebook-tests/</guid><description>Today the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) project is excited to announce the release of two new software tests which are designed to examine the blocking of WhatsApp and Facebook Messenger. You can now run these tests to monitor the accessibility of these apps across time, and to collect data that can serve as evidence when/if they are blocked.
WhatsApp test Many of our users have asked us to develop a test to examine the accessibility of WhatsApp, especially in light of it being blocked by various governments around the world during elections, protests, and other political events.</description></item><item><title>OONI releases new Web UI: Run censorship tests from your web browser!</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/web-ui-post/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/web-ui-post/</guid><description>Today we are excited to announce the beta release of our new web-based user interface (WUI) that enables OONI Probe users to run censorship tests from a web browser!
Whether you’re running OONI Probe from your desktop or a Raspberry Pi, you can now easily choose which tests you want to run through OONI’s web UI and run them with the click of a button. These tests are designed to examine the following:</description></item><item><title>OONI releases Lepidopter Raspberry Pi distribution</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/lepidopter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/lepidopter/</guid><description>The Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) team is happy to announce the beta release of OONI Probe&amp;rsquo;s distribution for Raspberry Pis, caĺled Lepidopter.
What is Lepidopter Lepidopter is a Raspberry Pi distribution image with all the required dependencies and software packages in place, configured to run network measurement tests via the OONI Probe software. It is developed and designed to require no physical attendance upon first bootstrap but also allows experienced users to further configure it as they wish.</description></item><item><title>OONI-dev meeting and hackathon 2016</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-dev-and-hackathon-2016/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-dev-and-hackathon-2016/</guid><description>Oonitarians are spread out across the globe, and OONI’s core team is no exception. We recently met in Berlin to hack on OONI’s software, work on our roadmap, and to have all those discussions that are more fruitful to have in person than on IRC. We also held a hackathon to engage new individuals with our project!
Below we document some of the things that we worked on as part of our OONI-dev meeting and hackathon.</description></item><item><title>OONI Hackathon: Join us to explore internet censorship!</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/berlin-hackathon-2016/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/berlin-hackathon-2016/</guid><description>Interested in exploring (and exposing) internet censorship? Join the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) hackathon in Berlin!
When? Friday, 11th November &amp;amp; Saturday, 12th November 2016
Where? The OnionSpace (Gottschedstraße 4, 13357 Berlin, Germany)
What time? 10am onwards
Who? Software developers, data analysts, academics, journalists, bloggers, lawyers, activists, and all those who don’t go by any particular label, but are curious enough to join! We only have one rule: Be excellent to each other.</description></item><item><title>OONI releases new Web Connectivity test for detecting online censorship</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/web-connectivity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/web-connectivity/</guid><description>Today the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) is excited to be releasing a brand new test, called Web Connectivity, which is designed to detect three different types of censorship: DNS tampering, TCP/IP blocking and HTTP blocking.
Advantages of running Web Connectivity This test allows us to see which websites are blocked and how, more accurately than ever before!
Previously we relied on running separate (http_request, dns_consistency and tcp_connect) tests with the aim of identifying various forms of censorship.</description></item></channel></rss>