<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>uganda on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.org/tags/uganda/</link><description>Recent content in uganda on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.org/tags/uganda/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Uganda&#39;s Social Media Tax through the lens of network measurements</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/uganda-social-media-tax/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/uganda-social-media-tax/</guid><description>Image by @neemascribbles.
Probed ISPs: MTN (AS20294), Africell (AS36991), Airtel (AS37075), Smile Telecom (AS37122), Africa Online Uganda (AS29039), DATANET (AS29032), Sombha Solutions (AS328015), Roke (AS37063), Airtel (AS36977), Uganda Telecom (AS21491)
OONI tests: Web Connectivity, HTTP Invalid Request Line, HTTP Header Field Manipulation, WhatsApp, Facebook Messenger, Telegram, Vanilla Tor. Testing/analysis period: 1st July 2018 to 24th October 2018
Censorship methods: HTTP blocking (resetting connections) and TCP/IP blocking
Key Findings</description></item><item><title>How Uganda blocked social media, again</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/uganda-social-media-blocked/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/uganda-social-media-blocked/</guid><description>Country: Uganda
Probed ISPs: Orange (AS36991), SMILE (AS37122)
Censorship method: IP blocking
OONI tests: HTTP Requests
Measurement period: 2016-05-12
Last Wednesday, the Ugandan Communications Commission (UCC) ordered ISPs to block access to social media leading up to the (fifth) inauguration of President Yoweri Museveni, who has governed the country since 1986. Authorities argued that the blocking was ordered for “security purposes”, but the move directly harms political opposition, which has relied on social media to organize a “defiance campaign” of protests.</description></item></channel></rss>