<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>uganda on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.org/tags/uganda/</link><description>Recent content in uganda on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.org/tags/uganda/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Investigating Internet shutdowns through Mozilla telemetry</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/2021-investigating-internet-shutdowns-mozilla-telemetry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/2021-investigating-internet-shutdowns-mozilla-telemetry/</guid><description>More than 200 million users worldwide use the Firefox web browser (developed by Mozilla) every month.
If access to the Internet is shut down in a country, Mozilla should expect to see a dramatic drop in Firefox usage from that country. Given how widespread the use of Firefox is around the world, could Mozilla telemetry be a valuable resource for the Internet freedom community to investigate Internet shutdowns?
To explore this question, the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) and Internet Outage Detection and Analysis (IODA) teams joined forces to analyze a dataset of potential outage signals gathered through regular Mozilla telemetry, access to which was provided by Mozilla as part of a relevant research project to validate assumptions about the data.</description></item><item><title>Uganda: Data on internet blocks and nationwide internet outage amid 2021 general election</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/2021-uganda-general-election-blocks-and-outage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/2021-uganda-general-election-blocks-and-outage/</guid><description>Last week, amid its 2021 general election, Uganda was disconnected from the internet entirely. The country experienced a widespread internet blackout that lasted 4 days, starting on the eve of the election (13th January 2021) and ending in the morning of 18th January 2021. In the days leading up to the election, access to major social media platforms and circumvention tools was blocked &amp;ndash; even when the OTT (Over the Top) tax (commonly referred to as the “Social Media Tax”) was paid.</description></item><item><title>Uganda's Social Media Tax through the lens of network measurements</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/uganda-social-media-tax/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/uganda-social-media-tax/</guid><description>Image by @neemascribbles.
Probed ISPs: MTN (AS20294), Africell (AS36991), Airtel (AS37075), Smile Telecom (AS37122), Africa Online Uganda (AS29039), DATANET (AS29032), Sombha Solutions (AS328015), Roke (AS37063), Airtel (AS36977), Uganda Telecom (AS21491)
OONI tests: Web Connectivity, HTTP Invalid Request Line, HTTP Header Field Manipulation, WhatsApp, Facebook Messenger, Telegram, Vanilla Tor. Testing/analysis period: 1st July 2018 to 24th October 2018
Censorship methods: HTTP blocking (resetting connections) and TCP/IP blocking
Key Findings</description></item><item><title>How Uganda blocked social media, again</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/uganda-social-media-blocked/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/uganda-social-media-blocked/</guid><description>Country: Uganda
Probed ISPs: Orange (AS36991), SMILE (AS37122)
Censorship method: IP blocking
OONI tests: HTTP Requests
Measurement period: 2016-05-12
Last Wednesday, the Ugandan Communications Commission (UCC) ordered ISPs to block access to social media leading up to the (fifth) inauguration of President Yoweri Museveni, who has governed the country since 1986. Authorities argued that the blocking was ordered for “security purposes”, but the move directly harms political opposition, which has relied on social media to organize a “defiance campaign” of protests.</description></item></channel></rss>