<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DNS on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/dns/</link><description>Recent content in DNS on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/dns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Measuring DoT/DoH Blocking Using OONI Probe: A Preliminary Study</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-doh-dot-paper-dnsprivacy21/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-doh-dot-paper-dnsprivacy21/</guid><description>When you enter a URL such as https://example.com/, under the hood, your web browser resolves the example.com domain to one or more IP addresses using the Domain Name System (DNS), a set of federated servers and protocols providing this name-to-IP-address mapping. For example, as of 2022-06-16, example.com resolves to the 93.184.216.34 (IPv4) and 2606:2800:220:1:248:1893:25c8:1946 (IPv6) addresses. Once it knows the IP addresses for the domain, the browser then uses them to fetch the requested webpage.</description></item><item><title>Iran Protests: DPI blocking of Instagram (Part 2)</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2018-iran-protests-pt2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2018-iran-protests-pt2/</guid><description>In early January 2018, OONI published a post reporting on the blocking of Telegram and Instagram amidst protests in Iran. We have since been analyzing RIPE data and other network measurements collected from Iran in an attempt to better understand the blockages. Upon further analysis, we found that Instagram was in fact blocked (during the Iran protests) through the use of Deep Packet Inspection (DPI) technology which targeted the TLS protocol.</description></item><item><title>Identifying cases of DNS misconfiguration: Not quite censorship</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/not-quite-network-censorship/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/not-quite-network-censorship/</guid><description>Country: Brazil, worldwide
OONI tests: Web Connectivity, HTTP requests
Probed ISPs: AS1916 (Associação Rede Nacional de Ensino e Pesquisa), AS262650 (Kyatera Informatica Ltda), AS2715 (Fundacao de Amparo a Pesquisa/RJ), AS27699 (TELEFÔNICA BRASIL S.A), AS28573 (CLARO S.A.), AS52873 (SOFTDADOS CONECTIVIDADE), AS7738 (Telemar Norte Leste S.A.), AS8167 (Brasil Telecom S/A - Filial Distrito Federal)
Measurement period: July 2016 — November 2017
Website inaccessibility reasons: IPv6 or DNS misconfiguration
We recently noticed that pernambuco.</description></item></channel></rss>