<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DNS on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/dns/</link><description>Recent content in DNS on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/dns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Measuring DoT/DoH Blocking Using OONI Probe: A Preliminary Study</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-doh-dot-paper-dnsprivacy21/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-doh-dot-paper-dnsprivacy21/</guid><description>&lt;p>When you enter a URL such as &lt;code>https://example.com/&lt;/code>, under the
hood, your web browser resolves the &lt;code>example.com&lt;/code> domain to one or
more IP addresses using the Domain Name System (DNS), a set of
federated servers and protocols providing this name-to-IP-address
mapping. For example, as of 2022-06-16, &lt;code>example.com&lt;/code> resolves to
the &lt;code>93.184.216.34&lt;/code> (IPv4) and &lt;code>2606:2800:220:1:248:1893:25c8:1946&lt;/code>
(IPv6) addresses. Once it knows the IP addresses for the domain,
the browser then uses them to fetch the requested webpage. Conceptually,
the browser tries the IP addresses in sequence until it finds one
that works. If no returned IP address works, the request fails.
Therefore, domain name lookups are key to browsing and, incidentally,
are also key to website censorship and surveillance.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Iran Protests: DPI blocking of Instagram (Part 2)</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2018-iran-protests-pt2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2018-iran-protests-pt2/</guid><description>&lt;p>In early January 2018, OONI published a &lt;a href="https://ooni.github.io/post/2018-iran-protests/">post&lt;/a>
reporting on the blocking of Telegram and Instagram amidst protests in Iran. We
have since been analyzing RIPE data and other network measurements collected
from Iran in an attempt to better understand the blockages. Upon further
analysis, we found that Instagram was in fact blocked (during the Iran
protests) through the use of Deep Packet Inspection (DPI) technology which
targeted the TLS protocol. And it was configured in an interesting way.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Identifying cases of DNS misconfiguration: Not quite censorship</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/not-quite-network-censorship/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/not-quite-network-censorship/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Country:&lt;/strong> Brazil, worldwide&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>OONI tests:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://ooni.org/nettest/web-connectivity/">Web Connectivity&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://ooni.org/nettest/http-requests/">HTTP requests&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Probed ISPs:&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://stat.ripe.net/AS1916">AS1916&lt;/a> (Associação Rede Nacional de Ensino e Pesquisa),
&lt;a href="https://stat.ripe.net/AS262650">AS262650&lt;/a> (Kyatera Informatica Ltda),
&lt;a href="https://stat.ripe.net/AS2715">AS2715&lt;/a> (Fundacao de Amparo a Pesquisa/RJ),
&lt;a href="https://stat.ripe.net/AS27699">AS27699&lt;/a> (TELEFÔNICA BRASIL S.A),
&lt;a href="https://stat.ripe.net/AS28573">AS28573&lt;/a> (CLARO S.A.),
&lt;a href="https://stat.ripe.net/AS52873">AS52873&lt;/a> (SOFTDADOS CONECTIVIDADE),
&lt;a href="https://stat.ripe.net/AS7738">AS7738&lt;/a> (Telemar Norte Leste S.A.),
&lt;a href="https://stat.ripe.net/AS8167">AS8167&lt;/a> (Brasil Telecom S/A - Filial Distrito Federal)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Measurement period:&lt;/strong> July 2016 — November 2017&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Website inaccessibility reasons:&lt;/strong> IPv6 or DNS misconfiguration&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We recently noticed that &lt;a href="http://pernambuco.com">pernambuco.com&lt;/a>, a
regional news portal, has not been reachable from several networks in Brazil for quite some
time. By looking at &lt;a href="https://ooni.github.io/post/not-quite-network-censorship/measurements.br.pernambuco.csv">OONI data&lt;/a>, we found that the site was not reachable and that it presented signs of &lt;a href="https://explorer.ooni.org/measurement/s3YPvS70pxtUQXG5qLv8z2wfafZ98eUzCmxcbYkvSRELpYS2mBWksZCacvAr5GqS?input=http:%2F%2Fwww.pernambuco.com%2Fdiario">DNS-based
blocking&lt;/a>
due to empty DNS responses that is usually a symptom of potential internet censorship. But upon further analysis, we found a number of DNS
misconfigurations of the nameservers hosting the domain in question. A
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Name_server">nameserver&lt;/a> is a function of a DNS server that implements a
network service for providing responses to queries against a directory service.
In this article we present an analysis of possible DNS misconfigurations that
may have caused &lt;code>pernambuco.com&lt;/code> to be inaccessible. We also provide some
solutions to resolve DNS misconfiguration for &lt;code>pernambuco.com&lt;/code> and other sites potentially affected in Brazil and worldwide.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>