<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ooni-data on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/ooni-data/</link><description>Recent content in ooni-data on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/ooni-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OONI’s submission for the OHCHR report on internet shutdowns and human rights</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-ooni-submission-ohchr-report-internet-shutdowns/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-ooni-submission-ohchr-report-internet-shutdowns/</guid><description>Currently, the 50th session of the UN Human Rights Council is taking place.
In response to the UN High Commissioner for Human Rights’s call for submissions in support of the OHCHR report on internet shutdowns and human rights to the 50th session of the Human Rights Council in June 2022, the OONI team provided a submission with relevant information on the occurrence of mandated disruptions of access to social media and messaging platforms over the past 5 years based on empirical OONI network measurement data.</description></item><item><title>New Launch: OONI Measurement Aggregation Toolkit (MAT)</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-ooni-mat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-ooni-mat/</guid><description>Today the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) team is thrilled to announce the public launch of the OONI Measurement Aggregation Toolkit (MAT)!
The MAT is a tool that enables you to create your own custom charts based on aggregate views of real-time OONI data collected from around the world.
Use the MAT to track internet censorship worldwide based on real-time OONI data!
About the MAT
What is OONI data?</description></item></channel></rss>