<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>country-it on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>/tags/country-it/</link><description>Recent content in country-it on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/country-it/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Italy blocks Gutenberg book publishing website</title><link>/post/2021-italy-blocks-gutenberg-book-publishing-website/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2021-italy-blocks-gutenberg-book-publishing-website/</guid><description>Cases of internet censorship (that affect public interest) are rarely reported in Europe. Yet, www.gutenberg.org, a book-publishing website run by a non-profit organization, has been blocked in Italy since May 2020.
In this report, we share OONI network measurement data on the ongoing blocking of www.gutenberg.org across networks in Italy.
Background
Methods
Findings
Blocking methods by ISP
Vodafone Italia (AS30722)
Fastweb (AS12874)
Wind (AS1267)
TIM (AS16232)
Telecom Italia (AS3269)</description></item><item><title>Measurement observations on network performance during the COVID-19 pandemic in Northern Italy</title><link>/post/2020-network-performance-covid19-italy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2020-network-performance-covid19-italy/</guid><description>We were recently invited to participate in a NetGain Partnership webinar (titled “Surging Demand and The Global Internet Infrastructure”) to discuss the changing landscape for internet infrastructure and technology in the wake of the COVID-19 pandemic.
As part of our preparation for this webinar, we looked at network performance measurements collected from northern Italy over the last months (i.e. when Italy was hit hard by the COVID-19 pandemic) in an attempt to understand whether and to what extent there was a correlation between increased internet use and reduced network performance.</description></item></channel></rss>