<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Socialmedia on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/socialmedia/</link><description>Recent content in Socialmedia on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/socialmedia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mali: Social media disruptions amid 2018 presidential election?</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/mali-disruptions-amid-2018-election/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/mali-disruptions-amid-2018-election/</guid><description>&lt;p>Two days ago, on 29th July 2018, Malians went to the polls to vote in &lt;a href="http://www.africanews.com/2018/07/26/mali-2018-presidential-election-top-10-facts/">presidential elections&lt;/a>
and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Internet_SF/status/1023883426208915456">reported&lt;/a> that social media was inaccessible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is &lt;em>not&lt;/em> the first time that social media is reportedly blocked in Mali.
Facebook and Twitter were &lt;a href="https://qz.com/762082/mali-is-the-latest-african-country-to-impose-a-social-media-blackout/">blocked two years ago&lt;/a>
amidst violent protests against the detention of a popular radio host. Last
month, Internet Sans Frontieres &lt;a href="https://www.accessnow.org/fighting-censorship-in-2018-elections/">reported&lt;/a>
that social media was disrupted in Mali, following a violent police crackdown
on banned opposition protests calling for transparency and accountability in
the 2018 presidential elections.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Internet Access Disruption in Turkey - July 2016</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/turkey-internet-access-disruption/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/turkey-internet-access-disruption/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>With the attempted coup in Turkey, reports went out about social media being throttled and/or blocked. We analysed data about this that we collected with RIPE Atlas and the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI).&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On 15 July, a coup was attempted in Turkey. We heard about social media being throttled and/or blocked, but much was unclear about what was actually going on. Here we present measurement data from various platforms that shared their data publicly.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>