<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research reports and blog posts on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/</link><description>Recent content in Research reports and blog posts on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introducing OONI Probe Web</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-ooni-probe-web/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-ooni-probe-web/</guid><description>Today, we are excited to announce the launch of OONI Probe Web: a new browser-based tool for measuring the blocking of websites.
We built OONI Probe Web in response to long-term community feedback, requesting a censorship measurement tool that can be run from a browser, without requiring the installation of any software. Our goal is to support rapid response efforts to emergent censorship events.
However, please note that OONI Probe Web is experimental, and what can be measured from a browser is very limited in comparison to what can be measured from an app.</description></item><item><title>How we're improving OONI data quality: An analysis of failed measurements</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/improving-data-quality-analysis-of-failed-measurements/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/improving-data-quality-analysis-of-failed-measurements/</guid><description>In this blog post, we manually analyse failed OONI measurements to assess why they were classified as such, whether they are symptomatic of censorship, and whether they still carry helpful information for researchers. We focus on measurements from three countries (India, Pakistan, and Indonesia) and outline steps on how we will improve overall data quality.
Background
Methodology
Results
Pakistan
India</description></item><item><title>OONI measurements show ongoing internet censorship in Azerbaijan</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-azerbaijan-internet-censorship/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-azerbaijan-internet-censorship/</guid><description>Azerbaijan is known to block access to independent news media websites – we previously reported on this in July 2021. At the time, we analyzed OONI measurements collected from Azerbaijan between January 2020 to May 2021 and found that ISPs in Azerbaijan were blocking access to several independent news media and circumvention tool sites. We also found that amid the 2020 Nagorno-Karabakh war, ISPs in Azerbaijan temporarily blocked access to social media services, and attempted to block access to Tor and Psiphon.</description></item><item><title>How Internet censorship changed in Russia during the 1st year of military conflict in Ukraine</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-russia-a-year-after-the-conflict/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-russia-a-year-after-the-conflict/</guid><description>As of today, last year, Russia started its military operation in Ukraine. This was followed by increased levels of internet censorship, as Internet Service Providers (ISPs) in Russia started blocking access to several news media websites. In early March 2022, OONI published a report documenting these blocks, as well as the blocking of a site (200rf.com) that shares information about captured and killed Russian soldiers in Ukraine. OONI also reported that Russian ISPs started throttling access to Twitter on 26th February 2022, and switched to blocking it by 4th March 2022 – at which point, they also started blocking access to Facebook.</description></item><item><title>Ethiopia: Ongoing blocking of social media</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-ethiopia-blocks-social-media/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-ethiopia-blocks-social-media/</guid><description>On 9th February 2023, amid church split tensions and calls for anti-government protests, access to social media platforms (TikTok, Facebook, Telegram) was reportedly blocked in Ethiopia. Access Now also published a statement urging authorities in Ethiopia to stop blocking access to social media.
OONI data collected from Ethiopia provides signals of these blocks. Specifically, OONI data shows the ongoing blocking of Facebook and Telegram (since 9th February 2023) and YouTube (since 10th February 2023).</description></item><item><title>Pakistan: Blocking of Wikipedia and Deutsche Welle (DW)</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-pakistan-blocks-wikipedia-and-dw/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-pakistan-blocks-wikipedia-and-dw/</guid><description>Over the past weeks, access to Wikipedia and Deutsche Welle’s (DW) website was reportedly blocked in Pakistan.
As part of this report, we share OONI data from Pakistan that provides signals of these blocks. Specifically, OONI data shows that access to Wikipedia was temporarily restricted between 1st to 6th February 2023, while access to Deutsche Welle (DW) remains blocked since (at least) 16th January 2023.
Blocking of Deutsche Welle</description></item><item><title>Turkey: Throttling and DNS blocking of Twitter following deadly earthquake</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-turkey-throttling-blocking-twitter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-turkey-throttling-blocking-twitter/</guid><description>On 6th February 2023, a devastating 7.8-magnitude earthquake (followed by many strong aftershocks) struck (southern and central) Turkey and (northern and western) Syria, resulting in more than 36,000 deaths.
In the aftermath of the earthquake (on 8th February 2023), access to Twitter was reportedly temporarily restricted. OONI data collected from Turkey provides evidence that the block was implemented through targeted throttling and DNS interference.
The following chart aggregates OONI measurement coverage from the testing of Twitter (twitter.</description></item><item><title>iMAP 2022: New Research Reports on Internet Censorship in 8 Asian countries</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-imap-8-research-reports-southeast-asia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-imap-8-research-reports-southeast-asia/</guid><description>On 21st December 2022, our long-term partner, Sinar Project, published 8 new research reports on internet censorship in Southeast Asia and Hong Kong (China) in collaboration with their Internet Monitoring and Action Project (iMAP) partners. We are particularly excited about these reports as they make use of OONI data!
Internet Monitoring Action Project (iMAP) aims to establish regional and in-country networks that monitor network interference and restrictions to the freedom of expression online in 8 countries: Myanmar, Cambodia, Hong Kong (China), Indonesia, Malaysia, Philippines, Thailand, and Vietnam.</description></item><item><title>iMAP State of Internet Censorship Report 2022 - Cambodia</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-cambodia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-cambodia/</guid><description>News and other websites are periodically blocked in Cambodia, particularly those that disseminate information that could be perceived as a threat to the ruling government.1 In July 2018, the government ordered internet service providers (ISPs) to block at least 15 news websites during the country’s election.2 In the wake of the COVID-19 pandemic, the government has reportedly blocked access to news sites.3 In June 2020, the Ministry of Post telecommunications (MPTC) blocked six online gambling sites.</description></item><item><title>iMAP State of Internet Censorship Report 2022 - Hong Kong</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-hong-kong/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-hong-kong/</guid><description>Hong Kong, a place geographically conjunct to the soil of Mainland China, has been previously known as a free society, endured and still enduring multiple historical occasions. Once, there was no nationwide internet censorship until the latest development that local authorities and Beijing forcefully implemented the Hong Kong national security law in late June 2020. Currently, at least four websites are known to be censored, and a few ongoing discussions among pro-Beijing parties and the government to put censorship up on instant messaging and social platforms.</description></item><item><title>iMAP State of Internet Censorship Report 2022 - Indonesia</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-indonesia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-indonesia/</guid><description>In July 2014, Regulation of the Minister of Communications and Informatics Number 19 of 2014 on the Handling of Negative Internet Sites came into force as part of the regulator&amp;rsquo;s programme for Healthy and Safe Internet (INSAN or Internet Sehat dan Aman). The law mandated ISPs to block any internet content that is deemed to carry &amp;ldquo;negative&amp;rdquo; elements such as pornography, hoaxes, or SARA conflicts.
As of September 2022, the Indonesian Ministry of Information and Communication (Kominfo) has blocked over 1,000,000 websites through TrustPositif,1 a filtering application that has been operational since 2010 per Ministerial Regulation No 19 of 2014.</description></item><item><title>iMAP State of Internet Censorship Report 2022 - Malaysia</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-malaysia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-malaysia/</guid><description>It is a codified guarantee that the internet will not be censored except for illegal, obscene and indecent content, while in reality the extent of censorship and its implementation are wider than projected and remain to be explored.
The Ministry of Communications and Multimedia (MCMC) do not publish list of blocked sites, however statements were released from time to time to announce the number of sites blocked. It was revealed that 2,195 websites promoting online gambling were blocked as of March 2021.</description></item><item><title>iMAP State of Internet Censorship Report 2022 - Myanmar</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-myanmar/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-myanmar/</guid><description>Blocking of independent New Media. 112 out of 2,130 websites were detected 1,473 confirmed blocking counts through 6 local vantages under DNS level interference and HTTP level interference. There were 11 out of 31 websites’ categories from OONI were found as confirmed blocking. Among 11 categories, News Media was experiential as the highest confirmed blocking measurement, following to pornography to the second largest blocking counts. Interestingly, within 117 government websites, OONI detects 15 websites were blocked from 2 vantage points of 2 ISPs.</description></item><item><title>iMAP State of Internet Censorship Report 2022 - Philippines</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-philippines/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-philippines/</guid><description>In recent years, and with the COVID-19 pandemic increasing people’s reliance on digital technologies and with it the role of ICT regulators, agencies such as the NTC have come under fire for the “politicization” of the country’s telecommunications sector.1 This was most apparent under the administration of former president Rodrigo Duterte, whose six-year presidency was marred by the systematic undermining of democratic institutions and countless attacks against critical media and activists.</description></item><item><title>iMAP State of Internet Censorship Report 2022 - Thailand</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-thailand/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-thailand/</guid><description>Thailand, a country situated on the mainland of Southeast Asia, was under military junta for five years from 2014 to 2019. Upon the general election in 2019, the country has been nominally a parliamentary constitutional monarchy, although with lèse-majesté laws continuing to be invoked especially with regard to internet censorship. Adding the COVID-19 pandemic into the picture, the Thai government introduced Regulation 29 to curb fake news, which led to reported incidences of internet censorship.</description></item><item><title>iMAP State of Internet Censorship Report 2022 - Vietnam</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-vietnam/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-vietnam/</guid><description>Swedish Ambassador to Vietnam Pereric Högberg affirmed that Vietnam is making good use of opportunities from the internet, being one of the leading countries in Southeast Asia in terms of internet connection and development1. Vietnam is not limited to using the Internet and social networks2. However, there are still websites with controlled access in Vietnam.
Under the authoritarian political system, freedom of assembly, association, expression, press and religion, as well as civil society activism, is tightly restricted and controlled by the party despite legislation recognising civil and political rights in the Constitution.</description></item><item><title>Year in Review: OONI in 2022</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2022/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2022/</guid><description>As the end of 2022 approaches, we publish this post to share some OONI highlights from the last year. We also share some of the things we’ll be working on in 2023!
OONI Team
OONI Probe
New OONI Probe experiments
New Test Lists Editor
OONI Run improvements
OONI Probe Web prototype
OONI data
1 billion measurements</description></item><item><title>OONI Community Video</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-community-video/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-community-video/</guid><description>We are happy to celebrate OONI&amp;rsquo;s 10th anniversary together with our amazing community, who have been at the heart of our work over the past decade.
Today, we are excited to share a new video with OONI community members, where they discuss how OONI has been useful to their work, while sharing what they would like to see OONI do in the future.
Featured community members and partners Andrés Azpúrua, Venezuela Inteligente Andrés is the co-founder and Director of Venezuela Inteligente, a non-profit organization that aims to facilitate information, communication and collaboration between citizens and civil society organizations to create impact from a non-partisan perspective.</description></item><item><title>Highlights: 10 Years of OONI</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/highlights-10-years-of-ooni/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/highlights-10-years-of-ooni/</guid><description>Today is OONI’s 10th anniversary!
As of today, 10 years ago, the first OONI measurement was published. Today, 10 years later, more than a billion OONI measurements have been published, shedding light on internet censorship worldwide.
In this post, we share some OONI highlights from the past 10 years, as well as some of our future plans.
You can start off by getting a glimpse of “OONI in 10 years” through the following animation, which shares some highlights from the past decade.</description></item><item><title>Technical multi-stakeholder report on Internet shutdowns: The case of Iran amid autumn 2022 protests</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-iran-technical-multistakeholder-report/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-iran-technical-multistakeholder-report/</guid><description>Coordinators: OONI, ISOC Contributors: OONI, IODA, Measurement Lab (M-Lab), Cloudflare, Kentik, Censored Planet, ISOC, Article19 Facilitators: European Commission, United States This report shares empirical technical findings on the recent Internet shutdown events that emerged in Iran following the death of Jhina (Mahsa) Amini in September 2022. The report is intended to be the first among a series of multi-stakeholder reports aimed at shedding light on what is becoming a widespread and increasingly sophisticated practice of certain governments around the world.</description></item><item><title>Join the 10th Ooniversary Events!</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/10th-ooniversary-events/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/10th-ooniversary-events/</guid><description>Subscribe on YouTube You’re invited to join us for the celebration of OONI’s 10th anniversary!
To share OONI highlights from the last 10 years, as well as how community members have used OONI tools and data as part of their work, we’ll be hosting 2 live-streamed events:
OONI Highlights:
Date and time: 5th December 2022 at 14:00 UTC (1 hour event)</description></item><item><title>Survey: Help shape OONI’s strategic priorities</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-survey-ooni-strategic-priorities/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-survey-ooni-strategic-priorities/</guid><description>OONI will celebrate its 10th anniversary on 5th December 2022!
This is a time for celebration, but also a time for reflection: What worked well? What should we improve? What should we do differently going forward?
The OONI community has been at the heart of our work over the past decade, and so we invite our community to help shape OONI’s strategic priorities for the future.
Please take a few minutes to complete our survey: https://ooni.</description></item><item><title>New online OONI training course launched by Advocacy Assembly</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-ooni-training-course-advocacy-assembly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-ooni-training-course-advocacy-assembly/</guid><description>We are excited to share that a free, online OONI training course (“Measuring Internet Censorship with OONI tools”) has been launched today on Small Media’s Advocacy Assembly platform!
Through this course, you will learn how to measure internet censorship through the use of OONI tools. You will also learn how to access and interpret real-time OONI data on internet censorship around the world.
Today, the course is available in English, Arabic, Spanish, and Farsi.</description></item><item><title>Iran blocks social media, app stores and encrypted DNS amid Mahsa Amini protests</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-iran-blocks-social-media-mahsa-amini-protests/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-iran-blocks-social-media-mahsa-amini-protests/</guid><description>Protests erupted in Iran over the last week following the death of Mahsa Amini, a 22-year-old Kurdish woman who was reportedly beaten to death by Iran’s morality police for allegedly violating strict hijab rules. Amid the ongoing protests, which have reportedly resulted in at least 31 civilian deaths, Iranian authorities cracked down on the internet in an attempt to curb dissent.
Over the past week, Iran experienced severe mobile network outages, in addition to increased levels of internet censorship.</description></item><item><title>Azerbaijan and Armenia block TikTok amid border clashes</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-azerbaijan-and-armenia-blocks-tiktok/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-azerbaijan-and-armenia-blocks-tiktok/</guid><description>Earlier this week, on 12th September 2022, fighting erupted between Azerbaijani and Armenian troops along their border. Over the next few days, community members in Azerbaijan reported that the TikTok app was blocked locally.
We analyzed OONI network measurement data to investigate the block. We found that TikTok has been blocked in both Azerbaijan and Armenia over the last few days.
In this report, we share our technical findings. In both Armenia and Azerbaijan, we found TLS and DNS level interference of TikTok domains and endpoints during the border clashes.</description></item><item><title>New Test Lists Editor: Contribute websites for censorship testing</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-test-lists-editor/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-test-lists-editor/</guid><description>Today the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) team is excited to announce the public launch of our new Test Lists Editor!
This platform enables the public to review and contribute to the lists of websites (“test lists”) that are tested for censorship by OONI Probe users around the world.
Help the internet freedom community discover website blocks around the world by contributing through the new Test Lists Editor!</description></item><item><title>Measuring DoT/DoH Blocking Using OONI Probe: A Preliminary Study</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-doh-dot-paper-dnsprivacy21/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-doh-dot-paper-dnsprivacy21/</guid><description>When you enter a URL such as https://example.com/, under the hood, your web browser resolves the example.com domain to one or more IP addresses using the Domain Name System (DNS), a set of federated servers and protocols providing this name-to-IP-address mapping. For example, as of 2022-06-16, example.com resolves to the 93.184.216.34 (IPv4) and 2606:2800:220:1:248:1893:25c8:1946 (IPv6) addresses. Once it knows the IP addresses for the domain, the browser then uses them to fetch the requested webpage.</description></item><item><title>A Quick Look at QUIC Censorship</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-quick-look-quic-censorship/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-quick-look-quic-censorship/</guid><description>This blog post was originally published by the Open Technology Fund to disseminate Kathrin Elmenhorst&amp;rsquo;s QUIC-and-HTTP/3 censorship research as part of her ICFP fellowship with OONI.
Last year, the new network protocol QUIC was introduced. QUIC is a general-purpose transport layer network with the goal of reducing latency compared to existing protocols. Since the introduction of QUIC, we have seen rising volumes of QUIC-based web traffic in the form of HTTP/3.</description></item><item><title>OONI’s submission for the OHCHR report on internet shutdowns and human rights</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-ooni-submission-ohchr-report-internet-shutdowns/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-ooni-submission-ohchr-report-internet-shutdowns/</guid><description>Currently, the 50th session of the UN Human Rights Council is taking place.
In response to the UN High Commissioner for Human Rights’s call for submissions in support of the OHCHR report on internet shutdowns and human rights to the 50th session of the Human Rights Council in June 2022, the OONI team provided a submission with relevant information on the occurrence of mandated disruptions of access to social media and messaging platforms over the past 5 years based on empirical OONI network measurement data.</description></item><item><title>Job Opening: OONI Community Coordinator</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-job-opening-ooni-community-coordinator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-job-opening-ooni-community-coordinator/</guid><description>Are you passionate about defending human rights on the internet? Are you extremely organized and enjoy supporting communities around the world? We have a job opening for you!
The OONI team (a non-profit fighting internet censorship) is looking for a dedicated community coordinator to help grow and support the OONI community around the world.
The application deadline is Sunday, 12th June 2022.
Job description By joining our team, you will support our partners and global community of human rights defenders to measure and fight internet censorship.</description></item><item><title>New Launch: OONI Measurement Aggregation Toolkit (MAT)</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-ooni-mat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-ooni-mat/</guid><description>Today the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) team is thrilled to announce the public launch of the OONI Measurement Aggregation Toolkit (MAT)!
The MAT is a tool that enables you to create your own custom charts based on aggregate views of real-time OONI data collected from around the world.
Use the MAT to track internet censorship worldwide based on real-time OONI data!
About the MAT</description></item><item><title>New blocks emerge in Russia amid war in Ukraine: An OONI network measurement analysis</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-russia-blocks-amid-ru-ua-conflict/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-russia-blocks-amid-ru-ua-conflict/</guid><description>Information controls are known to occur during conflicts, and that’s exactly what we’re seeing in Russia following the recent invasion of Ukraine on 24th February 2022.
In recent days, OONI network measurement data collected from Russia shows that many Internet Service Providers (ISPs) have started blocking access to several news media websites, as well as to a website (200rf.com) that shares information about captured and killed Russian soldiers in Ukraine. OONI data also shows that Russian ISPs started throttling access to Twitter on 26th February 2022, and switched to blocking it by 4th March 2022 – at which point, they also started blocking access to Facebook.</description></item><item><title>Measuring HTTP/3 censorship with OONI Probe</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-http3-measurements-paper/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-http3-measurements-paper/</guid><description>Last year, QUIC emerged as a new internet protocol for creating reliable connections and encrypting communications between clients over the new HTTP/3 protocol. Observing the emergence and growing deployment of HTTP/3, we want to enable OONI Probe to measure HTTP/3 censorship and monitor how censors respond and adapt to technical innovation.
We therefore added HTTP/3 support (in early 2021) into OONI Probe (through our urlgetter research tool) to conduct measurements in China, Iran, India and Kazakhstan to investigate the state of HTTP/3 censorship in these countries.</description></item><item><title>Year in Review: OONI in 2021</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2021/</guid><description>In light of the ongoing global COVID-19 pandemic, 2021 continued to be a challenging year for everyone.
Yet, several exciting things happened in the censorship measurement world. In this post, we share some OONI highlights from 2021, as well as some upcoming OONI projects for 2022!
OONI Probe
Automated OONI Probe testing
New Debian package for OONI Probe
New OONI Probe Command Line Interface for Linux and macOS</description></item><item><title>iThena integration of OONI Probe boosts censorship measurement coverage worldwide</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-ithena-boosts-ooni-measurement-coverage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-ithena-boosts-ooni-measurement-coverage/</guid><description>Over the last months, the iThena project integrated OONI Probe into their platform, resulting in a major spike in OONI censorship measurement coverage around the world.
In this blog post, we’re excited to introduce you to iThena and discuss how they helped support censorship measurement worldwide.
About iThena
OONI Probe integration into iThena
About iThena iThena, developed by the Cyber-Complex Foundation, is a distributed computation and measurement project based on the Berkeley Open Infrastructure for Network Computing (BOINC) platform.</description></item><item><title>Russia started blocking Tor</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-russia-blocks-tor/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-russia-blocks-tor/</guid><description>On 1st December 2021, some Internet Service Providers (ISPs) in Russia started blocking access to the Tor anonymity network.
In this report, we share OONI network measurement data on the blocking of the Tor network and www.torproject.org in Russia.
About Tor
Methods
Findings
Blocking of the Tor network
Blocking of the Tor Project website
Conclusion
Acknowledgements</description></item><item><title>[Event Report] India, Let's Build the List</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-event-india-test-list/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-event-india-test-list/</guid><description>This is a guest post by The Bachchao Project, originally published here.
The Bachchao Project in partnership with OONI hosted an online event on 9th and 10th October 2021 to update the Citizen Lab test list for India. The event, which was called “India, Lets build the list”, was organised to help strengthen community based monitoring of internet censorship in India. The event allowed experts from different fields to contribute to a curated list of websites that are relevant to India and which are regularly tested for censorship by volunteers in India.</description></item><item><title>Why Collaboration and Transparency is Key to Internet Measurement</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-internet-measurements-collaboration-transparency/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-internet-measurements-collaboration-transparency/</guid><description>This post was originally published on the Internet Society Pulse blog.
With Internet shutdowns, disruptions and censorship events on the increase around the world, tracking where such events are happening and gathering evidence to help in the fight against them is becoming more and more important.
Tracking these events is crucial because of the impact they have on society and the economy. When social media apps are blocked, for example, freedom of speech, access to information, and movement-building is hampered.</description></item><item><title>A multi-perspective view of Internet censorship in Myanmar</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-multiperspective-view-internet-censorship-myanmar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-multiperspective-view-internet-censorship-myanmar/</guid><description>In the wake of a military coup in February 2021, Myanmar experienced unprecedented levels of internet censorship.
In response, we collaborated with CAIDA’s Internet Outage Detection and Analysis (IODA) team and Myanmar ICT for Development Organization (MIDO) on publishing a research report which documents a series of nightly internet outages and the blocking of social media, Wikipedia, and circumvention tool sites in Myanmar following the military coup.
In the months that followed, we continued to examine internet censorship in Myanmar quite closely.</description></item><item><title>Investigating Internet shutdowns through Mozilla telemetry</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-investigating-internet-shutdowns-mozilla-telemetry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-investigating-internet-shutdowns-mozilla-telemetry/</guid><description>More than 200 million users worldwide use the Firefox web browser (developed by Mozilla) every month.
If access to the Internet is shut down in a country, Mozilla should expect to see a dramatic drop in Firefox usage from that country. Given how widespread the use of Firefox is around the world, could Mozilla telemetry be a valuable resource for the Internet freedom community to investigate Internet shutdowns?
To explore this question, the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) and Internet Outage Detection and Analysis (IODA) teams joined forces to analyze a dataset of potential outage signals gathered through regular Mozilla telemetry, access to which was provided by Mozilla as part of a relevant research project to validate assumptions about the data.</description></item><item><title>How countries attempt to block Signal Private Messenger App around the world</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-how-signal-private-messenger-blocked-around-the-world/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-how-signal-private-messenger-blocked-around-the-world/</guid><description>Signal Private Messenger, commonly used by human rights defenders worldwide, is widely considered the state-of-the-art app for private and secure communications. But as its popularity surged recently, we have started to observe its blocking in several countries.
In this report, we share our analysis of OONI network measurement data on the blocking of the Signal Private Messenger app in Iran, China, Cuba, and Uzbekistan.
Currently, circumvention is enabled by default for Signal users in Iran, Egypt, Oman, Qatar, and the UAE.</description></item><item><title>Job Opening: Mobile Developer for OONI Probe</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-job-opening-ooni-mobile-developer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-job-opening-ooni-mobile-developer/</guid><description>Are you a mobile developer interested in defending human rights on the internet? We have a job opening for you!
The OONI team (a non-profit fighting internet censorship, originally born out of the Tor Project) is looking for a dedicated mobile developer to work on OONI Probe: a free software app designed to measure internet censorship and network performance.
The application deadline is Sunday, 31st October 2021.
Job description If you join our team, you will lead the development of the OONI Probe mobile app, supporting human rights defenders worldwide to investigate and fight internet censorship.</description></item><item><title>Italy blocks Gutenberg book publishing website</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-italy-blocks-gutenberg-book-publishing-website/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-italy-blocks-gutenberg-book-publishing-website/</guid><description>Cases of internet censorship (that affect public interest) are rarely reported in Europe. Yet, www.gutenberg.org, a book-publishing website run by a non-profit organization, has been blocked in Italy since May 2020.
In this report, we share OONI network measurement data on the ongoing blocking of www.gutenberg.org across networks in Italy.
Background
Methods
Findings
Blocking methods by ISP
Vodafone Italia (AS30722)</description></item><item><title>No Access: LGBTIQ Website Censorship in Six Countries</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-no-access-lgbtiq-website-censorship-six-countries/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-no-access-lgbtiq-website-censorship-six-countries/</guid><description>Today, in collaboration with OutRight Action International and the Citizen Lab, we are excited to share our new research report, “No Access: LGBTIQ Website Censorship in Six Countries”, which examines the blocking of LGBTIQ websites in Indonesia, Malaysia, Iran, Russia, Saudi Arabia, and the United Arab Emirates (UAE).
READ FULL REPORT
Annotated Bibliography
Below we share some of our key research findings.
Summary of findings We joined forces with OutRight Action International and the Citizen Lab to examine the blocking of LGBTIQ websites in six countries: Indonesia, Malaysia, Iran, Russia, Saudi Arabia, and the United Arab Emirates (UAE).</description></item><item><title>A brief introduction to OONI</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/brief-introduction-to-ooni/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/brief-introduction-to-ooni/</guid><description>This is gentle introduction to OONI that does not require readers to have a technical background.
If you are familiar with how the Internet works and how it can be censored you can skip The basics.
For frequently asked questions and answers, please refer to the OONI FAQ.
The basics You might be connecting to the Internet from a local network or using an Internet Service Provider (ISP).
ISPs are usually not connected to each other.</description></item><item><title>Mining OONI data</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/mining-ooni-data/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/mining-ooni-data/</guid><description>OONI receives measurement data from OONI Probes around the world and processes it in real-time to detect censorship.
There are different ways to access the output of the processing: OONI Explorer, the OONI API and dumps of the PostgreSQL database.
OONI Explorer provides a user-friendly web interface to all visitors.
The OONI API is meant for developers and researches and allows searching for measurement metadata, fetching single measurements, and generating statistics.</description></item><item><title>Zambia: Social media blocked amid 2021 general elections</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-zambia-social-media-blocks-amid-elections/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-zambia-social-media-blocks-amid-elections/</guid><description>Recently, on 12th August 2021, general elections were held in Zambia, during which access to popular online social media platforms was reportedly blocked.
In this report, we share relevant OONI data on the blocking of WhatsApp, Twitter, and Facebook amid Zambia’s 2021 general election.
Background
Methods
Findings
Blocking of WhatsApp
Blocking of Twitter and Facebook
Conclusion</description></item><item><title>OONI Partner Training 2021</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-partner-training-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-partner-training-2021/</guid><description>Image: 1st OONI Partner Training, 28th-30th June 2021
Image: 2nd OONI Partner Training, 5th-7th July 2021
Over the last week, we had the pleasure to host two 3-day OONI Partner Training events for our partners in Africa, Latin America, the Middle East, and Asia. As part of these events, our goal was to share OONI-specific knowledge and skills, and to collect feedback to better serve community needs.</description></item><item><title>Media censorship in Azerbaijan through the lens of network measurement</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-azerbaijan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-azerbaijan/</guid><description>Key Findings Introduction Methods OONI network measurement Acknowledgement of limitations Background Network landscape and internet penetration Legal environment Internet censorship and media freedom environment Findings Blocked news media websites Blocking of social media amid 2020 Nagorno-Karabakh war Blocking of social media websites Blocking of instant messaging apps WhatsApp Telegram Blocked circumvention tool sites Tor and Psiphon Conclusion Acknowledgements Key Findings As part of our analysis of OONI measurements collected from Azerbaijan between January 2020 to May 2021, we found:</description></item><item><title>Making the OONI Probe Android app more resilient</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/making-ooni-probe-android-more-resilient/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/making-ooni-probe-android-more-resilient/</guid><description>We recently made OONI Probe Android more robust against accidental or deliberate blocking of our backend services. Specifically, we implemented support for specifying a proxy that speaks with OONI’s backend services. We also improved the build process to influence the TLS Client Hello fingerprint, which helps with avoiding accidental blocking.
Adding support for a proxy
Changing our Android TLS fingerprint
Future improvements
Adding support for a proxy Since late 2020, community members have been reporting specific OONI Probe Android failures.</description></item><item><title>Myanmar: Data on internet blocks and internet outages following military coup</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-myanmar-internet-blocks-and-outages/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-myanmar-internet-blocks-and-outages/</guid><description>On 1st February 2021, the military in Myanmar carried out a coup d’etat, seizing power and detaining the country’s State Counsellor (equivalent to a prime minister) and other democratically elected leaders.
A few days after the coup, ISPs in Myanmar started blocking access to Facebook services. On 5th February 2021, they started blocking access to Twitter and Instagram as well. On 6th February 2021, access to the internet was shut down entirely for nearly 30 hours.</description></item><item><title>Uganda: Data on internet blocks and nationwide internet outage amid 2021 general election</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-uganda-general-election-blocks-and-outage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-uganda-general-election-blocks-and-outage/</guid><description>Last week, amid its 2021 general election, Uganda was disconnected from the internet entirely. The country experienced a widespread internet blackout that lasted 4 days, starting on the eve of the election (13th January 2021) and ending in the morning of 18th January 2021. In the days leading up to the election, access to major social media platforms and circumvention tools was blocked &amp;ndash; even when the OTT (Over the Top) tax (commonly referred to as the “Social Media Tax”) was paid.</description></item><item><title>Year in Review: OONI in 2020</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2020/</guid><description>In light of the global COVID-19 pandemic, 2020 has been a challenging year for everyone.
Yet, several exciting things happened in the censorship measurement world. In this post, we share some OONI highlights from 2020, as well as some upcoming OONI projects for 2021!
OONI Probe
New OONI Probe Desktop App for Windows and macOS
New OONI Probe measurement engine
OONI Run usability study</description></item><item><title>Investigating Encrypted DNS Blocking in India</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-encrypted-dns-blocking-india/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-encrypted-dns-blocking-india/</guid><description>In October 2020, we collaborated with Divyank Katira and Gurshabad Grover, researchers at the Centre for Internet &amp;amp; Society, India, to implement and evaluate a new OONI experiment focused on detecting DNS censorship.
This new OONI experiment, called dnscheck, focuses on detecting the blocking of encrypted DNS transports such as DNS over TLS and DNS over HTTPS. Its methodology improves upon the measurement methodology OONI previously used to measure DoT blocking in Iran.</description></item><item><title>Tanzania blocks social media (and Tor?) on election day</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-tanzania-blocks-social-media-tor-election-day/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-tanzania-blocks-social-media-tor-election-day/</guid><description>Starting from yesterday (27th October 2020) &amp;ndash; on the eve of Tanzania&amp;rsquo;s 2020 general election &amp;ndash; OONI measurements continue to show the ongoing blocking of social media (and of the Tor circumvention tool) in Tanzania.
In this report, we share OONI data collected from Tanzania on these blocks, as well as relevant instructions for further OONI Probe testing.
Methods
Blocking of social media</description></item><item><title>OONI Probe ASN Incident Report</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-ooni-probe-asn-incident-report/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-ooni-probe-asn-incident-report/</guid><description>Last week we noticed that some OONI measurements were available on OONI Explorer under a report ID containing a valid Autonomous System Number (ASN), even though the raw JSON data contained zero as the ASN (i.e. encoded as AS0). We initially thought that this was caused by a bug in our API code, but it actually turned out to be an OONI Probe bug in our probe engine (which powers the OONI Probe apps).</description></item><item><title>Belarus protests: From internet outages to pervasive website censorship</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-belarus-internet-outages-website-censorship/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-belarus-internet-outages-website-censorship/</guid><description>Image: Block page served in Belarus.
This report was prepared in collaboration with Human Constanta and the Digital Observers Community Belarus.
More than 70 websites have been blocked in Belarus over the last weeks, following a controversial presidential election and amid ongoing anti-government protests. Many of the blocked sites include news media and are related to the elections, while several other sites expressing political criticism were blocked as well.</description></item><item><title>Internet Measurement Village 2020: Slides &amp; Video Recordings</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-imv-slides-recordings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-imv-slides-recordings/</guid><description>Over the last month, between 10th June 2020 to 3rd July 2020, we organized and hosted the Internet Measurement Village (IMV) 2020, an online community event aimed at sharing skills, knowledge, and resources on internet measurement, in defense of a free and open internet.
As all the IMV sessions were live-streamed and will continue to live on the OONI YouTube channel, we hope that these recordings will serve as a valuable resource on internet measurement for the internet freedom community.</description></item><item><title>Support the OTF: Support a Free and Open Internet</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-support-otf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-support-otf/</guid><description>Over the last month, the Open Technology Fund (OTF) &amp;ndash; one of the main funders of free censorship circumvention and privacy-enhancing technologies that human rights defenders worldwide rely on &amp;ndash; has been under threat, following the ousting of its leadership.
We previously published a statement in support of the OTF, explaining why we think the OTF is essential for internet freedom and encouraging the public to sign the letter to congress.</description></item><item><title>Measurement observations on network performance during the COVID-19 pandemic in Northern Italy</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-network-performance-covid19-italy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-network-performance-covid19-italy/</guid><description>We were recently invited to participate in a NetGain Partnership webinar (titled “Surging Demand and The Global Internet Infrastructure”) to discuss the changing landscape for internet infrastructure and technology in the wake of the COVID-19 pandemic.
As part of our preparation for this webinar, we looked at network performance measurements collected from northern Italy over the last months (i.e. when Italy was hit hard by the COVID-19 pandemic) in an attempt to understand whether and to what extent there was a correlation between increased internet use and reduced network performance.</description></item><item><title>Investigating TLS blocking in India</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-tls-blocking-india/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-tls-blocking-india/</guid><description>This report investigates Transport Layer Security (TLS)-based blocking in India. Previous research by the Centre for Internet &amp;amp; Society, India (CIS) has already exposed TLS blocking based on the value of the SNI field. OONI has also implemented and started testing SNI-based TLS blocking measurements.
Recently, the Magma Project documented cases where CIS India and OONI&amp;rsquo;s methodologies could be improved. They specifically found that blocking sometimes appears to depend not only on the value of the SNI field but also on the address of the web server being used.</description></item><item><title>Azərbaycan: OONI Probe Test üçün çağırış</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-azerbaijan-ooni-probe-testing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-azerbaijan-ooni-probe-testing/</guid><description>This is a guest post by Arzu Geybullayeva (Azerbaijan Internet Watch), originally published here.
Azerbaijan Internet Watch Azərbaycanda internet senzurasını izləyir və bu çərçəvədə aşkar etdiyi pozuntuları öz səhifəsində sənədləşdirir. Bu barədə daha ətraflı məlumatı buradan əldə edə bilərsiniz.
Layihənin bir vacib cəhətlərindən biri də ölkədə bloklanan veb səhifələri izləmək ve bu bloklamaların necə baş verdiyini araşdırmaqdır. Bu barədə isə daha ətraflı buradan və buradan məlumat əldə edə bilərsiniz.</description></item><item><title>DNS over TLS blocked in Iran</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-iran-dot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-iran-dot/</guid><description>DNS over TLS (DoT) is a network protocol that allows one to use DNS over TLS (i.e. with encryption and authentication of the remote DNS server).
We investigated whether DoT works in Iran by gathering a list of 31 well-known DoT endpoints and running experiments from four distinct Iranian mobile and fixed-line Internet Service Providers (ISPs): MCI, TCI, Irancell, and Shatel.
We discovered that:
57% of the endpoints are blocked on a least one ISP;</description></item><item><title>Save Internet Freedom: Support the Open Technology Fund</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-06-19-save-internet-freedom-support-the-open-technology-fund/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 16:48:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-06-19-save-internet-freedom-support-the-open-technology-fund/</guid><description>Last Wednesday was dubbed as a “Wednesday night massacre”, following the firing of the directors of four organizations overseen by the US Agency for Global Media (USAGM): Radio Free Asia, Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty, Middle East Broadcasting, and the Open Technology Fund (OTF).
Out of these four organizations, we would like to draw your attention to the OTF, not only because they have been a long-term funder of our project but, more importantly, because they have been essential in creating the internet freedom community as we know it.</description></item><item><title>Those Unspoken Thoughts: A study of censorship and media freedom in Manipur, India</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-those-unspoken-thoughts-otf-fellow-report/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-those-unspoken-thoughts-otf-fellow-report/</guid><description>This research report was produced by OTF Information Controls Fellow, Chinmayi S K. OONI served as her host organization throughout her fellowship.
Read full report The northeastern Indian state of Manipur has long been an area of conflict and crackdowns. But although human rights violations are well documented in the state, few studies have examined the impact of censorship and internet shutdowns in the region. In 2019, research fellow Chinmayi S K sought to address this critical gap by documenting the blocking of websites in Manipur and assessing how the use of information controls in the state compares to that in the rest of India.</description></item><item><title>OONI Run Usability Study: Findings</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-06-09-ooni-run-usability-study-findings/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 09:38:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-06-09-ooni-run-usability-study-findings/</guid><description>OONI Run is a platform (launched in September 2017) that you can use to generate mobile deep links and widget code to coordinate OONI Probe testing. To enable community members to more effectively useOONI Run, we researched its limitations and collected structured community feedback through an OONI Run usability study.
This report outlines the objectives, personas, assumptions, and methods of this study.
We also share the outcomes based on the analysis of information collected through our survey and interviews with community members, as well as some of the next steps towards improving OONI Run.</description></item><item><title>Join the online Internet Measurement Village 2020</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-internet-measurement-village/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-internet-measurement-village/</guid><description>Subscribe on YouTube We are excited to bring the first online Internet Measurement Village to you this month.
Interested in learning all about Internet measurement and how to detect Internet censorship? Curious to explore open datasets on Internet censorship and Internet outages? Eager to learn how advocates are pushing back against Internet shutdowns and defending a free and open Internet?
Join us for the online Internet Measurement Village, starting on Wednesday, 10th June 2020 and ending on Friday, 3rd July 2020.</description></item><item><title>Evaluating OONI’s New Measurement Engine in the Context of the Blocking of Women on Web in Spain</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-engine-evaluation-spain/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-engine-evaluation-spain/</guid><description>Reproduction rights site www.womenonweb.org has been blocked in Spain over the last months by several local Internet Service Providers (ISPs). Once Spanish hacktivist communities noticed that www.womenonweb.org was inaccessible, they coordinated on running OONI Probe tests to collect measurement data that could serve as evidence. The findings of this investigation have been published in an excellent report, whose writing was coordinated by our former colleague, Vasilis Ververis.
We were involved in the technical review of the report.</description></item><item><title>Burundi blocks social media amid 2020 general election</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-burundi-blocks-social-media-amid-election/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-burundi-blocks-social-media-amid-election/</guid><description>Yesterday, access to social media was reportedly blocked in Burundi amid its 2020 general election.
The lead-up to the election was marred by violence and unrest, as seven candidates vied to replace Incumbent President Nkurunziza, who has been in power over the last 15 years. Despite widespread deadly protests and a coup attempt, President Nkurunziza won a third term in 2015 following disputed elections. While President Nkurunziza reportedly announced that he would not contest the next elections, he is set to become a “supreme guide to patriotism” as he steps down now in 2020.</description></item><item><title>Myanmar blocks “fake news” websites amid COVID-19 pandemic</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-myanmar-blocks-websites-amid-covid19/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-myanmar-blocks-websites-amid-covid19/</guid><description>In March 2020, Internet Service Providers (ISPs) in Myanmar received a directive from the Ministry of Transport and Communications to block 230 websites, most of which contain adult content. However, 67 of these sites were blocked on the grounds of spreading “fake news”. The list of these 230 websites has not been published.
In an attempt to potentially identify the newly blocked websites, we analyzed OONI network measurements collected from Myanmar over the last months, between 1st January 2020 to 9th April 2020.</description></item><item><title>Measuring SNI based blocking in Iran</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-iran-sni-blocking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-iran-sni-blocking/</guid><description>In this blog post we start evaluating OONI&amp;rsquo;s new SNI blocking experiment. To this end, we will use measurements performed in Iran, where the blocking technique measured by this experiment is deployed.
OONI&amp;rsquo;s SNI blocking experiment discovers cases where a Client Hello packet carrying a specific SNI triggers blocking. In this context, SNI means Server Name Indication. It is an extension to the Transport Layer Security (TLS) protocol that allows a client to specify the domain name that it wants an HTTP server to serve.</description></item><item><title>OONI Run Survey &amp; Interviews: Share your feedback</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-ooni-run-survey-and-interviews/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-ooni-run-survey-and-interviews/</guid><description>OONI Run is a platform that you can use to generate mobile deep links and widget code to coordinate OONI Probe testing.
Researchers and human rights defenders around the world have used OONI Run to coordinate OONI Probe censorship measurement campaigns, particularly leading up to and during political events (such as elections and protests).
We’re excited to hear more about your experience with OONI Run so that we can improve it.</description></item><item><title>Launched: New OONI Probe Desktop App for Windows and macOS</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-ooni-probe-desktop-app/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-ooni-probe-desktop-app/</guid><description>Today, OONI is thrilled to announce the public launch of the new OONI Probe desktop app that you can download and install on Windows and macOS to measure internet censorship and network performance.
Install OONI Probe Desktop app By running the tests in the new OONI Probe desktop app, you can measure:
Blocking of websites;
Blocking of WhatsApp, Facebook Messenger, and Telegram;</description></item><item><title>Building a smart URL list system: Policy for URL prioritization</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-smart-url-list-system/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-smart-url-list-system/</guid><description>To improve the monitoring of website censorship around the world, OONI aims to create a smart URL list system, while ensuring, to the extent possible, the safety of the URL lists themselves by running them through the usual Citizen Lab URL review process. This will help ensure smarter test target selection and by extension, it will enable us &amp;ndash; and the broader internet freedom community &amp;ndash; to more effectively monitor, analyze, and respond to cases of website censorship around the world.</description></item><item><title>Let's measure the accessibility of COVID-19 websites around the world</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/covid-19-ooni-measurement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/covid-19-ooni-measurement/</guid><description>Ensuring a free and open internet during an emergency, like the current COVID-19 pandemic, is more important than ever. However, access to information related to the coronavirus pandemic has already been censored by certain governments. China censored information on the coronavirus on Chinese social media platforms, while Venezuela’s state-owned CANTV blocked access to a coronavirus information portal last week.
We therefore invite you to participate in a measurement campaign to check if COVID-19 sites are accessible in your country (and on the network you’re using) and to share relevant measurement data with the world.</description></item><item><title>Year in Review: OONI in 2019</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2019/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2019/</guid><description>As the new decade begins, we publish this post to share some OONI highlights from 2019. We also share some thoughts for 2020.
New Apps
Revamped OONI Probe Mobile App
New OONI Probe Desktop App
Near real-time publication of OONI measurements
Revamped OONI Explorer
OONI PostgreSQL MetaDB
Improved measurements
New OONI Probe tests</description></item><item><title>Iran temporarily blocks the Farsi language edition of Wikipedia</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-iran-blocks-farsi-wikipedia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-iran-blocks-farsi-wikipedia/</guid><description>Over the last days, between 2nd to 3rd March 2020, OONI measurements collected from 6 different networks in Iran showed that access to the Farsi edition of Wikipedia (fa.wikipedia.org) was temporarily blocked by means of DNS tampering and SNI filtering.
In this post, we share relevant OONI data.
Blocking of Farsi Wikipedia and Wikinews In the past, Iran mainly blocked the HTTP version of specific Wikipedia articles. But over the last years, this probably wasn’t very noticeable because Wikipedia used HTTPS with HSTS enabled, meaning that Iranian internet users could easily access the censored pages.</description></item><item><title>OONI Highlights: 2017-2019</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-highlights-2017-2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-highlights-2017-2019/</guid><description>This post was originally published on the OTF website.
Back in 2012, the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) was born with OTF support to create the first open methodologies that would enable anyone around the world to measure internet censorship and other forms of network interference.
Today, OONI comprises a global community that runs its censorship measurement software (OONI Probe) in more than 200 countries every month. Millions of measurements have been collected from tens of thousands of networks in 236 countries since 2012, all of which are openly published on OONI Explorer &amp;ndash; arguably the largest publicly available resource on internet censorship to date.</description></item><item><title>Togo: Instant messaging apps blocked amid 2020 presidential election</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-togo-blocks-instant-messaging-apps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-togo-blocks-instant-messaging-apps/</guid><description>Last Saturday, on 22nd February 2020, presidential elections were held in Togo. These elections follow a wave of protests over the last years against the 53-year rule of Gnassingbe Eyadema and, subsequently, his son, Faure Gnassingbe. A few days before the election, non-partisan election monitoring was restricted as National Democratic Institute (NDI) staff were expelled from the country. According to preliminary results from the electoral commission, incumbent President Faure Gnassingbe won re-election.</description></item><item><title>Call to Action: Let’s measure the blocking of LGBTQI websites around the world!</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-measure-blocking-lgbtqi-sites/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-measure-blocking-lgbtqi-sites/</guid><description>LGBTQI websites are blocked in several countries around the world, such as Malaysia and Indonesia. This includes popular dating apps and sites, like grindr, which is blocked in Lebanon and Iran.
How can we track the blocking of LGBTQI sites around the world?
We have teamed up with OutRight Action International &amp;ndash; a leading international LGBTQI human rights organization &amp;ndash; to investigate the blocking of LGBTQI sites worldwide.
We invite you to contribute to this research!</description></item><item><title>Iran’s nation-wide Internet blackout: Measurement data and technical observations</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-iran-internet-blackout/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-iran-internet-blackout/</guid><description>Over the last week, Iran experienced a nation-wide Internet blackout.
Most Iranians were barred from connecting to the global Internet and the outside world, but they had access to Iran’s national Intranet: the domestic network that hosts Iranian websites and services—all under the government’s watch.
This major Internet blackout was rolled out on 16th November 2019, right after protests erupted across multiple cities in Iran. The protests (against economic mismanagement and government corruption) were sparked by the government’s abrupt announcement to increase the price of fuel (as much as 300%) and to impose a strict rationing system.</description></item><item><title>On the blocking of abortion rights websites: Women on Waves &amp; Women on Web</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-blocking-abortion-rights-websites-women-on-waves-web/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-blocking-abortion-rights-websites-women-on-waves-web/</guid><description>Image: By Clarote (Coding Rights)
Read the Portuguese version by Coding Rights.
View the report&amp;rsquo;s press coverage by The Intercept.
As abortion remains partially or totally criminalized in numerous countries, the fight to promote sexual and reproductive rights, as well as women&amp;rsquo;s health, also relies on access to information. But recently, we were told that the website of the abortion rights non-governmental organization womeonwaves.org, which provides reproductive health services and education to women in countries with restrictive abortion laws, was inaccessible in Brazil.</description></item><item><title>Egypt blocks BBC and Alhurra: Expanding media censorship amid political unrest</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-egypt-blocks-bbc-and-alhurra/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-egypt-blocks-bbc-and-alhurra/</guid><description>Last weekend, protests erupted in Egypt in response to corruption allegations against President Abdul Fattah al-Sisi’s government.
Protests have been rare since President Sisi took power in 2014, but amid policies of economic austerity and recent corruption allegations, hundreds of Egyptians took to the streets. It was subsequently reported that BBC News and the US-funded Alhurra news website were amongst blocked services. The head of Egypt’s Supreme Council for Media Regulation reportedly stated that the BBC and other news websites may have been blocked because of their “inaccurate” coverage of the protests.</description></item><item><title>Next Generation OONI Explorer Launched!</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/next-generation-ooni-explorer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/next-generation-ooni-explorer/</guid><description>Today the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) team is thrilled to announce the public launch of the revamped, next generation OONI Explorer!
OONI Explorer is an open data resource on internet censorship around the world. This new platform offers access to millions of censorship measurements collected from 233 countries since 2012.
About OONI Explorer
Why use OONI Explorer?
Who is OONI Explorer for?</description></item><item><title>Resurgence of Internet Censorship in Ethiopia: Blocking of WhatsApp, Facebook, and African Arguments</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/resurgence-internet-censorship-ethiopia-2019/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/resurgence-internet-censorship-ethiopia-2019/</guid><description>Last year in June 2018, following years of pervasive internet censorship, Ethiopia unblocked hundreds of websites as part of political reforms under a new government. But merely a year later, we observe a resurgence of internet censorship in the country.
In mid-June 2019, Ethiopia experienced several internet blackouts and once internet access was restored, access to WhatsApp and Telegram was blocked. These events coincided with Ethiopia’s national high school exams and it is believed that internet access was restricted in an attempt to prevent exam leakage as has happened in the past.</description></item><item><title>Ethiopia: From internet blackouts to the blocking of WhatsApp and Telegram</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-whatsapp-telegram/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-whatsapp-telegram/</guid><description>Communication access in Ethiopia has significantly been disrupted over the last week. Internet access and Short Message Services (SMS) were disconnected intermittently across the country. During the first half of the week, internet connectivity was shut down completely. After access was restored, both WhatsApp and Telegram were blocked. A few days ago, Ethio Telecom (the only telecom in the country) published a notice, acknowledging the internet disruptions, but came short on details about the extent of communication disruptions or why they occurred in the first place.</description></item><item><title>Jordan: Measuring Facebook live-streaming interference during protests</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/jordan-measuring-facebook-interference/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/jordan-measuring-facebook-interference/</guid><description>Last December, anti-austerity protests erupted in Jordan against a controversial fiscal reform bill. The protests ensued once a week for several weeks thereafter. Amid the protests, locals reported that they were unable to view live-streaming from Facebook. But they also reported that viewing live-streaming was otherwise possible when protests were not taking place.
Therefore, our first hypothesis was that perhaps people in Jordan couldn’t load videos on Facebook because they were using overloaded networks (rather than Facebook live streaming being interfered with).</description></item><item><title>Nigeria’s 2019 elections through the lens of network measurements</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-nigeria-internet-censorship/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-nigeria-internet-censorship/</guid><description>Censorship events are increasingly being reported during political events in Africa (and elsewhere around the world). A few examples include the social media disruptions in Mali amid its 2018 presidential election, the blocking of social media in Uganda during its 2016 general elections, and the complete internet blackout in The Gambia during its 2016 presidential election.
Leading up to and during Nigeria’s 2019 general elections, we collaborated with our local partner, Paradigm Initiative, on measuring networks in the country to monitor potential censorship events.</description></item><item><title>China is now blocking all language editions of Wikipedia</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-china-wikipedia-blocking/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-china-wikipedia-blocking/</guid><description>translation: 中国封锁了所有语言版本的维基百科
China recently started blocking all language editions of Wikipedia. Previously, the blocking was limited to the Chinese language edition of Wikipedia (zh.wikipedia.org), but has now expanded to include all *.wikipedia.org language editions.
In this post, we share OONI network measurement data on the blocking of Wikipedia in China. We found that all wikipedia.org sub-domains are blocked in China by means of DNS injection and SNI filtering.
DNS injection Through the use of OONI Probe, Wikipedia domains have been tested from multiple local vantage points in China since 2015.</description></item><item><title>Benin: Social media blocking and Internet blackout amid 2019 elections</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-benin-social-media-blocking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2019-benin-social-media-blocking/</guid><description>Two days ago, social media was reportedly blocked and access to the Internet was shutdown in Benin during its 2019 parliamentary elections.
In this report, the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) and the Center for Applied Internet Data Analysis (CAIDA) teams share OONI, IODA, and RIPE Atlas network measurement data that corroborate and provide insight into these recent censorship events in Benin.
Background
Social media blocking</description></item><item><title>Cuba blocks independent media amid 2019 constitutional referendum</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/cuba-referendum/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/cuba-referendum/</guid><description>On 24th February 2019, Cubans voted on a new constitution for the first time in decades.
But a few hours before the referendum, independent news outlet Tremenda Nota reported that their website got blocked in Cuba.
In this post, we share OONI network measurement data that confirms the blocking of tremendanota.com, as well as the blocking of several other independent media websites during the referendum.
We also found that ETECSA, Cuba’s only telecommunications company, has changed its censorship techniques, now censoring access to sites that support HTTPS by means of IP blocking.</description></item><item><title>OONI Software Development Guidelines</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-software-development-guidelines/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-software-development-guidelines/</guid><description>The goal of this document is to explain and explicit some of the best practices relevant to software development that we follow at the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI).
By following these development guidelines we aim to produce higher quality code, which contains less defects and allows us to iterate more quickly delivering greater value to our end users is a shorter amount of time!
Version control Also known as: “How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Love the Git!</description></item><item><title>OONI Probe Android 2.0.0 Incident Report</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-probe-android-200-incident/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-probe-android-200-incident/</guid><description>The first public release of OONI Probe Android 2.0.0 (since 2.0.0-alpha.7) included a very serious bug: we lost measurements and collected measurements that we shouldn’t have. As soon as the problem was identified, we quickly released a fix (OONI Probe Android 2.0.1). All measurements that should not have been uploaded have been deleted and we are working on a new OONI Probe release (OONI Probe Mobile 2.1.0) that will allow you to manually re-upload measurements.</description></item><item><title>From the blocking of Wikipedia to Social Media: Venezuela's Political Crisis</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/venezuela-blocking-wikipedia-and-social-media-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/venezuela-blocking-wikipedia-and-social-media-2019/</guid><description>As political tension escalated in Venezuela over the last few weeks, so did internet censorship.
It started off with edits to Wikipedia pages earlier this month, referencing the opposition leader, Juan Guaidó, as the President of Venezuela. This resulted in the blocking of Wikipedia. Then a group of Venezuelan soldiers circulated videos, announcing an uprising against the government of President Maduro and calling on the public to join them in the streets.</description></item><item><title>Zimbabwe protests: Social media blocking and internet blackouts</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/zimbabwe-protests-social-media-blocking-2019/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/zimbabwe-protests-social-media-blocking-2019/</guid><description>Last week, protests erupted in Zimbabwe in response to the government’s announcement that the price of fuel would more than double. According to Zimbabwe’s government, the price hikes aim to avert fuel shortages and to crackdown on the illegal trading of fuel. The new prices, however, mean that Zimbabwe now has the most expensive fuel in the world.
Zimbabwe’s fuel protests lasted for three days (14th to 17th January 2019), during which 12 people were reportedly killed and many more beaten by security forces.</description></item><item><title>Year in Review: OONI in 2018</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2018/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2018/</guid><description>As the new year begins, we publish this post to share some OONI highlights from 2018. We also share some of the exciting new projects we’ll be launching in 2019!
New partnerships
Research publications
Dev work behind the scenes
Revamped OONI Probe mobile app
Revamped OONI Explorer
New OONI Probe desktop apps
Probe Orchestration
OONI workshops and presentations</description></item><item><title>Major Revamp: OONI Probe Mobile App 2.0 Launched!</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/revamped-ooni-probe-mobile-app/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/revamped-ooni-probe-mobile-app/</guid><description>Today the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) project is thrilled to announce the release of a major, new OONI Probe mobile app version!
Are websites and social media apps blocked? Is your network unusually slow?
Install OONI Probe now on Android or iOS to find out!
Why run OONI Probe?
OONI Probe 2.0 Highlights
Major UI overhaul
Overview of Test Results</description></item><item><title>Internet disruption in Gabon amid coup attempt</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/gabon-internet-disruption/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/gabon-internet-disruption/</guid><description>On 7th January 2019, a military coup was attempted in Gabon in a bid to end more than 50 years of rule by President Ali Bongo’s family. The coup attempt was quickly foiled. Security forces reportedly killed two suspects, arrested seven others, and Gabon’s government retained control.
Meanwhile, a curfew has been imposed and NetBlocks reported that access to the Internet has been shut down.
In this post, we share data that provides signals of network disruptions in Gabon.</description></item><item><title>Uganda's Social Media Tax through the lens of network measurements</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/uganda-social-media-tax/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/uganda-social-media-tax/</guid><description>Image by @neemascribbles.
Probed ISPs: MTN (AS20294), Africell (AS36991), Airtel (AS37075), Smile Telecom (AS37122), Africa Online Uganda (AS29039), DATANET (AS29032), Sombha Solutions (AS328015), Roke (AS37063), Airtel (AS36977), Uganda Telecom (AS21491)
OONI tests: Web Connectivity, HTTP Invalid Request Line, HTTP Header Field Manipulation, WhatsApp, Facebook Messenger, Telegram, Vanilla Tor. Testing/analysis period: 1st July 2018 to 24th October 2018
Censorship methods: HTTP blocking (resetting connections) and TCP/IP blocking
Key Findings</description></item><item><title>The State of Internet Censorship in Venezuela</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/venezuela-internet-censorship/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/venezuela-internet-censorship/</guid><description>A study by IPYS Venezuela, Venezuela Inteligente, and the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI).
Update (2018-10-19): The section on Tor becoming accessible was added.
Key Findings
Introduction
Background
Political environment
Legal environment
Reported cases of internet censorship
Methodology: Measuring internet censorship in Venezuela
Acknowledgement of limitations Findings
Blocked websites</description></item><item><title>South Sudan: Measuring Internet Censorship in the World's Youngest Nation</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/south-sudan-censorship/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/south-sudan-censorship/</guid><description>Image by Mandavi
Established in July 2011, South Sudan is the youngest country in the world. But the transition to independence from Sudan has been far from smooth, as the country experiences an ongoing civil war. Even though internet penetration levels remain quite low, two media websites and two independent blogs were reportedly blocked last year.
This report is a joint research effort by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) and South Sudan’s The Advocates for Human Rights and Democracy (TAHURID).</description></item><item><title>Mali: Social media disruptions amid 2018 presidential election?</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/mali-disruptions-amid-2018-election/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/mali-disruptions-amid-2018-election/</guid><description>Two days ago, on 29th July 2018, Malians went to the polls to vote in presidential elections and reported that social media was inaccessible.
This is not the first time that social media is reportedly blocked in Mali. Facebook and Twitter were blocked two years ago amidst violent protests against the detention of a popular radio host. Last month, Internet Sans Frontieres reported that social media was disrupted in Mali, following a violent police crackdown on banned opposition protests calling for transparency and accountability in the 2018 presidential elections.</description></item><item><title>Do you use OONI Probe? We want your feedback!</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooniprobe-ux-survey-and-interviews/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooniprobe-ux-survey-and-interviews/</guid><description>Survey (self-hosted mirror)
Since last year’s launch of the OONI Probe mobile apps, tens of thousands of people have been measuring internet censorship in around 200 countries every month. But OONI Probe is far from perfect.
We’re excited to hear more about your experience with the apps so that we can improve them.
We invite you to complete our survey and/or participate in an interview to provide feedback.
Survey We’d love to hear your thoughts on the current OONI Probe mobile apps.</description></item><item><title>The State of Internet Censorship in Egypt</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/egypt-internet-censorship/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/egypt-internet-censorship/</guid><description>The report uncovers anomalies on Egyptian networks, including censorship and the hijacking of unencrypted HTTP connections for advertising and cryptocurrency mining.
Read full report in English Read full report in Arabic Read the summary of the report in Arabic
Last year, Egypt ordered the blocking of 21 news websites. OONI, a censorship measurement project under the Tor Project, responded by publishing a report on the blocking of (at least) 10 media websites, including Mada Masr and Al Jazeera.</description></item><item><title>Ethiopia: Verifying the unblocking of websites</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-unblocking/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 19:49:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-unblocking/</guid><description>Pro PM Abiy Ahmed Rally at Meskel Square, June 2018 - Photo by Berhan Taye
On 22nd June 2018, the Ethiopian government reportedthat it had unblocked 264 websites. This (great) news was also reported by ESAT, a major Ethiopian media website that was blockedover the last years.
Today, OONIand Access Nowpublish new research based on the testing of sites that were previously found to be blocked, in an attempt to examine whether they have in fact been unblocked in recent days.</description></item><item><title>Nigeria: Measuring Internet Censorship</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/nigeria-internet-censorship/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/nigeria-internet-censorship/</guid><description>Last October, Nigeria’s National Communications Commission (NCC) reportedly ordered the blocking of 21 websites. In response, we collaborated with Nigeria’s Paradigm Initiative to test those websites and collect network measurement data that can shed light on whether and how they’re blocked.
Our findings are included in a joint research report that we published today with Paradigm Initiative. The full report, titled “Tightening the Noose on Freedom of Expression: Status of Internet Freedom in Nigeria 2018”, can be downloaded here.</description></item><item><title>OONI Community Interviews: Julie Owono</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-community-interviews-julie-owono/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-community-interviews-julie-owono/</guid><description>If you’ve met Julie Owono, you’ll probably agree that her passion and determination for defending digital rights is one of the things that stands out about her.
In her capacity as the Executive Director of Internet Sans Frontières (Internet Without Borders), Julie has spearheaded advocacy efforts in defense of online freedoms in many West African countries. Notably, Julie led campaigns against internet shutdowns in Cameroon, as well as in Togo and Chad.</description></item><item><title>OONI at RightsCon 2018</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-rightscon-2018/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-rightscon-2018/</guid><description>We are excited to participate at RightsCon next week: the world’s leading event on human rights in the digital age. Annually hosted by Access Now, this three-day conference will take place in Toronto between 16th-18th May 2018.
Over the last years, RightsCon has provided us the opportunity to participate in critical discussions in the digital rights field, meet many fascinating people and organizations, and to form new coalitions. We therefore look forward to participating at RightsCon and are eager to meet many new faces!</description></item><item><title>OONI Community Interviews: Moses Karanja</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-community-interviews-moses-karanja/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-community-interviews-moses-karanja/</guid><description>We first met Moses Karanja several years ago at the Citizen Lab Summer Institute. He’s a Kenyan information controls researcher, having previously worked with Strathmore University Law School research centre, CIPIT. Currently, he’s a PhD student at the University of Toronto.
Over the last years, Moses has championed OONI community engagement across Africa. Thanks to his tireless efforts, communities in many African countries are now running OONI Probe and using OONI data to examine internet censorship and other forms of network interference.</description></item><item><title>ParkNet: Short Documentary on Internet Censorship in Cuba</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/parknet-short-documentary-cuba/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/parknet-short-documentary-cuba/</guid><description>Last year we had the opportunity to travel to Cuba to explore its internet landscape. We spent most of our time hopping from one public WiFi hotspot to another, measuring networks in Havana, Santa Clara, and Santiago de Cuba. You might remember that we published a research report on our findings.
Today we publish a short documentary (“ParkNet”) on our study of internet censorship in Cuba.
“ParkNet” is a term that we coined to refer to parks that serve as public WiFi hotspots in Cuba.</description></item><item><title>OONI's recent participation at events in Africa, India, and Europe</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-africa-india-europe-conferences/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-africa-india-europe-conferences/</guid><description>Over the last months, the OONI team had the opportunity to host workshops, give presentations, and participate in discussions at the following conferences and events:
Seminar at the University of Cape Town (South Africa)
Internet Policy in Africa: Research Methods for Advocacy workshop (Uganda)
Nullcon 2018 (India)
Internet Freedom Festival (IFF) 2018 (Spain)
Tor Meeting (Italy)
These events provided us a great opportunity to meet many fascinating people from various communities, learn about their work, form new collaborations, and collect feedback for the improvement of our tools and methodologies.</description></item><item><title>Sierra Leone: Network disruptions amid 2018 runoff elections</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/sierra-leone-network-disruptions-2018-elections/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/sierra-leone-network-disruptions-2018-elections/</guid><description>Last weekend, two network disruptions occurred in Sierra Leone right before and after the country’s runoff elections.
This post examines these disruptions and shares data that corroborates local reports.
It seems that the network disruptions were caused by an ACE submarine cable cut. Google traffic and BGP data suggest that the second disruption, following the runoff elections, could be an internet blackout.
2018 general elections President Koroma is stepping down, having served ten years in office.</description></item><item><title>Investigating Internet Blackouts from the Edge of the network: OONI's new upcoming methodology</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/investigating-internet-blackouts/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/investigating-internet-blackouts/</guid><description>The OONI team is creating a new methodology aimed at automatically detecting and examining internet blackouts. Learn all about our methodology here.
Imagine a day where the internet is shut down completely. You have to work, check the news, and communicate with your friends and family. All of a sudden, you can’t do any of that, because there simply is no internet. It feels like a strange form of time travel has taken place: you’re thrown several decades into the past, into a world without internet, but in one which has learned to heavily rely on it.</description></item><item><title>Iran Protests: DPI blocking of Instagram (Part 2)</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2018-iran-protests-pt2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2018-iran-protests-pt2/</guid><description>In early January 2018, OONI published a post reporting on the blocking of Telegram and Instagram amidst protests in Iran. We have since been analyzing RIPE data and other network measurements collected from Iran in an attempt to better understand the blockages. Upon further analysis, we found that Instagram was in fact blocked (during the Iran protests) through the use of Deep Packet Inspection (DPI) technology which targeted the TLS protocol.</description></item><item><title>Iran Protests: OONI data confirms censorship events (Part 1)</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2018-iran-protests/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2018-iran-protests/</guid><description>At this point, you have probably read all about the major anti-government protests that erupted across Iran over the last week. You may have even read about how services like Telegram and Instagram were blocked, reportedly as part of a government attempt to stifle the unrest.
We publish this post to share OONI network measurement data collected from Iran between 28th December 2017 (when the protests started) to 2nd January 2018.</description></item><item><title>Year in Review: OONI in 2017</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2017/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2017/</guid><description>As the end of 2017 approaches, we publish this blog to share some OONI highlights from the last year. We also share some of the things we’ll be working on in 2018!
OONI Probe mobile apps
Speed and performance tests
OONI Run
OONI API
OONI Partner Gathering
Research reports
OONI in 2018
OONI Probe mobile apps In February 2017, measuring internet censorship with OONI Probe suddenly became easier than ever before!</description></item><item><title>OONI at the 34th Chaos Communication Congress (34C3)</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-34c3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-34c3/</guid><description>Next week the OONI team will be attending the 34th Chaos Communication Congress (34C3): Europe’s largest hacker conference on technology, society, and utopia. Are you going? We hope to see you there!
OONI lecture OONI&amp;rsquo;s founder and project lead, Arturo Filastò, will be presenting OONI at 34C3.
Lecture OONI: Lets Fight Internet Censorship Together! Day 29th December 2017 Time 14:30 Room Saal Borg Attend the lecture to learn all about OONI, recent censorship findings from around the world, and how you can join the fight against internet censorship.</description></item><item><title>OONI at LAVITS and Primavera Hacker 2017</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-lavits-phacker-2017/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-lavits-phacker-2017/</guid><description>Earlier this month we had the opportunity to present OONI at two conferences in Chile: LAVITS and Primavera Hacker.
LAVITS LAVITS is a Latin American network of surveillance technology and society studies that organizes international symposiums since 2009. It features publications, talks and workshops related to surveillance and technology, internet censorship, resistance and counter surveillance, identification, biometrics, protection of personal data and privacy. The fifth series of the LAVITS symposium took place in Santiago, Chile from 29th November to 1st December 2017.</description></item><item><title>How Pakistan blocked news outlets, social media sites, and IM apps amidst protests</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/how-pakistan-blocked-social-media/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/how-pakistan-blocked-social-media/</guid><description>Last weekend, a number of social media sites and news outlets were blocked in Pakistan during Islamist protests. Protesters gathered in Islamabad alleged that Mr. Zahid Hamid, the Federal Law Minister, should be removed from his position because he omitted a reference to the Prophet Muhammad in a parliamentary bill. On Saturday, 25th November 2017, law enforcement agencies initiated an operation to disperse the sit-in at the Faizabad Interchange linking Islamabad and Rawalpindi.</description></item><item><title>Identifying cases of DNS misconfiguration: Not quite censorship</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/not-quite-network-censorship/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/not-quite-network-censorship/</guid><description>Country: Brazil, worldwide
OONI tests: Web Connectivity, HTTP requests
Probed ISPs: AS1916 (Associação Rede Nacional de Ensino e Pesquisa), AS262650 (Kyatera Informatica Ltda), AS2715 (Fundacao de Amparo a Pesquisa/RJ), AS27699 (TELEFÔNICA BRASIL S.A), AS28573 (CLARO S.A.), AS52873 (SOFTDADOS CONECTIVIDADE), AS7738 (Telemar Norte Leste S.A.), AS8167 (Brasil Telecom S/A - Filial Distrito Federal)
Measurement period: July 2016 — November 2017
Website inaccessibility reasons: IPv6 or DNS misconfiguration
We recently noticed that pernambuco.</description></item><item><title>Writing a modern cross-platform desktop app</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/writing-a-modern-cross-platform-desktop-app/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/writing-a-modern-cross-platform-desktop-app/</guid><description>The goal of this article is to outline some of the architecture &amp;amp; design considerations made while thinking about how we would implement the OONI Probe desktop apps. This is the result of research and experimentation with a variety of different libraries and approaches. For each part of the technical stack we will outline the rationale leading to our choices.
Requirements &amp;amp; design goals Our primary goal with the OONI Probe desktop apps is to enable Windows and macOS desktop users to run OONI Probe network measurement tests without knowledge of the command line.</description></item><item><title>OONI Team Meeting: Montreal 2017</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-team-meeting-montreal-2017/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-team-meeting-montreal-2017/</guid><description>Last week, right before the Tor meeting, the OONI team gathered in Montreal for a 4-day meeting to reflect, regroup, hack, and plan.
This post shares information from our meeting and future plans with the broader community. All session notes are available on GitHub.
Summary: What OONI is working on
Sessions
Day 1 - 7th October 2017
Day 2 - 8th October 2017</description></item><item><title>Internet Censorship in Pakistan: Findings from 2014-2017</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/pakistan-internet-censorship/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/pakistan-internet-censorship/</guid><description>Islamabad: Political dissent in Pakistan under threat, government censors online content - PC: Haroon Baloch
A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) and Bytes for All Pakistan.
Table of contents
Key Findings
Introduction
Background
Network landscape and internet penetration
Legal environment
Freedom of expression
Press freedom
Access to information
Privacy and digital surveillance</description></item><item><title>Evidence of Internet Censorship during Catalonia's Independence Referendum</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/internet-censorship-catalonia-independence-referendum/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/internet-censorship-catalonia-independence-referendum/</guid><description>Image: Catalan Independence Referendum site seized
Two days ago, Catalonia held a referendum seeking independence from Spain. As the world awaits to see what happens next, we publish this post to share evidence of recent censorship events that occurred during and leading up to the referendum.
We confirm the blocking of at least 25 sites related to the Catalan referendum by means of DNS tampering and HTTP blocking, based on OONI Probe network measurements collected from three local networks.</description></item><item><title>Internet Censorship in Iran: Network Measurement Findings from 2014-2017</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/iran-internet-censorship/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/iran-internet-censorship/</guid><description>Image: Blockpage in Iran
A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI), ASL19, ARTICLE 19, and Small Media.
Table of contents
Key Findings
Introduction
Background
Network landscape
Internet use
Legal environment
Reported cases of internet censorship
Methodology: Measuring internet censorship in Iran
Review of the Citizen Lab&amp;rsquo;s test list for Iran</description></item><item><title>OONI Run: Let's fight internet censorship together!</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-run/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-run/</guid><description>Today we released OONI Run, a website linked to an exciting new OONI Probe mobile app feature that enables you to:
Engage your friends (and the world) to run censorship measurement tests
Monitor the blocking of your website around the world
OONI Run includes a variety of OONI Probe software testsdesigned to:
Test the blocking of websites
Find middleboxes
Measure the speed and performance of networks</description></item><item><title>Measuring Internet Censorship in Cuba's ParkNets</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/cuba-internet-censorship-2017/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/cuba-internet-censorship-2017/</guid><description>Image by Arturo Filastò (CC-BY-SA-3.0) A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI)
View the pdf version of the report here.
Table of contents
Key Findings
Introduction
Background
Network landscape and internet penetration
ETECSA
ParkNets
Joven Club
StreetNets
El Paquete
Summary
Measuring Internet Censorship in Cuba</description></item><item><title>OONI Partner Gathering 2017</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-partner-gathering-2017/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-partner-gathering-2017/</guid><description>Two weeks ago we hosted the first OONI Partner Gathering in Toronto, Canada. This report provides an overview of the event, partner needs and challenges, and future goals to address them.
View the pdf version of the report here.
About
Objectives
Sessions
Day 1 - 10th July 2017
Day 2 - 11th July 2017
Inclusiveness
Challenges and needs</description></item><item><title>#EgyptCensors: Evidence of recent censorship events in Egypt</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/egypt-censors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/egypt-censors/</guid><description>Country: Egypt
OONI tests: Web Connectivity, HTTP Header Field Manipulation, HTTP Invalid Request Line, HTTP Host, Vanilla Tor.
Probed ISPs: Link Egypt (AS24863), Vodafone Egypt (AS36935), Telecom Egypt (AS8452).
Analysis period: 23rd May 2017 to 17th June 2017.
Censorship method: Deep Packet Inspection (DPI) used to RESET connections.
Starting on May 24th, the Egyptian government ordered ISPs to block at least 21 news websites on the grounds of “supporting terrorism and spreading lies”.</description></item><item><title>The State of Internet Censorship in Indonesia</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/indonesia-internet-censorship/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/indonesia-internet-censorship/</guid><description>Image: Block page in Indonesia
A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) and Sinar Project.
Table of contents
Key Findings
Introduction
Background
Network landscape and internet penetration
Legal environment
Freedom of expression
Press freedom
Access to information
Privacy
Censorship and surveillance
Reported cases of internet censorship and surveillance</description></item><item><title>OONI at the CryptoRave 2017</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-cryptorave-2017/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-cryptorave-2017/</guid><description>CryptoRave is a free, non-commercial and collectively funded 48 hour event featuring talks, workshops and activities related to security, privacy, anonymity, hacking and freedom of expression that attracts more that 2,500 people mainly from South America. The event took place in São Paulo, Brazil on 5th and 6th May 2017.
A number of people attended the OONI presentation and workshop (&amp;ldquo;Listatona&amp;rdquo;) that was co-organized with Coding Rights. During the workshop participants were able to better understand OONI&amp;rsquo;s testing methodology, and how OONI Probe performs network measurements.</description></item><item><title>OONI at the Internet Freedom Festival &amp; RightsCon 2017</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-iff-rightscon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-iff-rightscon/</guid><description>Over the last month the OONI team joined the internet freedom community at the following events:
Vietnam Cyber Dialogue (VCD)
Internet Freedom Festival (IFF)
Iran Cyber Dialogue (ICD)
RightsCon 2017
International Journalism Festival (IJF)
These events provided us with the opportunity to engage with community members, create new friendships, learn about new projects, and to share skills and knowledge.</description></item><item><title>The State of Internet Censorship in Myanmar</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/myanmar-report/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 13:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/myanmar-report/</guid><description>A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI), Sinar Project, and the Myanmar ICT for Development Organization (MIDO).
Table of contents
Key Findings
Introduction
Background
Network landscape and internet penetration
Legal environment
Freedom of expression
Press freedom
Access to information
Privacy
Censorship and surveillance
Reported cases of internet censorship and surveillance</description></item><item><title>Examining internet blackouts through public data sources</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/examining-internet-blackouts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 16:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/examining-internet-blackouts/</guid><description>Pulling the plug on the internet is one of the ways that governments around the world attempt to exert control over the flow of information.
While the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) project has developed numerous software tests for examining different forms of internet censorship (such as the blocking of websites, instant messaging apps, and censorship circumvention tools), we currently do not have tests that are designed to examine internet blackouts, when the internet as a whole is rendered inaccessible within a location.</description></item><item><title>The State of Internet Censorship in Thailand</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/thailand-internet-censorship/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/thailand-internet-censorship/</guid><description>Image: Block page in Thailand
A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI), Sinar Project, and the Thai Netizen Network.
Table of contents
Key Findings
Introduction
Background
Network landscape and internet penetration
Legal environment
Freedom of expression
Press freedom
Access to information
Privacy
Censorship and surveillance
Reported cases of internet censorship and surveillance</description></item><item><title>New OONI Probe Mobile App: Measure Internet Censorship &amp; Performance</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-mobile-app/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-mobile-app/</guid><description>Today the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) project is thrilled to announce the release of a new mobile app (“OONI Probe - Measure Internet Censorship &amp;amp; Performance”) that can now be installed on Android and iOS for testing Internet censorship and network performance.
By running the tests included in OONI’s mobile app, you can monitor:
Blocking of websites; Presence of systems that could be responsible for censorship or surveillance; Speed and performance of your network.</description></item><item><title>Kenya: Censorship-free internet?</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/kenya-study/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/kenya-study/</guid><description>Over the last five months we ran OONI tests in Kenya almost every day to examine whether internet censorship events were occurring in the country. Hundreds of thousands of network measurements were collected and analyzed. 1,357 URLs were tested for censorship, including both international websites and sites that are more relevant to Kenya (e.g. local news outlets). Yet, after five months of intensive testing from four local vantage points in Kenya, we found almost no signs of internet censorship in the country.</description></item><item><title>The State of Internet Censorship in Malaysia</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/malaysia-report/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/malaysia-report/</guid><description>Block page in Malaysia
A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) and Sinar Project.
Table of contents
Key Findings
Introduction
Background
Network landscape and internet penetration
Legal environment
Freedom of expression
Press freedom
Access to information
Privacy
Censorship and surveillance
Previous cases of internet censorship and surveillance</description></item><item><title>New OONI tests examine the blocking of WhatsApp and Facebook Messenger</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/whatsapp-and-facebook-tests/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/whatsapp-and-facebook-tests/</guid><description>Today the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) project is excited to announce the release of two new software tests which are designed to examine the blocking of WhatsApp and Facebook Messenger. You can now run these tests to monitor the accessibility of these apps across time, and to collect data that can serve as evidence when/if they are blocked.
WhatsApp test Many of our users have asked us to develop a test to examine the accessibility of WhatsApp, especially in light of it being blocked by various governments around the world during elections, protests, and other political events.</description></item><item><title>Ethiopia: Evidence of social media blocking and internet censorship</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-report/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-report/</guid><description>Youth in Addis trying to get Wi-Fi Connection. Credit Addis Fortune Newspaper
Recently we published a post about what appeared to be a possible internet shutdown in Ethiopia during a wave of ongoing protests by ethnic groups. Today, in collaboration with Amnesty International we are releasing a report that includes evidence of recent censorship events during Ethiopia’s political upheaval.
See the Amharic translation of the report. Translated by Wolete Mariam.</description></item><item><title>OONI releases new Web UI: Run censorship tests from your web browser!</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/web-ui-post/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/web-ui-post/</guid><description>Today we are excited to announce the beta release of our new web-based user interface (WUI) that enables OONI Probe users to run censorship tests from a web browser!
Whether you’re running OONI Probe from your desktop or a Raspberry Pi, you can now easily choose which tests you want to run through OONI’s web UI and run them with the click of a button. These tests are designed to examine the following:</description></item><item><title>The Gambia: Internet Shutdown during 2016 Presidential Election</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/gambia-internet-shutdown/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/gambia-internet-shutdown/</guid><description>Last week we attempted to perform OONI network measurement tests in the Gambia to examine whether websites were blocked during its 2016 presidential election. But merely a few hours after we connected our probe to perform tests, it stopped working completely.
We suspected that this was due to an internet shutdown. To confirm this, we referred to third-party data to examine whether a country-wide internet blackout was taking place.
In this report, we summarize some of our key findings pertaining to the internet shutdown that appears to have occurred in the Gambia on the eve of its 2016 presidential election.</description></item><item><title>urandom.pcap: Belarus (finally) bans Tor</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/belarus-fries-onion/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/belarus-fries-onion/</guid><description>Country: Belarus
Probed ISPs: Beltelecom (AS 6697)
Censorship method: TCP injections
We have recently heard of network anomalies in Belarus. Tor has been finally blocked in December 2016, although it had been explicitly declared that Tor should be blocked since February 2015.
An anonymous cypherpunk has helped to gather some evidence regarding Tor being blocked in Belarus. It&amp;rsquo;s neither a complete study nor an in-depth research and it&amp;rsquo;s unclear if any other further evidence will be gathered, so we decided to share current knowledge as-is:</description></item><item><title>OONI releases Lepidopter Raspberry Pi distribution</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/lepidopter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/lepidopter/</guid><description>The Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) team is happy to announce the beta release of OONI Probe&amp;rsquo;s distribution for Raspberry Pis, caĺled Lepidopter.
What is Lepidopter Lepidopter is a Raspberry Pi distribution image with all the required dependencies and software packages in place, configured to run network measurement tests via the OONI Probe software. It is developed and designed to require no physical attendance upon first bootstrap but also allows experienced users to further configure it as they wish.</description></item><item><title>OONI-dev meeting and hackathon 2016</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-dev-and-hackathon-2016/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-dev-and-hackathon-2016/</guid><description>Oonitarians are spread out across the globe, and OONI’s core team is no exception. We recently met in Berlin to hack on OONI’s software, work on our roadmap, and to have all those discussions that are more fruitful to have in person than on IRC. We also held a hackathon to engage new individuals with our project!
Below we document some of the things that we worked on as part of our OONI-dev meeting and hackathon.</description></item><item><title>Egypt: Media censorship, Tor interference, HTTPS throttling and ads injections?</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/egypt-network-interference/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/egypt-network-interference/</guid><description>Country: Egypt
Probed ISPs: Noor (AS 20928), TE Data (AS 8452), Vodafone (AS 24835)
Censorship method: DPI, network throttling, TCP injections
OONI tests: HTTP Requests, Web Connectivity, Vanilla Tor
Measurement period: 2016-08-27 - 2016-10-26
We recently noticed network anomalies in Egypt and performed a study in an attempt to understand the situation.
Our findings indicate that the Tor anonymity network appeared to be interfered with in Egypt, while HTTPS connections to DigitalOcean&amp;rsquo;s Frankfurt data centre were throttled.</description></item><item><title>OONI Hackathon: Join us to explore internet censorship!</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/berlin-hackathon-2016/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/berlin-hackathon-2016/</guid><description>Interested in exploring (and exposing) internet censorship? Join the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) hackathon in Berlin!
When? Friday, 11th November &amp;amp; Saturday, 12th November 2016
Where? The OnionSpace (Gottschedstraße 4, 13357 Berlin, Germany)
What time? 10am onwards
Who? Software developers, data analysts, academics, journalists, bloggers, lawyers, activists, and all those who don’t go by any particular label, but are curious enough to join!</description></item><item><title>Zambia: Internet censorship during the 2016 general elections?</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/zambia-election-monitoring/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 10:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/zambia-election-monitoring/</guid><description>A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) and Strathmore University’s Centre for Intellectual Property and Information Technology Law (CIPIT).
Table of contents
Key Findings
Introduction
Background
Network landscape and internet penetration
Legal environment
Freedom of expression
Press freedom
Access to information
Privacy
Censorship and surveillance
Previous cases of internet censorship and surveillance</description></item><item><title>Ethiopia: Internet Shutdown Amidst Recent Protests?</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-internet-shutdown-amidst-recent-protests/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-internet-shutdown-amidst-recent-protests/</guid><description>Nearly 100 deaths and thousands of arrests have been reported in Ethiopia over the last days, as part of protests against the marginalization and persecution of the Oromos and Amharas, Ethiopia’s two largest ethnic groups. But the attacks and arrests may not have been the only forms of retribution carried out by the Ethiopian government in its crackdown against protesters.
Last weekend, the internet was reportedly shut down in the country.</description></item><item><title>Internet Access Disruption in Turkey - July 2016</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/turkey-internet-access-disruption/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/turkey-internet-access-disruption/</guid><description>With the attempted coup in Turkey, reports went out about social media being throttled and/or blocked. We analysed data about this that we collected with RIPE Atlas and the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI).
On 15 July, a coup was attempted in Turkey. We heard about social media being throttled and/or blocked, but much was unclear about what was actually going on. Here we present measurement data from various platforms that shared their data publicly.</description></item><item><title>OONI releases new Web Connectivity test for detecting online censorship</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/web-connectivity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/web-connectivity/</guid><description>Today the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) is excited to be releasing a brand new test, called Web Connectivity, which is designed to detect three different types of censorship: DNS tampering, TCP/IP blocking and HTTP blocking.
Advantages of running Web Connectivity This test allows us to see which websites are blocked and how, more accurately than ever before!
Previously we relied on running separate (http_request, dns_consistency and tcp_connect) tests with the aim of identifying various forms of censorship.</description></item><item><title>How Uganda blocked social media, again</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/uganda-social-media-blocked/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/uganda-social-media-blocked/</guid><description>Country: Uganda
Probed ISPs: Orange (AS36991), SMILE (AS37122)
Censorship method: IP blocking
OONI tests: HTTP Requests
Measurement period: 2016-05-12
Last Wednesday, the Ugandan Communications Commission (UCC) ordered ISPs to block access to social media leading up to the (fifth) inauguration of President Yoweri Museveni, who has governed the country since 1986. Authorities argued that the blocking was ordered for “security purposes”, but the move directly harms political opposition, which has relied on social media to organize a “defiance campaign” of protests.</description></item><item><title>OONI Data Reveals How WhatsApp Was Blocked (Again) in Brazil</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/brazil-whatsapp-block/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/brazil-whatsapp-block/</guid><description>Country: Brazil
Probed ISPs: Tim mobile (AS 26615), Oi landline (AS 7738)
Censorship method: DNS Hijacking
OONI tests: HTTP Requests, DNS Consistency
Measurement period: 2016-05-02 - 2016-05-03
19:10 UTC Saturday, 7 May 2016 Update: Add OONI Explorer measurements links
Ever since WhatsApp implemented end-to-end encryption to protect the privacy and security of its 1 billion users worldwide, several cases of censorship have been ordered by governments who are frustrated with the fact that they can no longer access users' private communications.</description></item><item><title>EEEP and Greek Internet censorship</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/eeep-greek-censorship/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/eeep-greek-censorship/</guid><description>Technical analysis of Hellenic gaming commission blacklist in Greece</description></item><item><title>Zambia, a country under Deep Packet Inspection</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/zambia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/zambia/</guid><description>&amp;quot;I do not have the details of the blocking of Zambianwatchdog.com, but I would celebrate.&amp;quot; Guy Scott Zambian Vicepresident, Friday 28th June 2013 The following article is a guest blog post by Mr T. an independent researcher and provider of hosting to various grass roots organizations.
This article summarizes how we discovered that the grass roots online newspaper Zambianwatchdog.com was being blocked inside Zambia. This report provides technical evidence of the unlawful presence of Deep Packet Inspection in the country to monitor the Internet communications and stop users from browsing the website.</description></item><item><title>Tab-Tab, Come in! Bypassing Internet blocking to categorize DPI devices</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/tab-tab-come-in/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/tab-tab-come-in/</guid><description>Analysis of censorship in Turkmenistan and Uzbekistan</description></item><item><title>Hadara Palestine</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/hadara-palestine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/hadara-palestine/</guid><description>This is the technical report on the politically motivated censorship going on in Bethlehem, West Bank</description></item><item><title>T-Mobile USA Web Guard</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/t-mobile-usa-web-guard/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/t-mobile-usa-web-guard/</guid><description>Measuring censorship on T-Mobile USA</description></item></channel></rss>