<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>event on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/event/</link><description>Recent content in event on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/event/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Internet Measurement Village 2020: Slides &amp; Video Recordings</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-imv-slides-recordings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-imv-slides-recordings/</guid><description>Over the last month, between 10th June 2020 to 3rd July 2020, we organized and hosted the Internet Measurement Village (IMV) 2020, an online community event aimed at sharing skills, knowledge, and resources on internet measurement, in defense of a free and open internet.
As all the IMV sessions were live-streamed and will continue to live on the OONI YouTube channel, we hope that these recordings will serve as a valuable resource on internet measurement for the internet freedom community.</description></item><item><title>Join the online Internet Measurement Village 2020</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-internet-measurement-village/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-internet-measurement-village/</guid><description>Subscribe on YouTube We are excited to bring the first online Internet Measurement Village to you this month.
Interested in learning all about Internet measurement and how to detect Internet censorship? Curious to explore open datasets on Internet censorship and Internet outages? Eager to learn how advocates are pushing back against Internet shutdowns and defending a free and open Internet?
Join us for the online Internet Measurement Village, starting on Wednesday, 10th June 2020 and ending on Friday, 3rd July 2020.</description></item></channel></rss>