<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>community on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/community/</link><description>Recent content in community on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OONI Community Video</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-community-video/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-community-video/</guid><description>We are happy to celebrate OONI&amp;rsquo;s 10th anniversary together with our amazing community, who have been at the heart of our work over the past decade.
Today, we are excited to share a new video with OONI community members, where they discuss how OONI has been useful to their work, while sharing what they would like to see OONI do in the future.
Featured community members and partners Andrés Azpúrua, Venezuela Inteligente Andrés is the co-founder and Director of Venezuela Inteligente, a non-profit organization that aims to facilitate information, communication and collaboration between citizens and civil society organizations to create impact from a non-partisan perspective.</description></item><item><title>Survey: Help shape OONI’s strategic priorities</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-survey-ooni-strategic-priorities/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-survey-ooni-strategic-priorities/</guid><description>OONI will celebrate its 10th anniversary on 5th December 2022!
This is a time for celebration, but also a time for reflection: What worked well? What should we improve? What should we do differently going forward?
The OONI community has been at the heart of our work over the past decade, and so we invite our community to help shape OONI’s strategic priorities for the future.
Please take a few minutes to complete our survey: https://ooni.</description></item><item><title>New online OONI training course launched by Advocacy Assembly</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-ooni-training-course-advocacy-assembly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-ooni-training-course-advocacy-assembly/</guid><description>We are excited to share that a free, online OONI training course (“Measuring Internet Censorship with OONI tools”) has been launched today on Small Media’s Advocacy Assembly platform!
Through this course, you will learn how to measure internet censorship through the use of OONI tools. You will also learn how to access and interpret real-time OONI data on internet censorship around the world.
Today, the course is available in English, Arabic, Spanish, and Farsi.</description></item><item><title>Job Opening: OONI Community Coordinator</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-job-opening-ooni-community-coordinator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-job-opening-ooni-community-coordinator/</guid><description>Are you passionate about defending human rights on the internet? Are you extremely organized and enjoy supporting communities around the world? We have a job opening for you!
The OONI team (a non-profit fighting internet censorship) is looking for a dedicated community coordinator to help grow and support the OONI community around the world.
The application deadline is Sunday, 12th June 2022.
Job description By joining our team, you will support our partners and global community of human rights defenders to measure and fight internet censorship.</description></item><item><title>[Event Report] India, Let's Build the List</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-event-india-test-list/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-event-india-test-list/</guid><description>This is a guest post by The Bachchao Project, originally published here.
The Bachchao Project in partnership with OONI hosted an online event on 9th and 10th October 2021 to update the Citizen Lab test list for India. The event, which was called “India, Lets build the list”, was organised to help strengthen community based monitoring of internet censorship in India. The event allowed experts from different fields to contribute to a curated list of websites that are relevant to India and which are regularly tested for censorship by volunteers in India.</description></item><item><title>OONI Community Interviews: Julie Owono</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-community-interviews-julie-owono/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-community-interviews-julie-owono/</guid><description>If you’ve met Julie Owono, you’ll probably agree that her passion and determination for defending digital rights is one of the things that stands out about her.
In her capacity as the Executive Director of Internet Sans Frontières (Internet Without Borders), Julie has spearheaded advocacy efforts in defense of online freedoms in many West African countries. Notably, Julie led campaigns against internet shutdowns in Cameroon, as well as in Togo and Chad.</description></item><item><title>OONI Community Interviews: Moses Karanja</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-community-interviews-moses-karanja/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-community-interviews-moses-karanja/</guid><description>We first met Moses Karanja several years ago at the Citizen Lab Summer Institute. He’s a Kenyan information controls researcher, having previously worked with Strathmore University Law School research centre, CIPIT. Currently, he’s a PhD student at the University of Toronto.
Over the last years, Moses has championed OONI community engagement across Africa. Thanks to his tireless efforts, communities in many African countries are now running OONI Probe and using OONI data to examine internet censorship and other forms of network interference.</description></item></channel></rss>