<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>technology on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.org/tags/technology/</link><description>Recent content in technology on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.org/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A brief introduction to OONI</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/brief-introduction-to-ooni/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/brief-introduction-to-ooni/</guid><description>This is gentle introduction to OONI that does not require readers to have a technical background.
If you are familiar with how the Internet works and how it can be censored you can skip The basics.
For frequently asked questions and answers, please refer to the OONI FAQ.
The basics You might be connecting to the Internet from a local network or using an Internet Service Provider (ISP).
ISPs are usually not connected to each other.</description></item><item><title>Mining OONI data</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/mining-ooni-data/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/mining-ooni-data/</guid><description>OONI receives measurement data from the OONI Probes and processes it in real time to detect censorship.
There are different ways to access the output of the processing: OONI Explorer, the OONI API and dumps of the PostgreSQL database.
OONI Explorer provides a user-friendly web interface to all visitors.
The OONI API is meant for developers and researches and allows searching for measurement metadata, fetching single measurements, and generating statistics. Hovever, is not designed for large data transfers (i.</description></item><item><title>OONI Software Development Guidelines</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/ooni-software-development-guidelines/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/ooni-software-development-guidelines/</guid><description>The goal of this document is to explain and explicit some of the best practices relevant to software development that we follow at the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI).
By following these development guidelines we aim to produce higher quality code, which contains less defects and allows us to iterate more quickly delivering greater value to our end users is a shorter amount of time!
Version control Also known as: “How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Love the Git!</description></item><item><title>Iran Protests: DPI blocking of Instagram (Part 2)</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/2018-iran-protests-pt2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/2018-iran-protests-pt2/</guid><description>In early January 2018, OONI published a post reporting on the blocking of Telegram and Instagram amidst protests in Iran. We have since been analyzing RIPE data and other network measurements collected from Iran in an attempt to better understand the blockages. Upon further analysis, we found that Instagram was in fact blocked (during the Iran protests) through the use of Deep Packet Inspection (DPI) technology which targeted the TLS protocol.</description></item><item><title>Writing a modern cross-platform desktop app</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/writing-a-modern-cross-platform-desktop-app/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/writing-a-modern-cross-platform-desktop-app/</guid><description>The goal of this article is to outline some of the architecture &amp;amp; design considerations made while thinking about how we would implement the OONI Probe desktop apps. This is the result of research and experimentation with a variety of different libraries and approaches. For each part of the technical stack we will outline the rationale leading to our choices.
Requirements &amp;amp; design goals Our primary goal with the OONI Probe desktop apps is to enable Windows and macOS desktop users to run OONI Probe network measurement tests without knowledge of the command line.</description></item></channel></rss>