<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/about/</link><description>Recent content in About on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://ooni.github.io/about/inform-users-long/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/about/inform-users-long/</guid><description>GOAL OONI is a project aimed at mapping network anomalies by performing measurements from the vantage point of a users. You may find details on what exactly it is that we measure by reading through our test specifications. The data we collect is then made available to the public for further analysis.
The goal of this study is to have a better understanding on how the internet works around the world and what is stopping it from working as it should.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://ooni.github.io/about/inform-users-short/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/about/inform-users-short/</guid><description>WARNING: Running OONI may be against the terms of service of your ISP or legally questionable in your country. By running OONI you will connect to web services which may be banned, and use web censorship circumvention methods such as Tor. The OONI project will publish data submitted by probes, possibly including your IP address or other identifying information. In addition, your use of OONI will be clear to anybody who has access to your computer, and to anybody who can monitor your internet connection (such as your employer, ISP or government).</description></item><item><title/><link>https://ooni.github.io/about/risks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/about/risks/</guid><description>Risks: Things you should know before running OONI Probe Translations:
Español, Riesgos: Lo que debes saber antes de ejecutar OONI Probe العربية, Risks: Things you should know before running OONI Probe فارسی, Risks: Things you should know before running OONI Probe Kiswahili, Hatari: Vitu unavyotakiwa kuvijua kabla ya kutumia OONI Probe Русский, Риски: что вы должны знать до запуска OONI Probe Français, Risques: Ce que vous devez savoir avant d&amp;rsquo;exécuter OONI Probe To our knowledge, no OONI Probe user has ever faced consequences as a result of using our software.</description></item><item><title>OONI Data Policy</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/about/data-policy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/about/data-policy/</guid><description>Last modified: March 20, 2023
Version: 1.4.7
This Data Policy discloses and explains what data the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) project (&amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;us&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;our&amp;rdquo;) collects, processes, stores and publishes relating to the users of its OONI Probe software (&amp;ldquo;you&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;your&amp;rdquo;). This Data Policy also outlines the data principles that govern OONI&amp;rsquo;s data practices.
Data Principles
1. Purpose Limitation
2. User Safety</description></item></channel></rss>