<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>blackout on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/blackout/</link><description>Recent content in blackout on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/blackout/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A multi-perspective view of Internet censorship in Myanmar</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-multiperspective-view-internet-censorship-myanmar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-multiperspective-view-internet-censorship-myanmar/</guid><description>In the wake of a military coup in February 2021, Myanmar experienced unprecedented levels of internet censorship.
In response, we collaborated with CAIDA’s Internet Outage Detection and Analysis (IODA) team and Myanmar ICT for Development Organization (MIDO) on publishing a research report which documents a series of nightly internet outages and the blocking of social media, Wikipedia, and circumvention tool sites in Myanmar following the military coup.
In the months that followed, we continued to examine internet censorship in Myanmar quite closely.</description></item><item><title>Investigating Internet shutdowns through Mozilla telemetry</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-investigating-internet-shutdowns-mozilla-telemetry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-investigating-internet-shutdowns-mozilla-telemetry/</guid><description>More than 200 million users worldwide use the Firefox web browser (developed by Mozilla) every month.
If access to the Internet is shut down in a country, Mozilla should expect to see a dramatic drop in Firefox usage from that country. Given how widespread the use of Firefox is around the world, could Mozilla telemetry be a valuable resource for the Internet freedom community to investigate Internet shutdowns?
To explore this question, the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) and Internet Outage Detection and Analysis (IODA) teams joined forces to analyze a dataset of potential outage signals gathered through regular Mozilla telemetry, access to which was provided by Mozilla as part of a relevant research project to validate assumptions about the data.</description></item><item><title>Myanmar: Data on internet blocks and internet outages following military coup</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-myanmar-internet-blocks-and-outages/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-myanmar-internet-blocks-and-outages/</guid><description>On 1st February 2021, the military in Myanmar carried out a coup d’etat, seizing power and detaining the country’s State Counsellor (equivalent to a prime minister) and other democratically elected leaders.
A few days after the coup, ISPs in Myanmar started blocking access to Facebook services. On 5th February 2021, they started blocking access to Twitter and Instagram as well. On 6th February 2021, access to the internet was shut down entirely for nearly 30 hours.</description></item><item><title>Uganda: Data on internet blocks and nationwide internet outage amid 2021 general election</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-uganda-general-election-blocks-and-outage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-uganda-general-election-blocks-and-outage/</guid><description>Last week, amid its 2021 general election, Uganda was disconnected from the internet entirely. The country experienced a widespread internet blackout that lasted 4 days, starting on the eve of the election (13th January 2021) and ending in the morning of 18th January 2021. In the days leading up to the election, access to major social media platforms and circumvention tools was blocked &amp;ndash; even when the OTT (Over the Top) tax (commonly referred to as the “Social Media Tax”) was paid.</description></item><item><title>Internet disruption in Gabon amid coup attempt</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/gabon-internet-disruption/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/gabon-internet-disruption/</guid><description>On 7th January 2019, a military coup was attempted in Gabon in a bid to end more than 50 years of rule by President Ali Bongo’s family. The coup attempt was quickly foiled. Security forces reportedly killed two suspects, arrested seven others, and Gabon’s government retained control.
Meanwhile, a curfew has been imposed and NetBlocks reported that access to the Internet has been shut down.
In this post, we share data that provides signals of network disruptions in Gabon.</description></item><item><title>Examining internet blackouts through public data sources</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/examining-internet-blackouts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 16:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/examining-internet-blackouts/</guid><description>Pulling the plug on the internet is one of the ways that governments around the world attempt to exert control over the flow of information.
While the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) project has developed numerous software tests for examining different forms of internet censorship (such as the blocking of websites, instant messaging apps, and censorship circumvention tools), we currently do not have tests that are designed to examine internet blackouts, when the internet as a whole is rendered inaccessible within a location.</description></item></channel></rss>