<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>blackout on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.org/tags/blackout/</link><description>Recent content in blackout on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.org/tags/blackout/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Uganda: Data on internet blocks and nationwide internet outage amid 2021 general election</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/2021-uganda-general-election-blocks-and-outage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/2021-uganda-general-election-blocks-and-outage/</guid><description>Last week, amid its 2021 general election, Uganda was disconnected from the internet entirely. The country experienced a widespread internet blackout that lasted 4 days, starting on the eve of the election (13th January 2021) and ending in the morning of 18th January 2021. In the days leading up to the election, access to major social media platforms and circumvention tools was blocked &amp;ndash; even when the OTT (Over the Top) tax (commonly referred to as the “Social Media Tax”) was paid.</description></item><item><title>Internet disruption in Gabon amid coup attempt</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/gabon-internet-disruption/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/gabon-internet-disruption/</guid><description>On 7th January 2019, a military coup was attempted in Gabon in a bid to end more than 50 years of rule by President Ali Bongo’s family. The coup attempt was quickly foiled. Security forces reportedly killed two suspects, arrested seven others, and Gabon’s government retained control.
Meanwhile, a curfew has been imposed and NetBlocks reported that access to the Internet has been shut down.
In this post, we share data that provides signals of network disruptions in Gabon.</description></item><item><title>Examining internet blackouts through public data sources</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/examining-internet-blackouts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 16:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/examining-internet-blackouts/</guid><description>Pulling the plug on the internet is one of the ways that governments around the world attempt to exert control over the flow of information.
While the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) project has developed numerous software tests for examining different forms of internet censorship (such as the blocking of websites, instant messaging apps, and censorship circumvention tools), we currently do not have tests that are designed to examine internet blackouts, when the internet as a whole is rendered inaccessible within a location.</description></item></channel></rss>