<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ooni on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.org/tags/ooni/</link><description>Recent content in ooni on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.org/tags/ooni/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building a smart URL list system: Policy for URL prioritization</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/ooni-smart-url-list-system/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/ooni-smart-url-list-system/</guid><description>To improve the monitoring of website censorship around the world, OONI aims to create a smart URL list system, while ensuring, to the extent possible, the safety of the URL lists themselves by running them through the usual Citizen Lab URL review process. This will help ensure smarter test target selection and by extension, it will enable us &amp;ndash; and the broader internet freedom community &amp;ndash; to more effectively monitor, analyze, and respond to cases of website censorship around the world.</description></item><item><title>Let's measure the accessibility of COVID-19 websites around the world</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/covid-19-ooni-measurement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/covid-19-ooni-measurement/</guid><description>Ensuring a free and open internet during an emergency, like the current COVID-19 pandemic, is more important than ever. However, access to information related to the coronavirus pandemic has already been censored by certain governments. China censored information on the coronavirus on Chinese social media platforms, while Venezuela’s state-owned CANTV blocked access to a coronavirus information portal last week.
We therefore invite you to participate in a measurement campaign to check if COVID-19 sites are accessible in your country (and on the network you’re using) and to share relevant measurement data with the world.</description></item><item><title>Year in Review: OONI in 2019</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/ooni-in-2019/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/ooni-in-2019/</guid><description>As the new decade begins, we publish this post to share some OONI highlights from 2019. We also share some thoughts for 2020.
New Apps
Revamped OONI Probe Mobile App
New OONI Probe Desktop App
Near real-time publication of OONI measurements
Revamped OONI Explorer
OONI PostgreSQL MetaDB
Improved measurements
New OONI Probe tests</description></item><item><title>OONI Highlights: 2017-2019</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/ooni-highlights-2017-2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/ooni-highlights-2017-2019/</guid><description>This post was originally published on the OTF website.
Back in 2012, the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) was born with OTF support to create the first open methodologies that would enable anyone around the world to measure internet censorship and other forms of network interference.
Today, OONI comprises a global community that runs its censorship measurement software (OONI Probe) in more than 200 countries every month. Millions of measurements have been collected from tens of thousands of networks in 236 countries since 2012, all of which are openly published on OONI Explorer &amp;ndash; arguably the largest publicly available resource on internet censorship to date.</description></item><item><title>Year in Review: OONI in 2018</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/ooni-in-2018/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/ooni-in-2018/</guid><description>As the new year begins, we publish this post to share some OONI highlights from 2018. We also share some of the exciting new projects we’ll be launching in 2019!
New partnerships
Research publications
Dev work behind the scenes
Revamped OONI Probe mobile app
Revamped OONI Explorer
New OONI Probe desktop apps
Probe Orchestration
OONI workshops and presentations</description></item><item><title>Year in Review: OONI in 2017</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/ooni-in-2017/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/ooni-in-2017/</guid><description>As the end of 2017 approaches, we publish this blog to share some OONI highlights from the last year. We also share some of the things we’ll be working on in 2018!
OONI Probe mobile apps
Speed and performance tests
OONI Run
OONI API
OONI Partner Gathering
Research reports
OONI in 2018
OONI Probe mobile apps In February 2017, measuring internet censorship with OONI Probe suddenly became easier than ever before!</description></item></channel></rss>