<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ooni on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/ooni/</link><description>Recent content in ooni on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/ooni/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New online OONI training course launched by Advocacy Assembly</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-ooni-training-course-advocacy-assembly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-ooni-training-course-advocacy-assembly/</guid><description>We are excited to share that a free, online OONI training course (“Measuring Internet Censorship with OONI tools”) has been launched today on Small Media’s Advocacy Assembly platform!
Through this course, you will learn how to measure internet censorship through the use of OONI tools. You will also learn how to access and interpret real-time OONI data on internet censorship around the world.
Today, the course is available in English, Arabic, Spanish, and Farsi.</description></item><item><title>New Test Lists Editor: Contribute websites for censorship testing</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-test-lists-editor/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-test-lists-editor/</guid><description>Today the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) team is excited to announce the public launch of our new Test Lists Editor!
This platform enables the public to review and contribute to the lists of websites (“test lists”) that are tested for censorship by OONI Probe users around the world.
Help the internet freedom community discover website blocks around the world by contributing through the new Test Lists Editor!</description></item><item><title>A Quick Look at QUIC Censorship</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-quick-look-quic-censorship/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-quick-look-quic-censorship/</guid><description>This blog post was originally published by the Open Technology Fund to disseminate Kathrin Elmenhorst&amp;rsquo;s QUIC-and-HTTP/3 censorship research as part of her ICFP fellowship with OONI.
Last year, the new network protocol QUIC was introduced. QUIC is a general-purpose transport layer network with the goal of reducing latency compared to existing protocols. Since the introduction of QUIC, we have seen rising volumes of QUIC-based web traffic in the form of HTTP/3.</description></item><item><title>OONI’s submission for the OHCHR report on internet shutdowns and human rights</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-ooni-submission-ohchr-report-internet-shutdowns/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-ooni-submission-ohchr-report-internet-shutdowns/</guid><description>Currently, the 50th session of the UN Human Rights Council is taking place.
In response to the UN High Commissioner for Human Rights’s call for submissions in support of the OHCHR report on internet shutdowns and human rights to the 50th session of the Human Rights Council in June 2022, the OONI team provided a submission with relevant information on the occurrence of mandated disruptions of access to social media and messaging platforms over the past 5 years based on empirical OONI network measurement data.</description></item><item><title>Job Opening: OONI Community Coordinator</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-job-opening-ooni-community-coordinator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-job-opening-ooni-community-coordinator/</guid><description>Are you passionate about defending human rights on the internet? Are you extremely organized and enjoy supporting communities around the world? We have a job opening for you!
The OONI team (a non-profit fighting internet censorship) is looking for a dedicated community coordinator to help grow and support the OONI community around the world.
The application deadline is Sunday, 12th June 2022.
Job description By joining our team, you will support our partners and global community of human rights defenders to measure and fight internet censorship.</description></item><item><title>New Launch: OONI Measurement Aggregation Toolkit (MAT)</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-ooni-mat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-ooni-mat/</guid><description>Today the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) team is thrilled to announce the public launch of the OONI Measurement Aggregation Toolkit (MAT)!
The MAT is a tool that enables you to create your own custom charts based on aggregate views of real-time OONI data collected from around the world.
Use the MAT to track internet censorship worldwide based on real-time OONI data!
About the MAT</description></item><item><title>Year in Review: OONI in 2021</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2021/</guid><description>In light of the ongoing global COVID-19 pandemic, 2021 continued to be a challenging year for everyone.
Yet, several exciting things happened in the censorship measurement world. In this post, we share some OONI highlights from 2021, as well as some upcoming OONI projects for 2022!
OONI Probe
Automated OONI Probe testing
New Debian package for OONI Probe
New OONI Probe Command Line Interface for Linux and macOS</description></item><item><title>iThena integration of OONI Probe boosts censorship measurement coverage worldwide</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-ithena-boosts-ooni-measurement-coverage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-ithena-boosts-ooni-measurement-coverage/</guid><description>Over the last months, the iThena project integrated OONI Probe into their platform, resulting in a major spike in OONI censorship measurement coverage around the world.
In this blog post, we’re excited to introduce you to iThena and discuss how they helped support censorship measurement worldwide.
About iThena
OONI Probe integration into iThena
About iThena iThena, developed by the Cyber-Complex Foundation, is a distributed computation and measurement project based on the Berkeley Open Infrastructure for Network Computing (BOINC) platform.</description></item><item><title>[Event Report] India, Let's Build the List</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-event-india-test-list/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-event-india-test-list/</guid><description>This is a guest post by The Bachchao Project, originally published here.
The Bachchao Project in partnership with OONI hosted an online event on 9th and 10th October 2021 to update the Citizen Lab test list for India. The event, which was called “India, Lets build the list”, was organised to help strengthen community based monitoring of internet censorship in India. The event allowed experts from different fields to contribute to a curated list of websites that are relevant to India and which are regularly tested for censorship by volunteers in India.</description></item><item><title>Why Collaboration and Transparency is Key to Internet Measurement</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-internet-measurements-collaboration-transparency/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-internet-measurements-collaboration-transparency/</guid><description>This post was originally published on the Internet Society Pulse blog.
With Internet shutdowns, disruptions and censorship events on the increase around the world, tracking where such events are happening and gathering evidence to help in the fight against them is becoming more and more important.
Tracking these events is crucial because of the impact they have on society and the economy. When social media apps are blocked, for example, freedom of speech, access to information, and movement-building is hampered.</description></item><item><title>Job Opening: Mobile Developer for OONI Probe</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-job-opening-ooni-mobile-developer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-job-opening-ooni-mobile-developer/</guid><description>Are you a mobile developer interested in defending human rights on the internet? We have a job opening for you!
The OONI team (a non-profit fighting internet censorship, originally born out of the Tor Project) is looking for a dedicated mobile developer to work on OONI Probe: a free software app designed to measure internet censorship and network performance.
The application deadline is Sunday, 31st October 2021.
Job description If you join our team, you will lead the development of the OONI Probe mobile app, supporting human rights defenders worldwide to investigate and fight internet censorship.</description></item><item><title>OONI Partner Training 2021</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-partner-training-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-partner-training-2021/</guid><description>Image: 1st OONI Partner Training, 28th-30th June 2021
Image: 2nd OONI Partner Training, 5th-7th July 2021
Over the last week, we had the pleasure to host two 3-day OONI Partner Training events for our partners in Africa, Latin America, the Middle East, and Asia. As part of these events, our goal was to share OONI-specific knowledge and skills, and to collect feedback to better serve community needs.</description></item><item><title>Year in Review: OONI in 2020</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2020/</guid><description>In light of the global COVID-19 pandemic, 2020 has been a challenging year for everyone.
Yet, several exciting things happened in the censorship measurement world. In this post, we share some OONI highlights from 2020, as well as some upcoming OONI projects for 2021!
OONI Probe
New OONI Probe Desktop App for Windows and macOS
New OONI Probe measurement engine
OONI Run usability study</description></item><item><title>Building a smart URL list system: Policy for URL prioritization</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-smart-url-list-system/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-smart-url-list-system/</guid><description>To improve the monitoring of website censorship around the world, OONI aims to create a smart URL list system, while ensuring, to the extent possible, the safety of the URL lists themselves by running them through the usual Citizen Lab URL review process. This will help ensure smarter test target selection and by extension, it will enable us &amp;ndash; and the broader internet freedom community &amp;ndash; to more effectively monitor, analyze, and respond to cases of website censorship around the world.</description></item><item><title>Let's measure the accessibility of COVID-19 websites around the world</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/covid-19-ooni-measurement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/covid-19-ooni-measurement/</guid><description>Ensuring a free and open internet during an emergency, like the current COVID-19 pandemic, is more important than ever. However, access to information related to the coronavirus pandemic has already been censored by certain governments. China censored information on the coronavirus on Chinese social media platforms, while Venezuela’s state-owned CANTV blocked access to a coronavirus information portal last week.
We therefore invite you to participate in a measurement campaign to check if COVID-19 sites are accessible in your country (and on the network you’re using) and to share relevant measurement data with the world.</description></item><item><title>Year in Review: OONI in 2019</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2019/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2019/</guid><description>As the new decade begins, we publish this post to share some OONI highlights from 2019. We also share some thoughts for 2020.
New Apps
Revamped OONI Probe Mobile App
New OONI Probe Desktop App
Near real-time publication of OONI measurements
Revamped OONI Explorer
OONI PostgreSQL MetaDB
Improved measurements
New OONI Probe tests</description></item><item><title>OONI Highlights: 2017-2019</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-highlights-2017-2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-highlights-2017-2019/</guid><description>This post was originally published on the OTF website.
Back in 2012, the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) was born with OTF support to create the first open methodologies that would enable anyone around the world to measure internet censorship and other forms of network interference.
Today, OONI comprises a global community that runs its censorship measurement software (OONI Probe) in more than 200 countries every month. Millions of measurements have been collected from tens of thousands of networks in 236 countries since 2012, all of which are openly published on OONI Explorer &amp;ndash; arguably the largest publicly available resource on internet censorship to date.</description></item><item><title>Year in Review: OONI in 2018</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2018/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2018/</guid><description>As the new year begins, we publish this post to share some OONI highlights from 2018. We also share some of the exciting new projects we’ll be launching in 2019!
New partnerships
Research publications
Dev work behind the scenes
Revamped OONI Probe mobile app
Revamped OONI Explorer
New OONI Probe desktop apps
Probe Orchestration
OONI workshops and presentations</description></item><item><title>Year in Review: OONI in 2017</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2017/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-in-2017/</guid><description>As the end of 2017 approaches, we publish this blog to share some OONI highlights from the last year. We also share some of the things we’ll be working on in 2018!
OONI Probe mobile apps
Speed and performance tests
OONI Run
OONI API
OONI Partner Gathering
Research reports
OONI in 2018
OONI Probe mobile apps In February 2017, measuring internet censorship with OONI Probe suddenly became easier than ever before!</description></item></channel></rss>