<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sni-Blocking on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/sni-blocking/</link><description>Recent content in Sni-Blocking on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/sni-blocking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Evaluating OONI’s New Measurement Engine in the Context of the Blocking of Women on Web in Spain</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-engine-evaluation-spain/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-engine-evaluation-spain/</guid><description>&lt;p>Reproduction rights site
&lt;a href="https://www.womenonweb.org">www.womenonweb.org&lt;/a> has been
blocked in Spain over the last months by several local Internet Service
Providers (ISPs). Once Spanish hacktivist communities noticed that
&lt;a href="http://www.womenonweb.org">www.womenonweb.org&lt;/a> was
inaccessible, they coordinated on running &lt;a href="https://ooni.org/install/">OONI
Probe&lt;/a> tests to collect
measurement data that could serve as evidence. The findings of this
investigation have been published in &lt;a href="https://blog.magma.lavafeld.org/post/women-on-web-blocking/">an excellent
report&lt;/a>,
whose writing was coordinated by our former colleague, Vasilis Ververis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We were involved in the technical review of the report. We found their
methodology particularly interesting. They used the OONI &lt;a href="https://ooni.org/nettest/web-connectivity/">Web
Connectivity experiment&lt;/a>
along with OONI&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://ooni.org/post/2020-iran-sni-blocking/">experimental SNI based blocking
methodology&lt;/a>,
and they also performed manual experiments with
&lt;a href="https://www.openssl.org/">OpenSSL&lt;/a> and
&lt;a href="https://curl.haxx.se/">cURL&lt;/a>. Because OONI&amp;rsquo;s mission is
to simplify and automate the collection of censorship evidence, we are
always interested in learning how we can expand &lt;a href="https://ooni.org/nettest/web-connectivity/">our Web Connectivity
methodology&lt;/a> to
automatically gather more data that is useful in specific cases.
Coincidentally, as part of &lt;a href="https://github.com/ooni/probe-engine/issues/40">rewriting the Web Connectivity
implementation in Go&lt;/a>, we
have already written experimental code that combines &lt;a href="https://ooni.org/nettest/web-connectivity/">vanilla Web
Connectivity&lt;/a>
with &lt;a href="https://ooni.org/post/2020-iran-sni-blocking/">SNI blocking&lt;/a>
and other techniques. We therefore asked them to run this experimental
code with &lt;a href="https://www.womenonweb.org">www.womenonweb.org&lt;/a>
as a target. Our goal was to evaluate whether our working prototype
would have allowed them to obtain the same research results, without
resorting to manually running specifically tailored network experiments.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Measuring SNI based blocking in Iran</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-iran-sni-blocking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-iran-sni-blocking/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this blog post we start evaluating &lt;a href="https://github.com/ooni/spec/blob/adf9537c43ef848b96792f8dea99fbd7f93fe608/nettests/ts-024-sni-blocking.md">OONI&amp;rsquo;s new SNI blocking
experiment&lt;/a>.
To this end, we will use measurements performed in Iran, where the
blocking technique measured by this experiment is deployed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>OONI&amp;rsquo;s SNI blocking experiment discovers cases where &lt;a href="https://tls.ulfheim.net/">a Client Hello
packet&lt;/a> carrying a specific SNI
triggers blocking. In this context, SNI means &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Server_Name_Indication">Server Name
Indication&lt;/a>.
It is an extension to the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Transport_Layer_Security">Transport Layer
Security&lt;/a>
(TLS) protocol that allows a client to specify the domain name that it
wants an HTTP server to serve. This extension is used in many TLS use
cases. For example, when you access
&lt;a href="https://www.google.com">https://www.google.com&lt;/a> with your
browser, the code will send a Client Hello packet containing the string
&lt;code>www.google.com&lt;/code> in the SNI extension.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>