<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>azerbaijan on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/azerbaijan/</link><description>Recent content in azerbaijan on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/azerbaijan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Azerbaijan and Armenia block TikTok amid border clashes</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-azerbaijan-and-armenia-blocks-tiktok/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-azerbaijan-and-armenia-blocks-tiktok/</guid><description>Earlier this week, on 12th September 2022, fighting erupted between Azerbaijani and Armenian troops along their border. Over the next few days, community members in Azerbaijan reported that the TikTok app was blocked locally.
We analyzed OONI network measurement data to investigate the block. We found that TikTok has been blocked in both Azerbaijan and Armenia over the last few days.
In this report, we share our technical findings. In both Armenia and Azerbaijan, we found TLS and DNS level interference of TikTok domains and endpoints during the border clashes.</description></item><item><title>Media censorship in Azerbaijan through the lens of network measurement</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-azerbaijan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-azerbaijan/</guid><description>Key Findings Introduction Methods OONI network measurement Acknowledgement of limitations Background Network landscape and internet penetration Legal environment Internet censorship and media freedom environment Findings Blocked news media websites Blocking of social media amid 2020 Nagorno-Karabakh war Blocking of social media websites Blocking of instant messaging apps WhatsApp Telegram Blocked circumvention tool sites Tor and Psiphon Conclusion Acknowledgements Key Findings As part of our analysis of OONI measurements collected from Azerbaijan between January 2020 to May 2021, we found:</description></item><item><title>Azərbaycan: OONI Probe Test üçün çağırış</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-azerbaijan-ooni-probe-testing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-azerbaijan-ooni-probe-testing/</guid><description>This is a guest post by Arzu Geybullayeva (Azerbaijan Internet Watch), originally published here.
Azerbaijan Internet Watch Azərbaycanda internet senzurasını izləyir və bu çərçəvədə aşkar etdiyi pozuntuları öz səhifəsində sənədləşdirir. Bu barədə daha ətraflı məlumatı buradan əldə edə bilərsiniz.
Layihənin bir vacib cəhətlərindən biri də ölkədə bloklanan veb səhifələri izləmək ve bu bloklamaların necə baş verdiyini araşdırmaqdır. Bu barədə isə daha ətraflı buradan və buradan məlumat əldə edə bilərsiniz.</description></item></channel></rss>