<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>telegram on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/telegram/</link><description>Recent content in telegram on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/telegram/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Brazil: OONI data on the blocking of Telegram</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-brazil-telegram/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-brazil-telegram/</guid><description>Encontre a versão em português do relatório localizada pela Coding Rights aqui: https://codingrights.org/library-item/brasil-dados-da-ooni-sobre-o-bloqueio-do-telegram/
Two days ago, on 26th April 2023, Brazil started blocking access to Telegram.
On the same day, a federal judge in Brazil reportedly ordered the temporary suspension of Telegram in response to the messaging service’s alleged failure to share all information on neo-Nazi chat groups requested by the police. This information was reportedly requested as part of a school attacks inquiry, as Brazilian authorities investigate neo-Nazi groups that are believed to have used Telegram to incite school attacks.</description></item><item><title>Ethiopia: From internet blackouts to the blocking of WhatsApp and Telegram</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-whatsapp-telegram/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ethiopia-whatsapp-telegram/</guid><description>Communication access in Ethiopia has significantly been disrupted over the last week. Internet access and Short Message Services (SMS) were disconnected intermittently across the country.
During the first half of the week, internet connectivity was shut down completely. After access was restored, both WhatsApp and Telegram were blocked. A few days ago, Ethio Telecom (the only telecom in the country) published a notice, acknowledging the internet disruptions, but came short on details about the extent of communication disruptions or why they occurred in the first place.</description></item></channel></rss>