<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>country-tz on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/country-tz/</link><description>Recent content in country-tz on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/country-tz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tanzania: Surge in online LGBTIQ censorship and other targeted blocks</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2024-tanzania-lgbtiq-censorship-and-other-targeted-blocks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2024-tanzania-lgbtiq-censorship-and-other-targeted-blocks/</guid><description>This report documents the blocking of LGBTIQ websites and other targeted blocks in Tanzania based on the analysis of OONI data.
Key Findings Introduction Methods Acknowledgement of limitations Findings Blocking of LGBTIQ websites LGBTIQ social networks LGBTIQ rights LGBTIQ news and culture LGBTIQ suicide prevention Blocking of websites that support human rights Blocking of online dating websites Blocking of Clubhouse and 4chan Blocking of ProtonVPN Conclusion Acknowledgements Key Findings Our analysis of OONI data collected from Tanzania over the last year (between 1st January 2023 to 31st January 2024) reveals the extensive blocking of LGBTIQ sites, which correlates with the escalating discrimination and crackdown on LGBTIQ communities in Tanzania in recent years.</description></item><item><title>Tanzania blocks social media (and Tor?) on election day</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-tanzania-blocks-social-media-tor-election-day/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-tanzania-blocks-social-media-tor-election-day/</guid><description>Starting from yesterday (27th October 2020) &amp;ndash; on the eve of Tanzania&amp;rsquo;s 2020 general election &amp;ndash; OONI measurements continue to show the ongoing blocking of social media (and of the Tor circumvention tool) in Tanzania.
In this report, we share OONI data collected from Tanzania on these blocks, as well as relevant instructions for further OONI Probe testing.
Methods
Blocking of social media
WhatsApp
Facebook Messenger
Telegram
Social media websites</description></item></channel></rss>