<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Job-Opening on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/job-opening/</link><description>Recent content in Job-Opening on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/job-opening/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Job Opening: OONI Backend Developer</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2024-job-opening-ooni-backend-developer/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2024-job-opening-ooni-backend-developer/</guid><description>&lt;p>Are you a backend developer interested in defending human rights on the
internet? We have a job opening for you!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://ooni.org/">OONI&lt;/a> team (a non-profit measuring internet censorship
globally) is looking for a dedicated &lt;strong>Backend Developer&lt;/strong> to work on our
backend components and infrastructure, and to provide OONI data analysis
support for our &lt;a href="https://ooni.org/reports/">research&lt;/a> efforts.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="job-description">Job description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>By joining our team, you will work on OONI’s backend components, ensuring the
stable and reliable performance of our infrastructure in response to the
growing global coverage of measurements. You will also provide OONI data
analysis support for OONI &lt;a href="https://ooni.org/reports/">research reports&lt;/a> and in
support of the research of our &lt;a href="https://ooni.org/partners">partners&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Job Opening: OONI Project Manager</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-job-opening-ooni-project-manager/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-job-opening-ooni-project-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>This job posting is now closed. Any applications received after 2023-06-28 will not be considered&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Are you a project manager interested in defending human rights on the
internet? We have a job opening for you!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://ooni.org/">OONI&lt;/a> team (a non-profit measuring
internet censorship globally) is looking for a dedicated &lt;strong>project
manager&lt;/strong> to help us manage our software development work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We will be reviewing applications on a rolling basis.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="job-description">Job description&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>By joining our team, you will help ensure that our software projects are
on track, supporting a global community that relies on our tools for
measuring and fighting internet censorship.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Job Opening: OONI Community Coordinator</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-job-opening-ooni-community-coordinator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-job-opening-ooni-community-coordinator/</guid><description>&lt;p>Are you passionate about defending human rights on the internet? Are you
extremely organized and enjoy supporting communities around the world?
We have a job opening for you!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://ooni.org/">OONI&lt;/a> team (a non-profit fighting internet
censorship) is looking for a dedicated &lt;strong>community coordinator&lt;/strong> to help
grow and support the OONI community around the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The application deadline is &lt;strong>Sunday, 12th June 2022&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="job-description">Job description&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>By joining our team, you will support our
&lt;a href="https://ooni.org/partners">partners&lt;/a> and global community of human
rights defenders to measure and fight internet censorship. Our community
is at the heart of our work, and you will play an important role in
helping to ensure that our tools meet the needs of our community.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Job Opening: Mobile Developer for OONI Probe</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-job-opening-ooni-mobile-developer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-job-opening-ooni-mobile-developer/</guid><description>&lt;p>Are you a mobile developer interested in defending human rights on the
internet? We have a job opening for you!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://ooni.org/">OONI&lt;/a> team (a non-profit fighting internet
censorship, originally born out of the &lt;a href="https://www.torproject.org/">Tor
Project&lt;/a>) is looking for a dedicated
&lt;strong>mobile developer&lt;/strong> to work on &lt;a href="https://ooni.org/install/mobile">OONI Probe&lt;/a>: a free software app designed
to measure internet censorship and network performance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The application deadline is &lt;strong>Sunday, 31st October 2021&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="job-description">Job description&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>If you join our team, you will lead the development of the &lt;a href="https://ooni.org/install/mobile">OONI Probe mobile app&lt;/a>, supporting human rights
defenders worldwide to investigate and fight internet censorship.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>