<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Partners on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/</link><description>Recent content in Partners on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/partners/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Access Now</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/access-now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/access-now/</guid><description>Access Now defends and extends the digital rights of users at risk around the world through policy and advocacy efforts. Every year, they host RightsCon, the world&amp;rsquo;s leading summit on human rights in the digital age.
Since 2016, Access Now&amp;rsquo;s #KeepItOn coalition — more than 220 organizations from 99 countries around the world — has been fighting internet shutdowns with all kinds of creative approaches, including grassroots advocacy, direct policy-maker engagement, technical support, corporate accountability, and legal intervention.</description></item><item><title>Asociación por los Derechos Civiles (ADC)</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/adc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/adc/</guid><description>Asociación por los Derechos Civiles (ADC) is a civil society organization based in Argentina that, since its foundation in 1995, works to defend and promote civil and human rights in Argentina and Latin America.</description></item><item><title>Association for Freedom of Thought and Expression (AFTE)</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/afte/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/afte/</guid><description>The Association for Freedom of Thought and Expression (AFTE) is a nongovernmental organization, registered in accordance with Egyptian law as a law firm since 2007. The association works to promote and protect freedom of expression and freedom of information. It uses research, legal support, monitoring of violations, and advocacy through its team of researchers and lawyers.
AFTE is concerned with a number of issues, such as: media freedom, digital rights, freedom of information, freedom of creativity, academic freedom, student rights and freedoms, the right to privacy.</description></item><item><title>Azerbaijan Internet Watch</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/azerbaijan-internet-watch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/azerbaijan-internet-watch/</guid><description>Azerbaijan Internet Watch (AIW) is an online resource platform tracking and mapping internet censorship and surveillance in real-time in Azerbaijan.</description></item><item><title>Campaign for Human Rights &amp; Development International (CHRDI)</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/chrdi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/chrdi/</guid><description>The Campaign for Human Rights and Development International (CHRDI) is a development and human rights organisation (based in Sierra Leone and the United Kingdom) that utilizes rights based and voice and accountability approaches to bridge the justice and social equity gaps. They envision a world in which all people enjoy their human rights and live with dignity, equality, and justice.
CHRDI is in Special Consultative Status to the United Nations Economic and Social Council (ECOSOS) and accredited to many UN Agencies.</description></item><item><title>Centre for Intellectual Property and Information Technology Law (CIPIT), Strathmore University</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/cipit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/cipit/</guid><description>The Centre for Intellectual Property and Information Technology Law (CIPIT) is an evidence-based research and training Centre based at Strathmore University, Nairobi, Kenya.
Their Mission is to study, create, and share knowledge on the development of intellectual property and information technology, especially as they contribute to African Law and Human Rights.
Their team is multidisciplinary, drawn from law, political science, computer science and development while using diverse methodological approaches to inform debates on ICT applications and regulation.</description></item><item><title>Coding Rights</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/coding-rights/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/coding-rights/</guid><description>Coding Rights are an organisation bringing an intersectional feminist approach to defend human rights in the development, regulation and use of technologies. They act collectively and in networks, use creativity and hacker knowledge to question the present and reimagine a future based on transfeminist and decolonial values.
Their mission is to expose and challenge technologies which reinforce power asymmetries, with focus on gender inequalities and its intersectionalities.
Openness, transparency, diversity, equality, privacy and freedom in the access and usages of technologies and in the interaction with governance processes are at the core of the development of a people-centered network and a democratic society.</description></item><item><title>Community Participation In Sustainable Development (COMPSUDEV) Cameroon</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/compsudev/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/compsudev/</guid><description>Community Participation in Sustainable Development (COMPSUDEV) is a non-profit association in Cameroon that sets out to empower youths and communities through sustainable livelihood programs in the domain of ICT and Open Access to the internet.
COMPSUDEV Cameroon is one of the pioneer members of the Cameroon Digital Rights Coalition working on digital security and censorship.
COMPSUDEV Cameroon is concerned with issues such as; right to privacy, information freedom, digital security, open internet, internet circumvention, digital rights and responsibilities and open data.</description></item><item><title>DefendDefenders</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/defenddefenders/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/defenddefenders/</guid><description>DefendDefenders (East and Horn of Africa Human Rights Defenders Project) seeks to strengthen the work of human rights defenders (HRDs) throughout the East and Horn of Africa sub-region by reducing their vulnerability to the risk of persecution and by enhancing their capacity to effectively defend human rights. They work in Burundi, Djibouti, Eritrea, Ethiopia, Kenya, Rwanda, Somalia/Somaliland, South Sudan, Sudan, Tanzania, and Uganda.
DefendDefenders serves as the secretariat of the East and Horn of Africa Human Rights Defenders Network, which represents hundreds of members consisting of individual HRDs, human rights organisations, and national HRD coalitions.</description></item><item><title>Derechos Digitales</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/derechos-digitales/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/derechos-digitales/</guid><description>Derechos Digitales is an independent, non-profit organization of Latin American scope, founded in 2005 and whose main objective is the development, defense and promotion of human rights in the digital environment.
The organization&amp;rsquo;s work is concentrated on three fundamental axes:
Freedom of expression. Privacy and personal data. Copyright and access to knowledge. The mission of Derechos Digitales is the defense, promotion and development of human rights in the digital environment in Latin America, through the study and dissemination of information on public policies and private practices, to promote social change around the respect and dignity of people.</description></item><item><title>Digital Security Lab Ukraine</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/digital-security-lab-ukraine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/digital-security-lab-ukraine/</guid><description>Digital Security Lab Ukraine managed efforts to establish a nationwide Internet censorship measurement system in Ukraine. In doing so, they engaged volunteers across different regions of Ukraine with the use of OONI Probe for censorship measurement, and they performed analysis of OONI data to uncover censorship events. They published several reports documenting their findings, showing how internet censorship varies across regions and networks within Ukraine.</description></item><item><title>Digital Society of Africa</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/digital-society-of-africa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/digital-society-of-africa/</guid><description>Digital Society of Africa (DSA) works to strengthen the resilience and ability of frontline activists; human rights defenders and other at-risk groups in the region to independently recognize and respond to digital threats and attacks. They seek to achieve this using the holistic security approach; through a range of activities including: organisational security audits; risk assessment; trainings, sustainable security accompaniment; security policy formulation and tech support.</description></item><item><title>Fundación Internet Bolivia</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/fundacion-internet-bolivia.org/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/fundacion-internet-bolivia.org/</guid><description>Fundación Internet Bolivia aims to defend digital rights in Bolivia through the generation of knowledge and the promotion of good practices. Their vision is to achieve free, open and secure Internet access for the Bolivian population.</description></item><item><title>Fundación Karisma</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/karisma-foundation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/karisma-foundation/</guid><description>Fundación Karisma is a Colombian civil society organization that seeks to respond to the threats and opportunities that “technology for development” poses to the exercise of human rights.
In 2019, Fundación Karisma won the Index Censorship Freedom of Expression Award.</description></item><item><title>ICT Users Association (ASUTIC)</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/asutic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/asutic/</guid><description>ASUTIC a non-profit organization in Senegal that protects digital rights, promotes digital economy and digital ecology, and works to strengthen democracy through ICT.
They strive for getting people access to knowledge and information, key drivers for sustainable development to the benefit of everyone.
ASUTIC are mobilized for a strong and dynamic democracy through transparency, accountability of policy makers and citizen participation, based on gender equality. They work to relocate power from politicians to citizens.</description></item><item><title>Internet Outage Detection &amp; Analysis (IODA)</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/ioda/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/ioda/</guid><description>The Internet Outage Detection and Analysis (IODA) project is run by the Internet Intelligence Research Lab, which is based at the Georgia Institute of Technology&amp;rsquo;s School of Computer Science in the College of Computing.
IODA monitors the Internet in near-realtime to identify macroscopic Internet outages affecting the edge of the network, i.e., significantly impacting a network operator (AS) or a large fraction of a country.
IODA combines information from three data sources, establishes the relevance of an event and generates alerts.</description></item><item><title>Internet Sans Frontières</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/internet-sans-frontieres/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/internet-sans-frontieres/</guid><description>Internet Sans Frontières is a non-profit organizations whose objective is to promote the free flow of information and knowledge, defend digital rights and freedoms and fight against all forms of censorship on connected networks.
Internet Sans Frontières has led advocacy efforts against internet shutdowns in West Africa.</description></item><item><title>Internet Society</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/internet-society/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/internet-society/</guid><description>The Internet Society is a global nonprofit empowering people to keep the Internet a force for good: open, globally connected, secure, and trustworthy. They believe that the Internet is for everyone. Their work centers on increasing the Internet’s reach, reliability and resilience, as well as ensuring that the Internet remains open, globally connected, secure, and trustworthy. To assess whether these efforts are working, they&amp;rsquo;re building Internet Society Pulse - a curated set of insights to help everyone gain deeper, data-driven insight into the health, availability and evolution of the global Internet.</description></item><item><title>IPYS Venezuela</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/ipys-venezuela/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/ipys-venezuela/</guid><description>IPYS Venezuela works for a Venezuela where there is full enjoyment of freedom of expression and the right to information, and demands that the necessary guarantees to exercise free and plural journalism, allowing the scrutiny of power, be met.
For the advancement of this vision, and as an organization formed by professionals and defenders of communication, IPYS Venezuela promotes the development of journalists and communicators, as well as the establishment of conditions that guarantee an independent and vigilant investigative journalism.</description></item><item><title>Jordan Open Source Association (JOSA)</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/josa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/josa/</guid><description>The Jordan Open Source Association (JOSA) is a non-profit organization that works for the promotion and implementation of the Open Source principles in Jordan. JOSA organizes activities and leads initiatives in different fields, including Open Source software and hardware, Open Content and Free Culture, and digital rights.
JOSA’s main objectives are building a more open, collaborative Jordan, pushing technical skillset for the tech community in Jordan to a global caliber, ensure readiness of ICT graduates and defending Jordanians’ rights online.</description></item><item><title>Localization Lab</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/localization-lab/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/localization-lab/</guid><description>Localization Lab believes that language shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a barrier when it comes to security and access to the Internet. Since 2012, they have helped expand the reach of Internet freedom tools by unlocking access to communities all over the world.
To this end, Localization Lab works to:
Expand the reach of Internet freedom technology and supporting materials.
Facilitate relationships between developers and end-users to increase the adoption of new technologies and ensure that community needs are being met.</description></item><item><title>Masaar - Technology and Law Community</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/masaar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/masaar/</guid><description>Masaar are a group of lawyers and technologists interested in enhancing and promoting digital rights and associated freedoms in Egypt. They focus on merging law and technology and deepening their understanding of their impact on human rights and fundamental freedoms.
Masaar&amp;rsquo;s activities focus on digital freedoms in the context of the Egyptian law, but that will not isolate Masaar from the human rights situation in other countries in the region and the world.</description></item><item><title>Myanmar ICT for Development Organization (MIDO)</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/mido/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/mido/</guid><description>Myanmar ICT for Development Organization (MIDO) aims to promote the spread of ICT technology in rural areas of Myanmar and to improve people&amp;rsquo;s lives and knowledge.</description></item><item><title>Netalitica</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/netalitica/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/netalitica/</guid><description>Netalitica aims to improve the Citizen Lab’s test lists that network measurement tools (i.e. OONI Probe, Centinel) use to uncover blocking of websites. If network probes have evolved over the years, test lists for some countries and regions have seen little updates, which negatively affects the quality of collected measurements and wastes resources of testers on the ground.
Netalitica&amp;rsquo;s test list project aims to address these issues by updating the lists for select censorship hot spots around the world and advance recommendations for streamlining the process of updating lists.</description></item><item><title>Open Culture Foundation (OCF)</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/open-culture-foundation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/open-culture-foundation/</guid><description>The Open Culture Foundation (OCF) is a nonpartisan, nonprofit organization, founded in 2014 by several members of Taiwan’s open source community. Their main goal is to support local communities advocate the use of open technologies in broader sectors, including open source software, open hardware, and open data. They help government, enterprises, and NGOs better understand the benefits of adopting open source,and promote the importance of open data to the public sphere.</description></item><item><title>Open Net Korea</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/open-net-korea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/open-net-korea/</guid><description>Founded in January 2013, Open Net Korea is a non-profit organization that aims to provide a forum for discussion and collaboration to explore effective policies and solutions in the following areas: Freedom of Expression, Freedom from Surveillance, Reforming Innovation-blocking Regulations, Net Governance and Neutrality, Open Data Policy, and Reforming the Intellectual Property Regime.
Open Net Korea is aspiring to become not only a legal and legislative advocacy organization that fights the regulations, but also a think tank that inquires into the reasons for these regulations and “thinks aloud” with the Korean public and the world on what has caused and what will prevent the Internet from becoming a “closed” circuit for some group of people, instead of “open network”.</description></item><item><title>OutRight Action International</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/outright-action-international/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/outright-action-international/</guid><description>OutRight Action International works at a global, regional and national level to eradicate the persecution, inequality and violence lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, intersex, and queer (LGBTIQ) people face around the world. From its offices in 7 countries and headquarters in New York, OutRight builds capacity of LGBTIQ movements, documents human rights violations, advocates for inclusion and equality, and holds leaders accountable for protecting the rights of LGBTIQ people everywhere. OutRight has recognized consultative status at the United Nations.</description></item><item><title>Paradigm Initiative</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/paradigm-initiative/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/paradigm-initiative/</guid><description>Paradigm Initiative is a social enterprise that builds an ICT-enabled support system and advocates digital rights in order to improve livelihoods for under-served youth. Their programs include digital inclusion programs – such as the Life Skills, ICT, Financial Readiness, Entrepreneurship (LIFE) training program and Tertiary program – and a digital rights program, Magoyi. Across their offices in Nigeria (Aba, Abuja, Ajegunle, Kano, Yaba), Cameroon (Yaoundé), Kenya (Nairobi), and beyond,they work to connect under-served youth with improved livelihoods through their digital inclusion and digital rights programs.</description></item><item><title>Psiphon</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/psiphon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/psiphon/</guid><description>Since 2006, Psiphon has provided open access to the internet for millions of citizens around the world.
Psiphon is a free and open source tool that utilizes VPN, SSH, and HTTP proxy technology for censorship circumvention. The Psiphon VPN essentially serves as a tunnel that enables you to circumvent censorship because you access resources on the internet through the non-censored tunnel that Psiphon provides.
OONI collaborated with Psiphon on developing an OONI Probe test that measures whether the Psiphon app works in a tested network.</description></item><item><title>Red en Defensa de los Derechos Digitales (R3D)</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/r3d/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/r3d/</guid><description>Red en Defensa de los Derechos Digitales (R3D) is a Mexican non-profit organization dedicated to the defense of human rights in the digital environment. They use various legal and communication tools to conduct policy research, strategic litigation, public advocacy and campaigns with the aim of promoting digital rights in Mexico. In particular, freedom of expression, privacy, access to knowledge and free culture.</description></item><item><title>Sinar Project</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/sinar-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/sinar-project/</guid><description>Sinar Project is a civic tech initiative using open technology, open data and policy analysis to systematically make important information public and more accessible to the Malaysian people. It aims to improve governance and encourage greater citizen involvement in the public affairs of the nation by making Parliament and Malaysian Government more open, transparent and accountable.
Sinar Project has worked across Southeast Asia to engage local communities with censorship measurement research.</description></item><item><title>Software Freedom Law Centre, India</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/sflc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/sflc/</guid><description>Software Freedom Law Centre, India (SFLC.IN) is a donor supported legal services organisation that brings together lawyers, policy analysts, technologists, and students to protect freedom in the digital world. SFLC.IN promotes innovation and open access to knowledge by helping developers make great Free and Open Source Software, protect privacy and civil liberties for citizens in the digital world by educating and providing free legal advice and help policy makers make informed and just decisions with the use and adoption of technology.</description></item><item><title>TEDIC</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/tedic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/tedic/</guid><description>The Association of Technology, Education, Development, Research, Communication (TEDIC) is an NGO that develops open civic technology and defends digital rights for a free culture on the Internet.
TEDIC promotes the use and development of free software and hardware, open design and open data. They seek for full compliance of civil rights on the Internet. They research, advocate and train in privacy, freedom of expression, network neutrality, copyright, among others.</description></item><item><title>Thai Netizen Network</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/thai-netizen-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/thai-netizen-network/</guid><description>Thai Netizen Network is a leading non-profit organisation in Thailand that advocates for digital rights and civil liberties. Founded in December 2008, it grew out of a group of netizens who had concerns about limited internet freedom during post-coup governments.
Its activities are based on five themes: 1) access to information, 2) freedom of opinion and expression, 3) privacy, 4) participatory internet governance, and 5) rights over information resources. The Network is run by a small working group, with consultation from its members and an advisory board drawn from civil society, industry and academia.</description></item><item><title>The Advocates for Human Rights and Democracy (TAHURID)</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/tahurid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/tahurid/</guid><description>The Advocates for Human Rights and Democracy (TAHURID) is an NGO in South Sudan working to promote and protect human rights and democracy through advocacy, capacity building, and legal representation in courts.
TAHURID aims to improve and safeguard the human dignity of every person by promoting and supporting the principles of democracy, human rights, rule of law, good governance and public accountability in South Sudan.</description></item><item><title>The Centre for Internet &amp; Society (CIS)</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/cis-india/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/cis-india/</guid><description>The Centre for Internet and Society (CIS) is a non-profit organisation that undertakes interdisciplinary research on internet and digital technologies from policy and academic perspectives.
CIS has been actively involved in research and measurement of web censorship in India. CIS' past work includes critical analysis of the Indian government&amp;rsquo;s power to block online content, the different techniques used by Internet Service Providers (ISPs) to censor websites and the consistency of website blocklists across different ISPs in India.</description></item><item><title>The Citizen Lab</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/citizen-lab/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/citizen-lab/</guid><description>The Citizen Lab is an interdisciplinary laboratory based at the Munk School of Global Affairs &amp;amp; Public Policy, University of Toronto, focusing on research, development, and high-level strategic policy and legal engagement at the intersection of information and communication technologies, human rights, and global security.
They use a “mixed methods” approach to research combining practices from political science, law, computer science, and area studies. Their research includes: investigating digital espionage against civil society, documenting Internet filtering and other technologies and practices that impact freedom of expression online, analyzing privacy, security, and information controls of popular applications, and examining transparency and accountability mechanisms relevant to the relationship between corporations and state agencies regarding personal data and other surveillance activities.</description></item><item><title>The Tor Project</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/tor-project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/tor-project/</guid><description>The Tor Project, Inc, became a 501(c)3 nonprofit in 2006, but the idea of &amp;ldquo;onion routing&amp;rdquo; began in the mid 1990s.
Just like Tor users, the developers, researchers, and founders who&amp;rsquo;ve made Tor possible are a diverse group of people. But all of the people who have been involved in Tor are united by a common belief: internet users should have private access to an uncensored web.
The Tor network, which is free and open source, provides its users with online anonymity, privacy, and censorship circumvention.</description></item><item><title>Tuwindi</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/tuwindi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/tuwindi/</guid><description>Tuwindi is a non-partisan, non-profit Malian law organization. Their goal is to use information and communication technologies to support social and economic development. Their mission is to propell economic and social development through the innovative use of ICT communication and information technologies.</description></item><item><title>Venezuela Inteligente</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/venezuela-inteligente/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/venezuela-inteligente/</guid><description>Venezuela Inteligente is a non-profit organization that aims to facilitate information, communication and collaboration between citizens and civil society organizations to create impact from a non-partisan perspective. They promote, facilitate and develop digital tools, improving access to information, collaboration and responsiveness, empowering organizations, activists and citizens. They fight for the rights of Venezuelans online and offline.
Through their VEsinFiltro project, Venezuela Inteligente investigate and document internet censorship in Venezuela, using (along with custom scripts and tools) OONI Probe and OONI data.</description></item><item><title>Zaina Foundation</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/partners/zaina-foundation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/partners/zaina-foundation/</guid><description>Founded in 2017, Zaina Foundation is a non-governmental, non-profit organization registered under NGO’s Act of 2002 with the aim of promoting digital rights in Tanzania.
Zaina Foundation’s vision is to empower women in technology through digital security and privacy capacity building, workshops and training. This is done by providing capacity building of digital security training to women and human rights defenders in Tanzania, localization and translation of open source tools in Swahili language in order to allow Swahili users to access secure tools for their communication.</description></item></channel></rss>