<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>country-es on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/country-es/</link><description>Recent content in country-es on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/country-es/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Evaluating OONI’s New Measurement Engine in the Context of the Blocking of Women on Web in Spain</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-engine-evaluation-spain/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-engine-evaluation-spain/</guid><description>Reproduction rights site www.womenonweb.org has been blocked in Spain over the last months by several local Internet Service Providers (ISPs). Once Spanish hacktivist communities noticed that www.womenonweb.org was inaccessible, they coordinated on running OONI Probe tests to collect measurement data that could serve as evidence. The findings of this investigation have been published in an excellent report, whose writing was coordinated by our former colleague, Vasilis Ververis.
We were involved in the technical review of the report.</description></item><item><title>Evidence of Internet Censorship during Catalonia's Independence Referendum</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/internet-censorship-catalonia-independence-referendum/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/internet-censorship-catalonia-independence-referendum/</guid><description>Image: Catalan Independence Referendum site seized
Two days ago, Catalonia held a referendum seeking independence from Spain. As the world awaits to see what happens next, we publish this post to share evidence of recent censorship events that occurred during and leading up to the referendum.
We confirm the blocking of at least 25 sites related to the Catalan referendum by means of DNS tampering and HTTP blocking, based on OONI Probe network measurements collected from three local networks.</description></item></channel></rss>