<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Get-involved on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.org/get-involved/</link><description>Recent content in Get-involved on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://ooni.org/get-involved/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://ooni.org/get-involved/contribute-test-lists/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/get-involved/contribute-test-lists/</guid><description>The test list methodology Censorship findings are only as interesting as the sites and services that you test.
We encourage you to suggest sites and services to test for censorship.
Please read the documentation below to contribute to community resources for censorship measurement research.
What are test lists?
What aren&amp;rsquo;t test lists?
Why contribute to test lists?
Contributing to test lists
Test list research</description></item><item><title/><link>https://ooni.org/get-involved/net-neutrality-us/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/get-involved/net-neutrality-us/</guid><description>Can you join our group of US-based volunteers?
When we need certain tests run to track net neutrality violations in the US, we’ll email you instructions on how to participate.
#mc_embed_signup{background:#fff; clear:left; font:14px Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif; } We promise we will not spam you.</description></item><item><title>OONI Partnership Program</title><link>https://ooni.org/get-involved/partnership-program/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/get-involved/partnership-program/</guid><description>What is the OONI Partnership Program?
What is the aim of the OONI Partnership Program?
What does the OONI Partnership Program entail?
Collecting ooniprobe network measurements
Reviewing community resources for censorship measurement research
Communicating internet censorship findings to the public
Who can join the OONI Partnership Program?
How can OONI support its partners?</description></item><item><title>Thematic OONI Probe testing</title><link>https://ooni.org/get-involved/run/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/get-involved/run/</guid><description>Social media, news websites, and VPNs often get blocked during political events (such as elections or protests) around the world.
To support rapid response to emergent censorship events, we share the following OONI Run buttons to enable the testing of specific types of websites.
Install the OONI Probe mobile app: Android, iOS, F-Droid
Tap the buttons below &amp;amp; open them with your OONI Probe mobile app (not with a browser)</description></item></channel></rss>