<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hackathon on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/hackathon/</link><description>Recent content in hackathon on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/hackathon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Join us at the IMC 2023 Hackathon on Network Interference using Open Data</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-imc-hackathon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-imc-hackathon/</guid><description>Are you attending the Internet Measurement Conference (IMC) 2023?
Join us at the IMC Hackathon on Network Interference using Open Data on Monday, 23rd October 2023, in Montreal, Canada. The hackathon is organized by the Internet Society (ISOC), the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI), M-Lab and Censored Planet.
IMC is a yearly academic conference focusing on Internet measurement and analysis. The conference is sponsored by ACM SIGCOMM.
This IMC Hackathon will be about exploring, analyzing, and visualizing open network measurement data with a focus on identifying Internet censorship and Internet shutdown events.</description></item><item><title>OONI-dev meeting and hackathon 2016</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-dev-and-hackathon-2016/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/ooni-dev-and-hackathon-2016/</guid><description>Oonitarians are spread out across the globe, and OONI’s core team is no exception. We recently met in Berlin to hack on OONI’s software, work on our roadmap, and to have all those discussions that are more fruitful to have in person than on IRC. We also held a hackathon to engage new individuals with our project!
Below we document some of the things that we worked on as part of our OONI-dev meeting and hackathon.</description></item><item><title>OONI Hackathon: Join us to explore internet censorship!</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/berlin-hackathon-2016/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/berlin-hackathon-2016/</guid><description>Interested in exploring (and exposing) internet censorship? Join the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) hackathon in Berlin!
When? Friday, 11th November &amp;amp; Saturday, 12th November 2016
Where? The OnionSpace (Gottschedstraße 4, 13357 Berlin, Germany)
What time? 10am onwards
Who? Software developers, data analysts, academics, journalists, bloggers, lawyers, activists, and all those who don’t go by any particular label, but are curious enough to join!</description></item></channel></rss>