<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>country-mm on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.org/tags/country-mm/</link><description>Recent content in country-mm on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.org/tags/country-mm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Investigating Internet shutdowns through Mozilla telemetry</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/2021-investigating-internet-shutdowns-mozilla-telemetry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/2021-investigating-internet-shutdowns-mozilla-telemetry/</guid><description>More than 200 million users worldwide use the Firefox web browser (developed by Mozilla) every month.
If access to the Internet is shut down in a country, Mozilla should expect to see a dramatic drop in Firefox usage from that country. Given how widespread the use of Firefox is around the world, could Mozilla telemetry be a valuable resource for the Internet freedom community to investigate Internet shutdowns?
To explore this question, the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) and Internet Outage Detection and Analysis (IODA) teams joined forces to analyze a dataset of potential outage signals gathered through regular Mozilla telemetry, access to which was provided by Mozilla as part of a relevant research project to validate assumptions about the data.</description></item><item><title>Myanmar: Data on internet blocks and internet outages following military coup</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/2021-myanmar-internet-blocks-and-outages/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/2021-myanmar-internet-blocks-and-outages/</guid><description>On 1st February 2021, the military in Myanmar carried out a coup d’etat, seizing power and detaining the country’s State Counsellor (equivalent to a prime minister) and other democratically elected leaders.
A few days after the coup, ISPs in Myanmar started blocking access to Facebook services. On 5th February 2021, they started blocking access to Twitter and Instagram as well. On 6th February 2021, access to the internet was shut down entirely for nearly 30 hours.</description></item><item><title>Myanmar blocks “fake news” websites amid COVID-19 pandemic</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/2020-myanmar-blocks-websites-amid-covid19/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/2020-myanmar-blocks-websites-amid-covid19/</guid><description>In March 2020, Internet Service Providers (ISPs) in Myanmar received a directive from the Ministry of Transport and Communications to block 230 websites, most of which contain adult content. However, 67 of these sites were blocked on the grounds of spreading “fake news”. The list of these 230 websites has not been published.
In an attempt to potentially identify the newly blocked websites, we analyzed OONI network measurements collected from Myanmar over the last months, between 1st January 2020 to 9th April 2020.</description></item><item><title>The State of Internet Censorship in Myanmar</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/myanmar-report/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 13:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/myanmar-report/</guid><description>A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI), Sinar Project, and the Myanmar ICT for Development Organization (MIDO).
Table of contents
Key Findings
Introduction
Background
Network landscape and internet penetration
Legal environment
Freedom of expression
Press freedom
Access to information
Privacy
Censorship and surveillance
Reported cases of internet censorship and surveillance</description></item></channel></rss>