<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>paper on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>/tags/paper/</link><description>Recent content in paper on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/paper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Measuring DoT/DoH Blocking Using OONI Probe: A Preliminary Study</title><link>/post/2022-doh-dot-paper-dnsprivacy21/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2022-doh-dot-paper-dnsprivacy21/</guid><description>When you enter a URL such as https://example.com/, under the hood, your web browser resolves the example.com domain to one or more IP addresses using the Domain Name System (DNS), a set of federated servers and protocols providing this name-to-IP-address mapping. For example, as of 2022-06-16, example.com resolves to the 93.184.216.34 (IPv4) and 2606:2800:220:1:248:1893:25c8:1946 (IPv6) addresses. Once it knows the IP addresses for the domain, the browser then uses them to fetch the requested webpage.</description></item><item><title>Measuring HTTP/3 censorship with OONI Probe</title><link>/post/2022-http3-measurements-paper/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2022-http3-measurements-paper/</guid><description>Last year, QUIC emerged as a new internet protocol for creating reliable connections and encrypting communications between clients over the new HTTP/3 protocol. Observing the emergence and growing deployment of HTTP/3, we want to enable OONI Probe to measure HTTP/3 censorship and monitor how censors respond and adapt to technical innovation.
We therefore added HTTP/3 support (in early 2021) into OONI Probe (through our urlgetter research tool) to conduct measurements in China, Iran, India and Kazakhstan to investigate the state of HTTP/3 censorship in these countries.</description></item><item><title>A multi-perspective view of Internet censorship in Myanmar</title><link>/post/2021-multiperspective-view-internet-censorship-myanmar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/post/2021-multiperspective-view-internet-censorship-myanmar/</guid><description>In the wake of a military coup in February 2021, Myanmar experienced unprecedented levels of internet censorship.
In response, we collaborated with CAIDA’s Internet Outage Detection and Analysis (IODA) team and Myanmar ICT for Development Organization (MIDO) on publishing a research report which documents a series of nightly internet outages and the blocking of social media, Wikipedia, and circumvention tool sites in Myanmar following the military coup.
In the months that followed, we continued to examine internet censorship in Myanmar quite closely.</description></item></channel></rss>