<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>country-ng on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.org/tags/country-ng/</link><description>Recent content in country-ng on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.org/tags/country-ng/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nigeria’s 2019 elections through the lens of network measurements</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/2019-nigeria-internet-censorship/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/2019-nigeria-internet-censorship/</guid><description>Censorship events are increasingly being reported during political events in Africa (and elsewhere around the world). A few examples include the social media disruptions in Mali amid its 2018 presidential election, the blocking of social media in Uganda during its 2016 general elections, and the complete internet blackout in The Gambia during its 2016 presidential election.
Leading up to and during Nigeria’s 2019 general elections, we collaborated with our local partner, Paradigm Initiative, on measuring networks in the country to monitor potential censorship events.</description></item><item><title>Nigeria: Measuring Internet Censorship</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/nigeria-internet-censorship/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/nigeria-internet-censorship/</guid><description>Last October, Nigeria’s National Communications Commission (NCC) reportedly ordered the blocking of 21 websites. In response, we collaborated with Nigeria’s Paradigm Initiative to test those websites and collect network measurement data that can shed light on whether and how they’re blocked.
Our findings are included in a joint research report that we published today with Paradigm Initiative. The full report, titled “Tightening the Noose on Freedom of Expression: Status of Internet Freedom in Nigeria 2018”, can be downloaded here.</description></item></channel></rss>