<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>elections on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.org/tags/elections/</link><description>Recent content in elections on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.org/tags/elections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tanzania blocks social media (and Tor?) on election day</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/2020-tanzania-blocks-social-media-tor-election-day/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/2020-tanzania-blocks-social-media-tor-election-day/</guid><description>Starting from yesterday (27th October 2020) &amp;ndash; on the eve of Tanzania&amp;rsquo;s 2020 general election &amp;ndash; OONI measurements continue to show the ongoing blocking of social media (and of the Tor circumvention tool) in Tanzania.
In this report, we share OONI data collected from Tanzania on these blocks, as well as relevant instructions for further OONI Probe testing.
Methods
Blocking of social media</description></item><item><title>Belarus protests: From internet outages to pervasive website censorship</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/2020-belarus-internet-outages-website-censorship/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/2020-belarus-internet-outages-website-censorship/</guid><description>Image: Block page served in Belarus.
This report was prepared in collaboration with Human Constanta and the Digital Observers Community Belarus.
More than 70 websites have been blocked in Belarus over the last weeks, following a controversial presidential election and amid ongoing anti-government protests. Many of the blocked sites include news media and are related to the elections, while several other sites expressing political criticism were blocked as well.</description></item><item><title>Burundi blocks social media amid 2020 general election</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/2020-burundi-blocks-social-media-amid-election/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/2020-burundi-blocks-social-media-amid-election/</guid><description>Yesterday, access to social media was reportedly blocked in Burundi amid its 2020 general election.
The lead-up to the election was marred by violence and unrest, as seven candidates vied to replace Incumbent President Nkurunziza, who has been in power over the last 15 years. Despite widespread deadly protests and a coup attempt, President Nkurunziza won a third term in 2015 following disputed elections. While President Nkurunziza reportedly announced that he would not contest the next elections, he is set to become a “supreme guide to patriotism” as he steps down now in 2020.</description></item><item><title>The Gambia: Internet Shutdown during 2016 Presidential Election</title><link>https://ooni.org/post/gambia-internet-shutdown/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.org/post/gambia-internet-shutdown/</guid><description>Last week we attempted to perform OONI network measurement tests in the Gambia to examine whether websites were blocked during its 2016 presidential election. But merely a few hours after we connected our probe to perform tests, it stopped working completely.
We suspected that this was due to an internet shutdown. To confirm this, we referred to third-party data to examine whether a country-wide internet blackout was taking place.
In this report, we summarize some of our key findings pertaining to the internet shutdown that appears to have occurred in the Gambia on the eve of its 2016 presidential election.</description></item></channel></rss>