<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>country-in on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/country-in/</link><description>Recent content in country-in on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/country-in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Measuring HTTP/3 censorship with OONI Probe</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-http3-measurements-paper/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-http3-measurements-paper/</guid><description>Last year, QUIC emerged as a new internet protocol for creating reliable connections and encrypting communications between clients over the new HTTP/3 protocol. Observing the emergence and growing deployment of HTTP/3, we want to enable OONI Probe to measure HTTP/3 censorship and monitor how censors respond and adapt to technical innovation.
We therefore added HTTP/3 support (in early 2021) into OONI Probe (through our urlgetter research tool) to conduct measurements in China, Iran, India and Kazakhstan to investigate the state of HTTP/3 censorship in these countries.</description></item><item><title>[Event Report] India, Let's Build the List</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-event-india-test-list/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-event-india-test-list/</guid><description>This is a guest post by The Bachchao Project, originally published here.
The Bachchao Project in partnership with OONI hosted an online event on 9th and 10th October 2021 to update the Citizen Lab test list for India. The event, which was called “India, Lets build the list”, was organised to help strengthen community based monitoring of internet censorship in India. The event allowed experts from different fields to contribute to a curated list of websites that are relevant to India and which are regularly tested for censorship by volunteers in India.</description></item><item><title>Investigating Encrypted DNS Blocking in India</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-encrypted-dns-blocking-india/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-encrypted-dns-blocking-india/</guid><description>In October 2020, we collaborated with Divyank Katira and Gurshabad Grover, researchers at the Centre for Internet &amp;amp; Society, India, to implement and evaluate a new OONI experiment focused on detecting DNS censorship.
This new OONI experiment, called dnscheck, focuses on detecting the blocking of encrypted DNS transports such as DNS over TLS and DNS over HTTPS. Its methodology improves upon the measurement methodology OONI previously used to measure DoT blocking in Iran.</description></item><item><title>Investigating TLS blocking in India</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-tls-blocking-india/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-tls-blocking-india/</guid><description>This report investigates Transport Layer Security (TLS)-based blocking in India. Previous research by the Centre for Internet &amp;amp; Society, India (CIS) has already exposed TLS blocking based on the value of the SNI field. OONI has also implemented and started testing SNI-based TLS blocking measurements.
Recently, the Magma Project documented cases where CIS India and OONI&amp;rsquo;s methodologies could be improved. They specifically found that blocking sometimes appears to depend not only on the value of the SNI field but also on the address of the web server being used.</description></item></channel></rss>