<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Country-Ph on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/country-ph/</link><description>Recent content in Country-Ph on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/country-ph/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>iMAP 2022: New Research Reports on Internet Censorship in 8 Asian countries</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-imap-8-research-reports-southeast-asia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-imap-8-research-reports-southeast-asia/</guid><description>&lt;p>On 21st December 2022, our long-term partner, &lt;a href="https://ooni.org/partners/sinar-project/">Sinar Project&lt;/a>, published &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://imap.sinarproject.org/reports/2022">8 new research reports&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> on
internet censorship in Southeast Asia and Hong Kong (China) in collaboration with their
&lt;a href="https://imap.sinarproject.org/">Internet Monitoring and Action Project (iMAP)&lt;/a> partners. We are particularly
excited about these reports as they make use of &lt;a href="https://ooni.org/data">OONI data&lt;/a>!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://imap.sinarproject.org/about">Internet Monitoring Action Project (iMAP)&lt;/a> aims to establish regional
and in-country networks that monitor network interference and
restrictions to the freedom of expression online in 8 countries:
Myanmar, Cambodia, Hong Kong (China), Indonesia, Malaysia, Philippines,
Thailand, and Vietnam.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>iMAP State of Internet Censorship Report 2022 - Philippines</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-philippines/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2022-state-of-internet-censorship-philippines/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>In recent years, and with the COVID-19 pandemic increasing people’s reliance on digital technologies and with it the role of ICT regulators, agencies such as the NTC have come under fire for the “politicization” of the country’s telecommunications sector.&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> This was most apparent under the administration of former president Rodrigo Duterte, whose six-year presidency was marred by the systematic undermining of democratic institutions and countless attacks against critical media and activists.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>