<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>kazakhstan on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/kazakhstan/</link><description>Recent content in kazakhstan on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/kazakhstan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kazakhstan: TLS MITM attacks and blocking of news media, human rights, and circumvention tool sites</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2024-kazakhstan-drl-report/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2024-kazakhstan-drl-report/</guid><description>In recent years, internet censorship in Kazakhstan has been reported quite extensively. As part of this study, OONI, Internet Freedom Kazakhstan (IFKZ), and Eurasian Digital Foundation collaborated to investigate internet censorship in Kazakhstan over the past year (between June 2023 to June 2024) through the analysis of empirical network measurement data.
In this report, we share OONI censorship measurement findings and relevant legal context. We found numerous news media, human rights, and circumvention tool websites blocked in Kazakhstan by means of TLS interference.</description></item><item><title>Throttling of news media amid Kazakhstan’s 2022 presidential election</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-throttling-kz-elections/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-throttling-kz-elections/</guid><description>Snap presidential elections were held in Kazakhstan in November 2022, following a wave of unrest that started in January 2022. Following the victory of incumbent president Tokayev, early legislative elections were held in March 2023.
Through the analysis of OONI data, we observe the throttling of Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty (RFE/RL) Kazakhstan&amp;rsquo;s service websites in Kazakh and Russian (www.azattyq.org and rus.azattyq.org) in Kazakhstan, starting from 27th September 2022 and lasting until at least 11th April 2023.</description></item></channel></rss>