<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tls-blocking on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/tls-blocking/</link><description>Recent content in tls-blocking on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/tls-blocking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Investigating TLS blocking in India</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-tls-blocking-india/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-tls-blocking-india/</guid><description>This report investigates Transport Layer Security (TLS)-based blocking in India. Previous research by the Centre for Internet &amp;amp; Society, India (CIS) has already exposed TLS blocking based on the value of the SNI field. OONI has also implemented and started testing SNI-based TLS blocking measurements.
Recently, the Magma Project documented cases where CIS India and OONI&amp;rsquo;s methodologies could be improved. They specifically found that blocking sometimes appears to depend not only on the value of the SNI field but also on the address of the web server being used.</description></item><item><title>DNS over TLS blocked in Iran</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-iran-dot/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2020-iran-dot/</guid><description>DNS over TLS (DoT) is a network protocol that allows one to use DNS over TLS (i.e. with encryption and authentication of the remote DNS server).
We investigated whether DoT works in Iran by gathering a list of 31 well-known DoT endpoints and running experiments from four distinct Iranian mobile and fixed-line Internet Service Providers (ISPs): MCI, TCI, Irancell, and Shatel.
We discovered that:
57% of the endpoints are blocked on a least one ISP;</description></item></channel></rss>