<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>country-pk on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/country-pk/</link><description>Recent content in country-pk on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/country-pk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pakistan: Blocking of Wikipedia and Deutsche Welle (DW)</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-pakistan-blocks-wikipedia-and-dw/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2023-pakistan-blocks-wikipedia-and-dw/</guid><description>Over the past weeks, access to Wikipedia and Deutsche Welle’s (DW) website was reportedly blocked in Pakistan.
As part of this report, we share OONI data from Pakistan that provides signals of these blocks. Specifically, OONI data shows that access to Wikipedia was temporarily restricted between 1st to 6th February 2023, while access to Deutsche Welle (DW) remains blocked since (at least) 16th January 2023.
Blocking of Deutsche Welle
Blocking of Wikipedia</description></item><item><title>How Pakistan blocked news outlets, social media sites, and IM apps amidst protests</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/how-pakistan-blocked-social-media/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/how-pakistan-blocked-social-media/</guid><description>Last weekend, a number of social media sites and news outlets were blocked in Pakistan during Islamist protests. Protesters gathered in Islamabad alleged that Mr. Zahid Hamid, the Federal Law Minister, should be removed from his position because he omitted a reference to the Prophet Muhammad in a parliamentary bill. On Saturday, 25th November 2017, law enforcement agencies initiated an operation to disperse the sit-in at the Faizabad Interchange linking Islamabad and Rawalpindi.</description></item><item><title>Internet Censorship in Pakistan: Findings from 2014-2017</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/pakistan-internet-censorship/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/pakistan-internet-censorship/</guid><description>Islamabad: Political dissent in Pakistan under threat, government censors online content - PC: Haroon Baloch
A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) and Bytes for All Pakistan.
Table of contents
Key Findings
Introduction
Background
Network landscape and internet penetration
Legal environment
Freedom of expression
Press freedom
Access to information
Privacy and digital surveillance
Censorship
Reported cases of internet censorship and surveillance
Methodology: Measuring internet censorship in Pakistan</description></item></channel></rss>