<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>country-zm on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/tags/country-zm/</link><description>Recent content in country-zm on OONI: Open Observatory of Network Interference</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ooni.github.io/tags/country-zm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Zambia: Social media blocked amid 2021 general elections</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-zambia-social-media-blocks-amid-elections/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/2021-zambia-social-media-blocks-amid-elections/</guid><description>Recently, on 12th August 2021, general elections were held in Zambia, during which access to popular online social media platforms was reportedly blocked.
In this report, we share relevant OONI data on the blocking of WhatsApp, Twitter, and Facebook amid Zambia’s 2021 general election.
Background
Methods
Findings
Blocking of WhatsApp
Blocking of Twitter and Facebook
Conclusion
Acknowledgements
Background While Zambia hasn’t experienced pervasive forms of internet censorship (such as the blocking of popular social media apps) over the last years, various forms of censorship have been reported in the country.</description></item><item><title>Zambia: Internet censorship during the 2016 general elections?</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/zambia-election-monitoring/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 10:52:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/zambia-election-monitoring/</guid><description>A research study by the Open Observatory of Network Interference (OONI) and Strathmore University’s Centre for Intellectual Property and Information Technology Law (CIPIT).
Table of contents
Key Findings
Introduction
Background
Network landscape and internet penetration
Legal environment
Freedom of expression
Press freedom
Access to information
Privacy
Censorship and surveillance
Previous cases of internet censorship and surveillance
Zambia’s 2016 general elections and constitutional referendum
Examining internet censorship during Zambia’s 2016 general elections</description></item><item><title>Zambia, a country under Deep Packet Inspection</title><link>https://ooni.github.io/post/zambia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ooni.github.io/post/zambia/</guid><description>&amp;quot;I do not have the details of the blocking of Zambianwatchdog.com, but I would celebrate.&amp;quot; Guy Scott Zambian Vicepresident, Friday 28th June 2013 The following article is a guest blog post by Mr T. an independent researcher and provider of hosting to various grass roots organizations.
This article summarizes how we discovered that the grass roots online newspaper Zambianwatchdog.com was being blocked inside Zambia. This report provides technical evidence of the unlawful presence of Deep Packet Inspection in the country to monitor the Internet communications and stop users from browsing the website.</description></item></channel></rss>